( bagpipes playing )
They'll be here
any minute.
- Calm down, Hector.
- We haven't won this race for years.
It's time to restore
the family honor, Golly!
Here they come.
Right on time,
Kilwillie.
Lovely day,
old chap.
Yes, isn't it?
Well... Where is he?
- Where's who?
- Why, Archie, of course.
Aren't you here to
declare your intention
- To race against me?
- Well, not you, Hector.
The Flight of the Maiden
Boat Race
Is between the Laird
of Kilwillie Castle
And the Laird
of Glenbogle.
Oh, dear.
( theme music playing )
Kilwillie:... And in
accordance with the custom,
I invite the Laird
and the man of his choice
To race against me
and the man of my choice
To rescue a fair maiden.
That's me.
Do you, as a true
and honest man,
Undertake to accept
this solemn challenge
As is your right
and duty?
- He's worse than a wedding.
- Hector: Answer him, man!
- What do I say?
- I do.
Well?
Oh... I do.
I very much do.
This race has been rowed the
same way for nearly 200 years.
Father, I really don't
have time for all this.
Oh, in that case I'll tell
Kilwillie I'm taking your place.
The Laird has to rise
to the challenge.
Besides, Archie used to
be jolly good at rowing.
Your grandfather,
there was an oarsman.
Won this race
every time.
I'm expecting these people
from Glasgow any minute.
- What was that?
- Oh, nothing for you to worry about.
Who are these people
you're meeting?
They're coming to help Archie
market the spring water.
It's nothing sinister.
Of course it's sinister!
They're from Glasgow.
Why don't you go
and enjoy yourself?
- How, exactly?
- Oh, I don't know.
Shoot something.
That usually cheers you up.
Man on radio: Later we'll be talking to
the Chief Executive of the Highland Council
To find out what role the Highlands has
to play in the new, devolved Scotland
And ask whether rule
from Westminster
Will simply be replaced
by rule from Edinburgh.
Man 2:
Don't trust anyone.
Don't trust them, says Davey,
but who can you trust then?
Man 3: Certainly not
the Thistle defense.
After two superbly crafted
goals in the first half,
They snatched defeat from the
jaws of victory last night,
Going down 3-2 against
a revived Clydebank.
All the Bankie's goals-
Yes!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Yes! Yes!
Yes!
I can just about
hear you, Archie.
I'm afraid we're lost.
I'm sorry, no photos. I've
only just heard the news myself,
And you can tell your colleague
I'm not ready to give interviews.
- Come again?
- Okay, yeah. Think I've got that.
See you in a bit then.
Yeah.
But I will say
I intend to win,
And when I do,
I'll do all I can
For the real people
of this area.
My mother
always warned me
Not to come
this far north.
I'll bet she also told you
to keep away from strange men.
( gasps )
I tell you, I'm away
from Glenbogle for good.
What has Lexie
done now?
Don't talk to me about women.
I'm done with women!
- Lexie: Is this your idea of a joke, Duncan?
- Sorry?
I found this hanging
in the washing line.
That must've given
you a nasty turn,
Great ugly face
just staring at you.
I'm used to that.
Spend all day round him.
Well?
It's got nothing
to do with me.
Well, someone
put it there.
Or something.
Have you never heard
of Red Bonnet?
- It's nonsense, Golly.
- You used to believe.
"please, Golly," you'd say,
"please tell us the tale of
Red Bonnet and his treasure. "
When I was six.
I didn't know you really
believed all that stuff.
Archie, lad, in matters
of the other world,
It's best to keep
an open mind.
That fish could be
the pointer to untold riches.
So could that
spring water project
If these people
do a good job.
Just make sure they get
a feel for the place,
Okay?
Archie.
( chuckles )
Hi, Fiona Lennox,
Lennox marketing.
- Man: Great costume.
- Oh, and this is Gavin.
Welcome to Glenbogle.
Thank you.
Hello.
Might actually win this year
with you and Archie rowing.
Aye, it'd be nice
to go out on a bang.
- "go out"?
- I'm leaving.
Right. The best way is to
decide where the door is,
Put one foot in front of the
other and pass through it,
Taking care to open it, of course.
No, I mean for good.
Why is that then?
Well...
I've always felt I was born
to live a more exciting life,
Like the song says,
"in a city that never sleeps. "
- Such as?
- Dundee.
A place where I can discover
my true potential.
What did you have in mind,
particle physics?
Mock all you like.
I'm born
for greater things.
Lexie, dear,
I'm looking for
The biggest cake tin
we've got.
( stammering )
I- listen,
There are things
I have to be doing, you know?
Just one more.
Great.
- And again.
- Fiona: And, uh...
This what we did
For the Pit Lochry
Spring Water.
Right.
Great.
We'll have to do
your logo
And find the right image
for the artwork-
Don't tell her
anything, Archie!
You lot don't waste
any time, do you?
Katrina, this is
Fiona. She's-
From the press.
I'm sorry, Archie.
I wanted to tell you myself.
Why is Golly
posing like that?
- Like what?
- Look to me. To me.
Like he's in an ad
for shortbread.
Oh, not shortbread-
water.
A marketing company.
I found them
in the yellow pages.
And their master plan
Is to put Golly's
hairy legs on the label?
- They're just trying to capture
a feel for the place. - What?
To attract
outside investment.
Outside investment
means outside control.
The only reason I agreed
to help you with this
Was because the spring could
mean jobs for people round here.
So how else are we
gonna raise the money?
I've been selected
as candidate
For the local
council election.
Excuse me.
"well done, Katrina.
You must be so pleased. "
How much time is
this gonna take up?
Archie, you're not
my employer.
Anyway, it's
the school holidays.
I'll have plenty of time
to campaign.
Which will leave you no time at all
to help find funding for the spring.
We've got to think
long term.
I might be able to get us
funding if I win this election.
Great. I'll tell you what, as backup,
I'll buy
a lottery ticket.
Thanks very much for
the vote of confidence.
You know that
Kilwillie's
Held that council seat
for centuries.
Kilwillie's been systematically
exploiting this land-
All right, you're not
on the hustings yet.
Trust you not
to take an interest
In anyone but yourself.
Excuse me.
Um... I asked your butler
to take our bags to our rooms.
- "Butler"?
- Mm.
Hector, she wasn't
to know.
Father...
This is Fiona Lennox,
from Glasgow.
Katrina,
wait!
I- I'm so sorry,
Mr. MacDonald.
I- I just
didn't realize
Who you were.
( laughs weakly )
Why should you?
I'll fetch help
for the bags.
Look, I was only trying
to move things along a bit.
That's not the point.
Why didn't you tell me?
We talked about working on the
spring water project as a team.
If we're a team,
you should consult me
- On everything.
- I know. I'm sorry.
Look, why don't you come round
tonight and we'll talk strategy?
What about
Saatchi and Saatchi?
I'll tell them I need a
private chat about the project.
- Our project.
- Okay.
Tell you what, apparently a friendly
spirit brought us a pike last night.
- A what?
- Don't ask.
But I could...
Cook it, you know.
I better go and earn my supper
by looking over those accounts.
So that's where all
my mixed peel went.
Well...
Don't they
always say, dear,
The quickest way
to a man's heart
- Is through his stomach?
- Mother always said
It was straight through the
ribs with a boning knife.
Didn't think it was
anyone's birthday for a bit.
No. No, it's not.
Gavin, I think
you should let Archie
Show you around
the estate.
Mm.
Super.
Careful with that.
It's expensive equipment.
Oh, uh...
Who's that?
Uh, it's Duncan.
Very cute.
Don't waste
your time on him,
He isn't interested
in lassies.
Is that so?
Hi.
Hello.
I was told there
was a fax machine.
Okay.
Listen, I'm sorry
about my behavior earlier.
It must've seemed
a bit odd.
It's okay. Archie
explained everything.
Did he now?
Good old Archie.
You must be thrilled
to be selected, though.
Congratulations.
Do you know, you're the
first person to say that?
Well, I know
how much it means.
Really?
Oh, I've been in
the party for years.
Often thought about
standing myself, but...
Never quite
had the time or...
Maybe the bottle.
Anyway, win or lose,
You're doing a really
good thing, Katrina.
Well, thank you
very much.
So, Roger, did Kilwillie send
you down here to spy on us?
Leave the lad alone.
He's here just to help
with the launching site.
So... Roger... How
often do you work out?
People around here should
be running their own affairs,
Running the estate,
the spring water scheme,
Instead of tolerating
some outdated feudal regime.
You make it sound like
Glenbogle's still in the dark ages.
Well, it is.
Take this silly boat race
they're having tomorrow.
- A boat race?
- Grown men pretending to rescue
Defenseless maidens
from across the loch.
It just sounds
like a bit of... Fun.
Well, it is.
But it's backward-looking.
It's like when we play
the English at football,
All those banners saying
"Remember Bannockburn. "
When are we going
to forget about the past
And do something
about the future?
So, what's
your game plan
For the election?
- Game plan?
- Campaign strategy?
I take it
you have one?
You know,
living round here,
You forget how fantastic the scenery is.
I can manage!
- I said I can-
- aah!
Roger! Are you
all right?
It was an accident!
Yes, it's the ring,
all right.
And what's so special
about it?
It's the Laird's
ring, Archie,
Passed down through
generations.
To my eternal shame,
I lost it some years ago.
Now you've got it
back again.
- It's Kilwillie's now.
- What?
Tradition says the ring belongs
to the clan that finds it.
And Kilwillie's man
found it.
You're joking. Surely
you can prove it's ours.
I don't think your 16th century ancestor
Kept the receipt,
Archie.
16th century?
Must be worth
a fortune.
This could be the answer
to all our problems.
My father
gave me that ring.
His father
gave it to him,
Just as every Laird did
for nearly 400 years.
There are more important
things in life than money,
And even if
we still did have it,
I'd never sell it.
Never, do you hear?
I was only thinking
of him... Of all this.
I know.
So what do you know about
the other candidates then?
There's only one
worth worrying about,
And he's over there.
Angus Kilwillie.
It's quite an interesting
little trinket.
Well done. Thank you.
It's Red Bonnet
you have to thank.
Another wives' tale.
All the same, best
to keep an open mind
In matters of
the other world.
There's only one world that
matters, Golly, and this is it.
A man's got to take control
of his own destiny.
Sitting councilor, local
landowner, and robber baron.
He's had the place
in his pocket for years.
- Fiona: And what sleaze do we have on him?
- Sorry?
You know, dirt.
Scandal.
Hang on, you're not
in Glasgow now.
We don't run those type
of campaigns around here.
Oh, really? So how come he's
been in office so long then?
I bet he has his tricky
little ways and means.
Miss Finlay.
I gather you're
standing against me.
How did you know that? I
only found out this morning.
Oh... I've got
my ways and means.
( chuckling )
so what's your platform?
Oh, you'll find out
soon enough, Mr. Kilwillie.
Going to throw our last
dastardly landowners out, are you?
Oh, dear me. Better get home
and pull up my drawbridge.
( chuckling )
Well, good luck.
And may the best man win.
Now that you mention it,
there was a bit of gossip
About him and a certain lady
from Loch Nacree.
- Hah!
- Hector!
Haven't you heard
of knocking?
If you want to get rid
of me, it's less messy
To sue for divorce!
What are you playing at?
- All is not lost!
- Hector, please!
The only way to get that
ring back is by combat!
- Combat?
- I shall challenge Kilwillie!
You will do
no such thing!
( growls )
Hector,
now get a grip.
You are not
a child anymore.
Really? Then why does
everybody treat me like one?
"don't you worry
about it, Hector. "
"none of your business, Hector. "
"go and play with your toys, Hector. "
Well, I know
when I'm not needed!
Hector, I just came
to tell you that I...
Made you a cake.
( door slams )
So, no one special
back in Glasgow then,
Nice boy like you?
I've just come out of
a messy relationship.
Really?
What was he like?
It's always the cute ones, isn't it?
Why's he always
so miserable?
He thinks that
a place like this
Has got nothing to
offer someone like him.
He's right there.
- Hey, Duncan.
- What?
How about I get
some shots of you?
Oh.
Sure.
Once she starts with this election
nonsense, I'll never see her.
Then stop referring
to it as nonsense.
People find
different things important.
You should encourage
Katrina more,
Listen to her more.
That's the secret of
a good partnership.
- I suppose you're right.
- Isn't that how it works with Justine?
- That's different.
- Well, of course it is.
She's your girlfriend.
It must be a very
understanding relationship
If it can work while
you're both so far apart.
Yes, it must be.
You must miss her
very much.
Right. I'll just go check on that fish.
Oh, tell Lexie
I'll be eating upstairs.
- You sure you don't mind?
- Of course not.
I'll leave you and Katrina
to have a good time.
It's a business dinner,
mother.
Of course it is.
Katrina will
never eat that.
I'll have you know
this is a big delicacy
In certain parts
of Europe,
A recipe known
only to a few.
Anyway, I called Justine
for some advice.
Oh, really? "darling, I'm doing
a candlelight dinner for Katrina.
Could you help me
perk up my pike?"
Just shut up
and drain the veg.
But you did tell her
who it was for, right?
In your own time.
Hello?
I can hardly hear you.
- You're an hour late.
- What? The line's really bad.
Look, I'll come over
to your place.
Oh...
Archie, I am so sorry.
This is so embarrassing.
Fiona and I
just got talking.
How could you forget?
Fiona was helping me
draw up my manifesto.
She's in the party.
I'm so sorry.
Fiona's working for me.
I thought she
was working for us.
( clock striking )
( clock ticking loudly )
Could you pass
the salt, please?
- Pepper?
- No, thanks.
He was a magnificent
sight, my father...
Thrashing his way
through the waters.
Never lost a boat race-
Ever.
Fine huntsman, too.
Everybody looked up to him.
People still needed him...
Until the day he died.
Who needs me, eh?
- I-
- I was just-
- After you.
- Go ahead.
I just wanted to say
I'm really pleased
You were nominated
for the election.
Thank you.
So you think you might
be able to get us
The money for the spring
if you win?
Listen, could we
discuss this tomorrow?
It's just that Fiona-
I promised her
I wouldn't be long.
Fine.
I thought you wanted
to talk about it tonight.
Come on, the spring's not
going to dry up overnight.
- No, but Justine's patience might.
- Oh.
So that's what
this is about.
Sorry?
You want to get the spring
Up and running as soon
as possible
So you can skip back
to your girlfriend in London.
- I do not skip. - Where you can manage
your swanky restaurant
And get back to what
you probably call normality.
You seem very sure
of what I want.
You know you're not
going to stay here forever.
Go on then.
Tell me you've decided
to stay and run the estate.
Tell me that this
is more important to you
Than anything else.
I'm as cynical
as the next man,
But best to keep
an open mind
Where the other world
is concerned.
If it exists,
I hope it makes more
sense than this one.
Go on, Golly.
Now, take Red Bonnet.
Legend has it that he
steals into houses
In the dead of night.
He means no harm.
He leaves you a clue
To where a treasure
is to be found,
Then returns
the next night
To claim some supper
as a reward.
- Oh, come on.
- Duncan: No, Golly's right.
The fish was a sign.
It led to the ring.
Okay, okay, I'm sorry to apply
logic to the situation,
But if he was hungry,
why didn't he just eat the fish?
Maybe he's
a vegetarian spirit.
Ha ha. People always mock
what they're afraid of.
Ain't that the truth?
Who could be afraid
of a little man in a red cap?
The forest is full of less
kindly spirits than Red Bonnet.
Have you
seen them, Golly?
- No.
- Archie: You see?
Nor would I want to.
But I've heard them.
In the night.
Whispering.
Caterwauling.
Coming from nowhere.
Coming from everywhere.
Ah, it's just the wind
or small furry creatures.
Maybe.
But have you not heard
The story of Barrach-Bayne,
the Mad MacDonald?
Didn't like women.
Was that the one?
He spent the night alone in the
woods, day before his wedding.
He was to marry the daughter
of a neighboring chief
At the Great Clan Gathering
of 1611.
What happened?
Well, they say he
lost his mind that night...
Or had it taken from him.
The next day,
at the gathering,
He lifted up his betrothed
like this...
And wailing like a banshee,
Pitched her headlong
into the Kinrothie bog.
Near brought down
the MacDonalds.
Led to 40 years warfare
in this glen.
Way I heard it, she looked better when she
came out of the bog than when she went in.
Nevertheless...
No MacDonald since then...
Has ever spent
the night alone...
In those woods.
It wouldn't
bother me if I did.
Well, it wouldn't!
I'm up at the crack of dawn
for the boat race.
You think I'm scared,
don't you?
Right, let's do it.
Right, this'll do.
Torch.
You sure you still
want to do this?
Yeah, it's just what I need-
a night out of that madhouse.
Okay, it's all yours.
Duncan:
Sounds a bit silly.
Go on, it'll be a laugh,
And it might just be the
image we need for the label.
Oh, pardon me.
I was looking for Golly.
I'll go and get
my stuff.
Duncan...
You do know
about Gavin, don't you?
I know he's
the first person
Ever took me
seriously.
Oh?
Aye. And he agrees
I don't belong here.
Reckons I should
move to Glasgow,
Find myself.
What if you're not there
when you get there?
Oh, go on, mock.
You're just jealous 'cause
you're gonna spend your whole life
Skivvying here
for other people
While I'm-
I'm moving on.
( sighs )
You're right.
Of course.
I wish you
all the best.
But may I give you
a bit of advice?
What?
It's just...
It's best to try and be
like those big city types-
You know, if you
want to fit in.
- How do you mean?
- Well...
For a start,
they're very touchy-feely.
Lots of...
Hugging and stuff.
- Aye, I've seen them.
- Mm.
What else?
So they know
you're confident,
They need eye contact.
Long, lingering
eye contact.
Right.
Molly's voice: Pull yourself
together. You're not a child any more.
Hector: Then why does
everyone treat me like one?
"don't worry about it, Hector. "
"none of your business, Hector. "
"go play with
your toys, Hector. "
Well, I know
when I'm not needed.
( twig snaps )
( faint footsteps running )
( pot clanks )
( lock turns )
( owl hooting )
( clanking )
- Ow!
- Oh!
Aaah!
- I couldn't sleep, so I came
down to add some walnuts.
Maybe Red Bonnet
doesn't care for walnuts.
It was Hector's
favorite.
The thing is,
We've all been
ignoring him lately.
How can anyone
ignore Hector?
We all run round him
like blue-
Like people running round
after Hector.
I know, like people
running round
After a child.
He hates that.
Poor old Hector.
I'm more to blame
than anyone.
He's been sneaking off
at night lately,
Which he does
when he's feeling...
Thoughtful.
I should have
just sat him down
And given him
a good talking to,
Told him that we all
need him round here.
Instead, I made this
stupid cake! ( crying )
- How long's this been here then?
- About half an hour.
I used to love
night fishing.
I don't get much chance
to do it in London, though.
I'm sure London has other
nighttime attractions.
( yawning )
yeah, I guess so.
You ought to be in bed
getting a good night's sleep,
Preparing your mind and
body for tomorrow's battle.
It's not a battle,
it's a boat race.
How did that ring
end up in the loch?
Didn't you hear?
Red Bonnet put it there.
- Father.
- I lost it swimming.
Stupid thing to do.
"damn stupid thing
to do, Hector,"
My father said.
"you've really let me down.
I despair of you ever
amounting to anything. "
I wanted to explain it was an
accident, it could happen to anybody,
That I was sorry.
Sorry I'd let him down.
Well, why didn't you?
Because he was
a cantankerous old git
Who was impossible
to talk to.
Can you imagine having
a father like that?
No. No, I can't.
- That was-
- shh!
Red Bonnet.
We just saw Red Bonnet.
Come on.
- ( Archie snorts )
- ye gods.
Now I've seen everything.
Gavin: That's it, Duncan.
More of that. More!
Yeah. Great!
( laughs )
That's it.
Right arm up.
What's Duncan
playing at?
Golly was right.
Some things are beyond
human comprehension.
Duncan: It's been a
real stroke of fortune...
Me meeting you.
I feel
like I can-
I can see
my whole future
Stretching out
in front of me.
- The real me.
- Good man.
That's the first step...
Admitting to yourself
who you are.
Aye.
And you'll meet plenty
more like you in Glasgow.
Thanks for all
your advice.
No problem.
You've really changed
my outlook.
I was thinking...
When I move to Glasgow,
Could I stay with you
for a while?
Oh, Duncan...
I'm really flattered.
Flattered?
Look...
It's not you.
It's me.
- Oi.
- What are you doing here?
Fiona and I got so wrapped
up in the manifesto,
Molly said I
could stay the night.
You look rough.
Well, all in all,
it was a pretty rough night.
I said some things
last night-
Yeah, well, you were
probably right.
Look, I've got a...
Race to row.
Good luck.
Oh, where is everyone?
( lightly snoring )
I love you,
you silly old fool.
I better go.
Golly's taking me to the woods.
We may not be able to get
your father's ring back,
But at least we can try
and win this race for him.
Mother, you're a genius!
The race!
- Lexie: How did the photo shoot
go last night? - Smashing.
In fact, better than I
could've possibly imagined.
- Really?
- Yeah. It went so well,
Duncan's agreed to come to
Glasgow as soon as possible.
- He's gonna move in with me.
- You're joking!
I'm not.
Duncan's not quite the
full shilling sometimes.
- Is that so?
- He's easily led astray.
You'd have firsthand
experience of that, would you?
- I just don't want to see him get hurt.
- Why is that, then?
Uh, he's a pal.
Real-ly?
Look, he'd be lost
in Glasgow.
He'd miss all his mates
and... We'd miss him.
Oh, Dunc!
Lexie here has got
something to tell you.
Uh, yeah.
Good luck
in the boat race.
Yeah, thanks.
( deep voice )
give 'em hell, big boy!
Has Archie
lost his bottle?
Thought you weren't
interested in this.
Oh, could be
quite fun.
Here's Archie.
I thought you'd thrown in
the towel, lad!
Golly: Right, let it begin!
The maidens are in position.
Hold on, Golly.
Kilwillie,
I challenge you to combat for
the ring of my forefathers.
I beg your pardon?
I wanna race you for
that ring you're wearing.
That's out of the question.
It's mine by right.
You're not scared,
are you?
Believe me, Archie,
All the incentive
in the world
Won't help you win.
Right.
Let battle commence!
Stop!
Now what?
Kilwillie,
I challenge you to combat
For the ring
of my forefathers.
You don't need the swords.
I've made the challenge already.
- We're racing for the ring.
- Oh. Why didn't you say so?
- Move over, Duncan.
- What?
Take those, will you?
Archie, as Laird,
It is your privilege to choose
your comrade in oars.
You can all row together,
for all I care. Roger!
Hector:
Good god!
There's nothing in the rules
against it. Is there, Golly?
It's a stealth boat.
That man is unbelievable!
Right, that does it.
Do you know
where he picks up
The so-called maidens?
I think so.
Why?
First rule
of politics:
Do it to them before
they do it to you.
Come on.
Right. The maidens are on
the other side of the loch.
The Laird must accompany
the maiden back,
And the first team
to take their seats
Is the winner.
Are our warriors ready?
Oh, get on with it.
On your marks...
Get set...
Oh, they must have been
practicing all year.
Stroke.
We've got no chance.
It just doesn't
seem right.
Look, you don't want
Kilwillie to win, do you?
Archie's really cute,
isn't he?
Is he?
You're finished,
MacDonald!
You're past it!
I want that ring,
Kilwillie!
It's no good.
Nil desperandum!
( camera clicking )
Well?
Kilwillie's walking it.
Look...
This Gavin...
You do know that he's-
Lexie,
I didn't
really know it...
But I've been waiting for
someone like Gavin all my life.
And I'm really looking forward
to living in a big city.
Duncan,
you'll hate Glasgow.
It's full of scary
and selfish people,
And that's
just my family.
Just because you
couldn't take the pace
Doesn't mean to say
that I won't.
Anyway, Gavin will be
there to see me through.
You've made up
your mind then?
- Nothing to keep me here.
- Of course there is.
Nobody
wants you to go.
I don't want you to go.
There.
I said it.
Are you sure
this is going to work?
Look, we're just going
for a walk in the woods.
He doesn't have to stop and chat
if he doesn't want to.
Flora: Daddy!
Molly: Archie?
Archie-ee-ee!
- Daddy!
- I'm coming, flora!
Woman spookily:
Kilwillie...
Woman 2 eerily:
Loch Nacree, Kilwillie...
- Right, that's it.
- Flora: Roger, I'm here!
Come and take me now,
Roger! Ha ha!
Steady on, dear,
it's only pretend.
Oh good- Roger!
- Where's daddy?
- Come on.
Whoa!
( laughing )
Roger!
Come on, Roger!
( giggling )
Aw- come on!
( calling softly )
Kilwillie...
Loch Nacree...
- Kilwillie...
- Remember Loch Nacree...
- Stop!
- Kilwillie...
- Who are you?
- Loch Nacree...
Where-
where are you?!
Mother.
Hector, what
are you doing here?
No time for conversation,
woman. Come on.
Tell us about the lady
from Loch Nacree...
Who are you?
Loch Nacree...
And what about
Loch Nacree?
I haven't seen that girl
for years!
It was all lies anyway!
Daddy!
( echoing )
Loch... Loch... Loch...
( echo continues )
Daddy!
They've caught up!
We're going to lose!
Come on, Archie.
Come on.
MacDonald! I don't know
what's going on here!
Just- get in,
will you?!
Move!
Get a move on, Archie.
They're not far behind.
Golly: I don't believe
it. We're winning.
- Roger's catching up fast.
- Come on!
Lexie:
Come on, Archie!
Hector: Come on, Archie.
For the ring. For the ring!
- Come on, Roger! Get a move on!
- Faster!
Oh, put your back
into it, man!
- Flora: Roger, come on!
- Lexie: Come on, Archie, row.
- Come on, come on!
- Come on, Archie!
- Stroke!
- Behind!
Come on, boys!
Katrina: Come on.
Lexie: Oh, Archie, go on, hurry up.
Oh, you can do it!
Show some muscle!
Move it!
Stroke!
- ( cheering )
- come on, Archie!
I am so proud of you.
Well done, arch!
( laughing )
Well done, Archie.
Lexie:
Oh, Duncan!
- Hmm.
Oh, darling.
Thank you.
Hector: Disembodied voices
in the wood, you say?
Quite right.
They were all over the place.
What were
they saying?
I couldn't quite
make it out.
It was a...
Was a damn strange affair.
Hector: There'll be a
rational explanation.
'course there will.
We all thought
That Red Bonnet
had brought us a fish
Until we discovered that Hector
had been off night fishing.
Didn't catch a damn thing
all week though.
Well then, who
did bring the fish?
Ah, well, you see,
there's no accounting
For the ways
of the other world.
Slainte.
You were right.
She's gutted at the thought
of me going.
She's crazy
about you, man.
A bit of unfair,
kidding around that-
You and me were...
Well, you know.
What, after she tried
to set you up last night?
You're too good
for her.
I still think you could
make a go of it in Glasgow.
They do have women
there too, you know.
Aye, but I
couldn't leave here
Knowing how much
Lexie needs me.
She'd be lost
without me.
All right, Lex?
Don't "all right" me! I've
been listening to you two.
- Oh dear.
- You sneaky little-
You can talk.
"they love eye contact. "
you didn't tell me why.
Well, you can
run off to Glasgow
For all I care.
What you asked me
yesterday
About whether I'll be
staying around much longer...
- Duncan: It's your fault, Lexie!
- The truth is I don't know.
- Duncan: You bet I can!
- Lexie: I'll catch you!
Right.
The thing is, I'm no longer
absolutely sure that I won't be either.
This place, it gets
under your skin.
Well, it's always
been under mine.
That's why
I want to do
What I can
for the place.
Give something back,
you know?
That's what
my manifesto's about.
"by far the most
compelling reason
For transferring the estate
to the control of the tenants
Is the damage that has accrued
to the land and resources
Due to years of exploitation
and incompetence
- by the incumbent family. "
- Fiona wrote that bit.
Yeah, but you think it,
don't you?
- You know it's true.
- Do I indeed?
You said so yourself.
This place has been run
into the ground.
Oh, and you're gonna save
it single-handed, are you?
If that's
what it takes, yes.
Oh, I just can't
believe you've done this!
- I haven't done anything.
- Working together, you said.
And so that means
I can't criticize you?
Gavin: So...
How often
do you work out?
Hey?
( theme music playing )
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0