Ahh... mine, I think.
Just get...
dirty magazines,
Hector?
Huh!
At your age!
Please!
Good morning, Archie.
( theme music playing )
It's from Lizzie.
Is she coming up?
I'm sure my sister has better
things to do than rush up here
just because
it's my birthday.
Archie, it's not just any
birthday. It's a special birthday.
I just wish everyone would
forget about it- I want to.
And what about you, father?
Isn't this your cue
for a special speech?
- What speech is that, lad? - The same
speech we've heard every day this week.
The one that goes,
"when I was your age,
I'd liberated europe from the
hun and sired half a polo team. "
Archie, you're a grown man.
You don't need me
interfering in your future.
Right.
That's settled then.
No fuss.
Both:
Good.
Gather the troops, Lexie.
Boathouse, five minutes.
Ahh...
Duncan: It's just that I thought
I'd have more
responsibility.
Did you?
I mean, assistant
head ranger...
I'm still
just a skivvy!
Will you change
the record!
It's Archie's ear you
should be bending, not mine.
Aye, and maybe he doesn't
think I'm up to it.
Duncan, you'll never
know unless you ask.
Report for duty.
What duty?
Children's
party detail.
Archie: You've done a great job
setting up the nature trail, Fergal.
Fergal: It'll be good to try it out,
before the paying
punters start turning up.
Yeah,
that's fine by me.
Cool.
I'll tell Katrina.
Katrina?
Yeah.
She said the kids
would love to see
around the estate.
You're seeing quite
a lot of her, aren't you?
Ha! Not as much
as I'd like to.
No need to wait.
Now, we need to find the
fairy lights, the streamers-
and there's a banner
around the house somewhere.
We have to move quickly,
'cause Archie's going to move
all this stuff out today
so the contractors can move in.
Hey... ha ha!
Look at this.
Here.
( Molly laughing )
What a party that was!
Rained all day, but we still
had the most wonderful time.
Remember, Golly?
I remember a young lassie
eating too much cake
and throwing up
into the fruit punch.
Wee Jamie, he-
oh, it's all right.
You can talk about Jamie.
I wish people would
talk about him more.
Aww...
this was his.
It's funny. Something about
the sound of children
I remember most.
Shouting, arguing,
giggling, laughing.
All just seemed to say
life is wonderful.
Oh, Hector used to love
racing these with the boys.
This house
was so full of joy.
Then it's time
it was again.
We can start with
Archie's party tomorrow.
It'll be the best MacDonald
birthday party in the history of...
Both:
MacDonald birthday parties.
Hector: Well, of course,
old chap, why not?
Pop over today.
Shall we say at 4:00?
Excellent.
Thanks for ringing.
Archie will hit the roof
when he sees this!
He'll thank me
for it later on.
We've got
to get him hitched!
Good lord,
by the time I was 30,
I had three children!
I know.
I was there.
Of course you were.
He's got to live up
to his responsibility-
- ( rings )
- Hello.
Oh, hello,
your lordship.
Yes... yea-
of course you can
bring your daughter over
to meet the laird.
Yes, absolutely delighted.
Ha ha ha!
Yes, bye, your lordship.
( huffs )
Katrina: You know, I
could've saved you a trip.
I've got to go up
to the big house later
to pay my rent
and tug my forelock.
I wanted to tell you the
good news straightaway.
Kids'll have a great time tomorrow.
Yeah.
Thanks.
And you know...
I think you deserve
a reward.
Oh? And what did you have in mind?
Hmm... coffee?
Well, I've a million
things to do.
You can thank me
another time.
Without MI5
observing us.
- If you'd just wait in here? Thanks.
- Thank you.
Molly?
Come here.
Come see this. You're
never gonna believe this.
Look...
they're all
queueing up in here.
What? Oh!
Go get Archie
immediately.
Right.
Archie...
I was wondering...
as assistant
head ranger...
I was think-
I was hoping
that I'd get
to be showing some
of the trekking
parties around.
Forget it.
Bad idea.
No, it's a good idea.
You know the place
as well as anyone.
I'll talk to Fergal
about it.
Right!
Thanks!
I won't
let you down.
Arch, Hector wants to see you in the
ballroom, matter of extreme urgency.
Thank you, Alexandra.
( clock striking )
- Lovely to see you again, Gordon.
- You too, old chap.
Molly:
The, um...
the last time
that we saw you,
the girls were...
how old?
- Both: 12.
- ( giggling )
That'll be all, Lexie.
( laughs pleasantly )
So, um...
wh-what do you do
these days?
What do you mean?
Why don't I show you
around the house, Gordon?
Lexie: Just because you've
got some fancy new title-
assistant head ranger,
with special responsibilities
for guided tours!
Doesn't give you the right
to take food without asking.
I told you-
I didn't!
So that salmon just uncooked
itself, and swam away, did it?
Golly: How long has
food been going missing?
A couple of days now.
And I know
this is premature...
but we may as well
get it out of the way.
- I'd prefer July.
- But September would suit me better.
I'm sorry,
I don't understand.
For a wedding.
For a-
just what is
going on here?
Your father says here
you'd be anxious
to do it before
the year is out.
Sorry, it's all
been a mistake.
Mistake?
I am not up for auction, thank you.
Goodbye.
Father!
Hector: I'm only trying to help!
A chap your age needs
a woman by his side!
I have told you
countless times,
when and indeed if
I decide to marry-
- if?
- It will be to somebody I care about!
What about that Justine woman?
You were with her for years!
- You hated each other!
- I did not! She had a spark!
I admired that.
Wide enough hips.
Oh, so that's
what this is about!
Not my future bride,
but your future grandchild!
You have a responsibility
to your lineage!
Stay out of my private
life, do you hear?!
If you don't,
I'll- I'll-
- I'll have the snip!
- Snip?
I will have
my lineage cut off!
( laughs nervously )
Hector.
This house is tainted by a
lack of moral responsibility.
How nice to see
you too, Katrina.
( car door shuts )
Poor old Archie.
You don't have to have
time for dynasties,
but you must find
some time for yourself.
Forget about this
place for five minutes.
What do they say
these days?
Chill out?
While you're still young.
If money were no object,
what would you buy?
You know that.
I'd secure a future
for Glenbogle.
I don't mean that.
What would you buy for you?
Well, I've always
fancied a Porsche.
Really?
Yeah, a red one.
Ahem-hem!
I'll need some help
to set up the beach
for the party.
Oh, sorry.
I've got my assistant head
ranger duties to perform.
I've agreed to let Duncan take
our first group around the estate.
It'll be like
"The Blair Witch Project"
all over again.
( giggles )
Take no notice,
Duncan.
You'll be great.
Anyway, the teachers
will be with him.
- Teachers?
- Yep.
It's the kids from the school
you'll be showing round.
Did you say kid-
children?
15 sweet little
10-year-olds.
It's a party
of children, Dunc,
not a party
of ax murderers.
( screams )
Katrina: You know it
was a mistake, don't you?
The bank cocked up
the direct debits.
Yeah, I know. I'm sorry
about the threatening letter.
It goes out to any of the
tenants who get into arrears.
Just another one
of your tenants now, am I?
You know
I didn't mean...
I gather Fergal's asked you to
bring the kids over tomorrow.
- It was my idea actually.
- Right.
It must be good having
someone like Fergal around.
Really seems to know
how to make the place work.
Certainly understands
people.
You included?
What goes on between me
and Fergal
is my business,
don't you think?
- You'd better come quick.
- What is it?
There's one of your tenants
in my kitchen,
saying that you chucked
him out into the street.
At least you understand
responsibility.
Loyalty. Duty.
( horn honking )
( vehicle approaching )
Hector MacDonald?
Yes?
Kieran Conway.
We spoke
on the phone earlier.
Oh, yes.
I'm afraid you've had
a wasted journey.
This is my daughter Tanya.
Absolutely enchanted.
I'm sorry,
mister, um...
Tosh.
Tosh McKellan.
I don't understand what
you're talking about.
I have never evicted
any of my tenants.
- Not you. Your father.
- I might've known.
Fergal: Evicted you from where?
My cottage.
By the west wood.
Is that one of the ones you've
been renting out to tourists?
They've been vacant
for years.
Sent me to a home.
I didn't want to go there!
Wanted to stay in the house
I lived in 46 years!
I am sorry, but you are going
to have to go back to the home.
I'll not go back there!
You're the laird.
I am your responsibility.
You can't stay here.
Archie, he can bunk
down with me tonight.
We can just sort it out in the morning.
Right, thanks.
Arch, you're wanted.
Oh, now what?
- You've got guests.
- Guests!
An elderly gentleman,
and his young,
very unmarried daughter.
Right.
( men laughing )
Sorry to disappoint, but
I am going to my room,
and I shall emerge sometime
after my 70th birthday.
You have had a wasted
journey, I'm afraid.
I told my father
of my intention
to take a lifetime vow of chastity
some months ago,
but he seems
to have forgotten!
Archie, may I introduce you
to the Earl of Nissalagh,
from the beautiful
Republic of Ireland?
Good night.
And may I introduce
my daughter,
Tanya?
Hello.
You got something
on your mind?
Oh, it's just...
these kids
coming tomorrow.
What?
Well...
you might find this
hard to believe,
me being a man
of the world and that,
but when I was a kid,
I was...
an object of fun
and ridicule.
Surely not.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Butt of the jokes.
The guy that had
his bike stolen,
the itching powder
down his sports-
it's just 'cause I wanted
to learn stuff, you know.
I never...
I never had any friends.
Hector:
No, no, I insist!
You'll both
stay the night.
Well... that's
jolly decent of you.
Not at all.
Go through.
I'll get Lexie to take
the port to the library.
Going rather well,
don't you think?
I thought Archie told you
to stop this skulduggery.
Listen, that chap has
a huge estate in Ireland.
Now, I don't want
to be vulgar,
but an alliance would solve
all our financial problems.
Hector, this isn't
the middle ages.
People don't marry
to secure dynasties
and increase
their assets.
Archie's got enough
on his plate
without worrying about
the precious family line.
Besides, you can't just throw
two people together like that!
- We were thrown together.
- Yes, and I wish I could say
that it was love
at first sight,
but it wasn't!
We grew together,
and I learned
to know what a warm,
kindhearted,
wonderful man
that you are,
and then...
and only then,
did I fall deeply
in love with you.
Archie deserves
that chance.
- ( laughter )
- ah.
We thought
we'd go for a walk.
- It's such a lovely night.
- Hector: yes.
( humming wedding march )
This is stunning.
You're so lucky.
You must have views
like this at home.
Yeah.
Yeah, but I never
have time to look.
Yep, I know
that feeling.
I hope you don't
mind me saying so,
but you...
you don't seem obvious laird material.
Well, I wasn't
supposed to be.
I had an older brother,
Jamie. He died.
Oh. I'm sorry.
I was kind of thrown into
this laird stuff.
Mostly I've been trying
to prove myself to my father.
What about you,
your old man the same?
Yeah, I guess so.
I'm all he's got.
Well, you must have
more time on your hands
now that you've managed
to turn the estate around.
Yeah, true.
It was tough,
though.
Had to sell off
the family silver.
Tell me about it.
Of course, father made me
keep some stuff back,
things he could
never part with.
Bet Hector did the same.
Well, if he has,
he's never told me about it.
The truth is,
we are stony broke.
- Broke?!
- Completely skint.
They're pinning all their
hopes on this visitor center.
Damn!
We'd best get out
of here first thing.
No. I have spent
a fortune on this,
hiring that car, the suit,
those diamonds-
I'm not leaving
without some compensation.
They haven't got anything
worth nicking, dad!
Don't you believe it.
Aristos always say
they're broke.
But they never mention the
Gainsborough stashed away in the attic.
Look,
I'll work
on the old duffer tomorrow.
You charm the lad.
( slams )
Welcome to Glenbogle.
My name is...
Dunc.
I'm called...
I'm called Duncan,
and this place
is called Glenbogle.
So Archie doesn't know
about the party?
No, so whatever it takes, just
keep him away from the beach.
- How will I do that?
- You'll think of something.
- Archie: gone?
- Fergal: yeah.
He bedded down on my sofa last
night. This morning, no sign of him.
- Maybe he went back to the home?
- No chance.
We'll have to search
for him. Dunc?
Sorry, I've got to look
after the school kids.
I'll ask around.
Who's he?
Oh, don't you start.
They seem to be
getting on awfully well.
Ha ha ha!
Indeed.
So...
how many acres
do you have here?
About 38,500.
Ooh...
not a bad little plot.
Little? Ha ha!
How many acres do you have in Ireland?
Oh, give or take,
about... 50,000.
Excellent.
Still, this old pile of yours
is pretty impressive.
Yes, well...
it could do with a coat
of paint, I suppose.
( both chuckling )
- You're not fooling anyone.
- I'm not?
Keep this place looking
rundown, scare away the taxman.
Well...
still, it's always a
sign of true breeding,
keeping the really
expensive stuff
under lock and key.
Most unostentatious.
Well, never seen the need
to... flaunt one's wealth.
I've lots of antiques
hidden away.
Really?
Me too.
Oh, yes.
( children stepping down )
Quickly now.
Right.
Well.
Over to you,
Duncan.
Welcome to Glenbogle.
My name's Duncan,
and I'm your show here
to guide you-
I mean,
I'm your guide here
to show you around
this ancient and very...
old...
and beautiful estate.
Let's get started.
I'll catch up
later.
Come on.
Maybe Fergal's
found him.
Hi.
Happy birthday.
Thanks.
Hello.
Sorry. Katrina, this is Tanya.
Nice to meet you.
So, any special plans
for the big day?
Yes, we're playing
hide-and-seek
with an octogenarian
tenant.
- What?
- Fergal: okay, I found Tosh.
- oh, good.
- Not good.
Fergal:
Sorry, Archie,
he must've nicked
the chain from my place.
I'll not budge till you
give me my cottage back!
Be reasonable.
You can't stay here.
I claim
squatter's rights!
I'm calling
the police!
Katrina: He's your tenant,
your responsibility.
He's got to go! The
contractor's been paid
a fortune to sort
this place out!
He's a person
with feelings.
I'm sure Archie's doing
what's best for the estate.
You'd know all
about that, would you?
Fergal:
Okay, come on, Tosh.
Let's talk
about this outside.
I'll not budge
till you give me
my cottage back.
( sloshing )
Hector: Kieran?
Kieran?
Where are you,
old chap?
Ah, there you are,
old chap.
What have you got there?
"Robert the Bruce. "
Excellent.
Oh, Lexie!
Oh!
Do you need a hand?
I need several pairs.
Did you get
Archie's present?
Yes, red one. Pop up
headlights. The lot.
Mmm.
Archie?
They're gonna be on double
time in a couple hours.
Okay, okay.
What are you
gonna do?
He'll have to come out
when he's hungry, won't he?
( footsteps approaching )
He has to eat...
here you are, Tosh.
Excuse me.
There's ham and cheese.
I didn't know whether you
took sugar, so I didn't stir.
- She's very pretty.
- I'm sorry?
- Tanya: Katrina.
- How're you feeling?
Yes, I suppose she is.
What's the story?
She's just another one
of my tenants.
Duncan:
These trees are...
well, firs.
And these ones
over here are...
firs, too.
Duncan, they've
seen trees before.
Right.
One of the reasons that
this place is so important
is because...
of the amazing amount of...
wildlife.
You like animals,
right?
- Yes?
- Is this forest natural?
Or has it been replanted
by the landowners?
Children:
Hmmm?
This is mainly natural,
but if you like,
I can take you up
to our new
replanting project.
Children:
Nnnn...
Maybe not.
Bad idea.
Right.
Let's have a break.
( children laughing,
talking )
They hate me.
Of course they do.
You're an adult.
You're doing fine.
That room's out of bounds,
I'm afraid, old chap.
Buried treasure, eh?
My late son's room.
Family only, I'm afraid.
Come on over
to this music box.
It's over 100 years old.
( music box playing )
( children playing )
Okay,
my wee friends.
Time to go.
Right!
Back in line now!
Sometimes, they just need
to know who's boss.
Odd one out, eh?
What's your name?
Duncan.
I'll die here.
I have had
enough of this.
My father would not
have kicked him out!
That's what he did! I could still
have done a decent day's work.
You know
that's not true.
You tell him
what really happened.
I'll not budge.
What happened, Tosh?
My Annie died,
that's what happened.
Annie?
Without her, I-
I didn't cope so well.
The truth is
I went to pieces.
I'd always had her
beside me, 40-odd years.
But she went so sudden.
It was a bad time.
I stopped behaving
like a man.
Stopped looking
after meself.
Lost my self-respect.
They packed me off
to that place.
But I'm stronger now.
I could do
a day's work.
I want my dignity back.
I want my home back.
Thanks.
What for?
Asking a question
earlier.
That really helped
me out, that did.
Girls think it isn't cool
if you ask questions.
If you keep
asking questions,
you become
really clever.
You could be a...
you could be a doctor
or an astronaut, maybe.
Did you ask questions
at school?
Well, I used to.
But the other kids,
they...
they put me off.
I wish they hadn't.
I wish I'd kept
asking questions.
So you could've been
an astronaut?
( laughs )
Aye.
I think your job's
dead cool.
Can I have
your autograph?
Tosh, I would love
to help you, but...
I have other people
to think of.
Things have moved on since
you were a tenant here.
I wish I could
let you stay, but...
we just
can't afford it.
There was a time
when this estate
employed 100 workers
on the land,
and 50 in the house,
but...
well, now
we only have four.
If I don't balance
the books,
and make this place
pay, then...
no one'll have
a home here.
No one.
I'm sorry, Tosh.
I can't help you.
It's called autumn days,
the number's in the book.
Happy birthday to me.
Golly, you've been
saying recently
that you could do
with a hand.
You know, odd jobs
from time to time.
What?
Oh, aye, aye.
That's right.
And I was wondering how much
the council are paying
to keep Tosh
at that home?
I could ask them
if they'd pay
for the cottage
instead.
Well done,
Archie.
Right. I think you can
move back into your cottage.
Do you mean it?
Absolutely.
You'll not get it
for free, though.
Golly here
needs some help.
You're a top man, Archie.
You're taking a risk,
but I won't
let you down.
Tanya:
It just feels wrong.
These people,
they're up against it.
Archie has to make
this place work.
We've all got
to make a living.
It's not just
about the money, dad.
These are... decent folk.
They support each other.
They rally round.
Has this young lad
turned your head, huh?
Listen, we might
never get a chance
like this again.
They'll all be at Archie's party later.
We'll grab what we can,
and then be gone
before he blows
his candles out.
I need your help,
darling.
Hi there.
Hi.
Do you still want to see
around the place?
( children talking )
Don't let the dogs
eat the food.
( lock turns )
You're very quiet.
That's the pot calling
the kettle black.
Yeah, I suppose
you're right.
Listen, thank you for
making my birthday...
well, different.
Before you say anything, there's
something you should know.
It's about you and me.
It would never work.
Funny, I was going
to say the same thing.
I mean, you're... tied up
with running your estate,
and... I'm...
tied up with mine.
I thought you
were going to say
it was because
of Katrina.
Archie MacDonald, you're
crazy about that girl.
What on earth
makes you say that?
Take it from someone
who knows.
Don't waste a chance
to be really happy
with a good person.
It doesn't happen
very often.
Tell me you're not
in love with her.
- I, um-
- party guests: Surprise!
# happy birthday
to you... #
oh, no!
- Did you know about this?
- Yes.
So that's why you spent a day
with me, keep me off the trail.
No, I spent the day with
you because I wanted to.
# happy birthday
to you. #
thank you
very much.
Duncan:
It'll be good fun.
You like parties,
don't you?
Wow...
is that the new series?
- Like cars, do you?
- Yeah.
Uh-uh. That'll be
one of the guests'.
Best not to touch.
Go to the party.
You said I should
ask questions.
Has it got a V-8 engine?
I don't suppose
it would do any harm
to have a wee look.
No touching, mind.
Lexie:
Enjoying yourself, Arch?
Thank you so much.
Can't thank you enough.
Cake's wonderful.
See? She's already part of the family.
She's only been here
one day.
She looks pretty much
in there to me.
But we all know
what a sucker Archie is
for a pretty face, eh?
Hector:
So, where's your father?
Oh, he has
a slight headache.
He said
he'd join us later.
Splendid.
Well...
here's to new beginnings, eh?
New beginnings.
I know you didn't want
a fuss, Archie,
but I couldn't help thinking
about the past. Remember?
All the parties here,
children, Lizzie...
Jamie would've
loved this.
I don't think
you realise, Archie,
how lucky and proud
I feel to have you,
birthday boy.
Thank you very much,
mother.
( playing with controls )
Might've one of these
myself one day.
I'm sure a bright lad like you
will be able to have one too.
Oh, don't touch that!
That's the ejector button!
( playing with buttons )
You scared the wits
out of me!
Have you no shame?
- I can't afford shame.
- This is wrong!
Look, the lad's dead.
He has no use
for this stuff.
These trophies
aren't worth much.
This is more like it.
I have done my best
for you for 10 years,
but I can't let you
do this!
Look at you, dad.
Look at what
you've become.
Oh, thanks, Lexie.
Just tell me you're not
seriously thinking about it.
About what?
Come on.
Arranged marriages.
You don't really believe
in all that stuff, do you?
I've only just met her.
For what it's worth,
I think she's all right.
All right?
And besides, whatever goes
on between me and Tanya,
or anyone else, for that
matter, is my business.
It's always been
the same, hasn't it?
"You wouldn't let your old
man down now, would you?
Just one more job and I'll be set
- " please!
Let's just go! We
can't take any of this!
It's too late!
Kieran:
Get away from my car.
What's going on?
Kieran:
Get away! Get away!
Get away from my car!
( honking )
( distant honking )
( dogs barking )
Where are you
going, dad?
running to now?
What's going on,
old chap?
( yelling )
A real bright spot
that lad.
Takes one to know one.
Come on,
the party's over.
( van leaving )
I tried to tell you.
Before the party.
Yeah, I know.
Why?
Because, believe it or
not, I really like you.
I like all of you.
He is my father,
Archie.
It's the family business.
You understand that.
Trying to make the family
business work, don't you?
I'm gonna have
to call the police.
It's all right, Archie.
Let them go.
We've been disturbed enough
by you people.
Jamie's been
disturbed enough.
Thank you,
Mr. MacDonald.
Thank you, Archie.
- Archie...
- don't gloat.
I'm not!
That man is impossible!
- You all right, father?
- I'm fine.
I'm sorry your party
was spoiled.
At least that's my birthday
over for another year.
Ho ho.
Not quite.
Molly:
This is to remind you
that you were once
a little boy,
my little boy.
Your very own
red Porsche.
Couldn't afford
the real thing.
Oh, mother,
it's perfect.
Hector:
I'm sorry I interfered.
I wish you all the luck
in the world.
I hope you
find someone
who makes you as happy
as your mother makes me.
Thank you.
I was just trying
to tell him
that I was sorry things
didn't work out with Tanya,
but he wouldn't listen.
What's so funny?
Just you and Archie.
Always seem to be
upsetting each other.
Yeah.
Well...
he can be a very
upsetting person.
Lexie: ready...
steady...
go!
And they're off!
And he's off!
Can you believe it?
( yelling )
He's round the tunnel,
he's in the tunnel...
and it's
over the hill.
( yelling; chattering )
I better go.
I'll see you soon.
( theme music playing )
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0