Can you see me okay?
Perfectly. You've got a wee
spot on the end of your nose.
Thank you very much.
Charming.
What about the tilt?
Is that working?
Hold on.
Yep. Good.
Microphone.
- Testing... one, two, two.
- I'm hearing you, loud and clear.
Good. You'd better check
the other cameras.
Golly, are you there?
- Yes.
- is Lexie there?
This better not
take all day.
I've got dinner for 12
to make.
- Lexie?
- Duncan?
Molly, I know I can
rely on you.
Oh, hello dear.
I'm in go mode
in the library. Beep.
Is father there?
No, don't worry, he'll
be here in a minute.
Good. What about Duncan?
Has anyone seen him?
- He promised- Duncan!
- Duncan?!
- Duncan! - tell him we're going to
be online in a minute.
- get over here, boy!
- Duncan...
hang on,
I think I've got him.
( all yelling at Duncan )
Duncan!
Ready?
Right.
Good luck, Archie.
Thank you.
Lexie: Look, look
- come on.
Ten... nine...
Golly, the wheelbarrow!
- Yes, right, okay.
- seven... six...
five... Duncan!
- Three... two...
- ( everyone jabbering )
One!
The highlands of Scotland,
a beautiful
and magical place.
And here by the shores
of the distant loch,
stands an ancient
family home.
Welcome to Glenbogle.
Deep in the heart
of Caledonia,
now going online
to the world,
my name is
Archie MacDonald,
I am the laird here.
- for 400 years and more,
my family have lived... - Molly!
- ... in this fantastic place.
- What am I supposed to do? It's embarrassing!
Lean against the mantelpiece
and look aristocratic.
Ugh!
Go.
Go!
Hector: What about my lunch?
Molly: You've just had breakfast.
What am I supposed to do now?
Look at the camera,
and smile.
Ronald! Holly!
Dogs sit!
Sit!
Hector: Down, sir, down. Wee bit, down.
Lexie: Come on, Arch...
nearly on, come on!
Go.
Now, a new day dawns
at Glenbogle.
After centuries as a tranquil
retreat for one family,
we're throwing it open
so that others can-
enjoy it too.
To keep up with our exciting
new developments here,
log onto our web site,
and wherever you are,
Pasadena or Paisley,
check out the fantastic views
captured by the webcams,
at w-w-w dot-
Glenbogle dot com.
Yes!
Well, how was it?
Archie, it was great!
You should be
on television.
Thank you very much.
Justine,
you missed it!
Sorry, I was-
just running our business.
But I see you're
in good hands.
Literally.
( sneezes )
Bless you.
( theme music playing )
These came
for you.
Thanks.
I'm sorry.
It's not really me
you should apologise to.
I'd never have got this whole
thing running without Katrina.
I.T. training, business degree
and golden curls.
Look, just because we
were at school together,
and we happen to have
quite a lot in common-
and she's always here,
and you like each other.
That doesn't mean she's
a threat to you, sweetheart.
Doesn't it?
Can't you just try
to get on with her?
She could be
a real help to us.
Okay.
For you.
Archie: Oh, look
- someone's dropped in for tea.
That's not someone-
that's Mr. Brown.
International man
of mystery.
( plane approaching )
Welcome to Glenbogle,
Mr. Brown.
I do hope you have
a successful course.
What could possibly
go wrong?
Hector:
Good day to you.
I knew our home was being
invaded by aliens,
but isn't this a touch
over the top?
Watch out!
What's that?
Gear.
Gear?
This is
Hector MacDonald,
my partner's
father.
And this is
Mr. Brown,
who is organising the
management training weekend.
How monumentally
uninteresting.
Tell me,
are you as dull
as your name and
occupation suggest?
- Hector?
- Huh?
We're having your people
picked up per your instructions.
This equipment needs
to be stowed in my office.
Office?!
Man: You'll love working
at the old bank, Mary.
They really look out
for their employees.
- Really? - Yes, treat you with
courtesy and consideration.
Not like those hard-nosed
so-and-so's you used to be with.
I'm a bit
frightened though-
a team building exercise
in my first week.
There's nothing to it.
- A few day's r & r away from base.
- ( sheep passes gas )
And you'll love it here.
There it is, children.
Prepare to enter
the kingdom of heaven.
A haven of peace
and harmony.
Looks a total dump,
if you ask me.
( beeping )
( sheep bleats )
Man 2: I turned down a corporate box
at the open
for this?
Two miles down the track
in an army truck...
and a dose
of mad cow disease.
( chatting )
Mary:
This is beautiful!
You see, the thing is, Katrina,
Archie and I have been
together for a long time,
and that's not
going to change,
especially now that I've
committed myself to Glenbogle.
So... it's a waste
of your time,
energy, and frankly,
your dignity,
trying to
prise him away.
I am doing
no such thing.
Come off it.
You're never away
from the place.
Glenbogle is my home,
and has been for far longer
than it's been yours.
Correction-
your home is
20 minutes cycle ride down the glen.
Maybe you should
stay there.
Aye, maybe I will.
This conversation
is demeaning,
especially for you,
Justine.
As long as you get
the message.
Perhaps I should
express it
in the language
of the highland laird,
private property.
Keep off.
Are you piping this piston, or not?
Justine said
not to bother
- with that sturmarche anymore.
- Oh, she did, did she?
Well, why don't we all
stop wearing kilts,
eating deep fried mars bars,
and hating the english?
And all our other ancient
Scottish traditions?
Golly:
Who rattled your cage?
Anyways, since when
have you been so in love
with the scuttle
of the pipes?
Maybe when Glenbogle's
answer to Mrs. Thatcher
started
banning them.
- Golly: it's okay.
- Duncan: yeah, fair play.
She's okay.
Well... -ish.
Answer me this,
then-
is it as much fun as
when it was just Archie?
Lexie, the bankers have arrived
so we'll eat at 7:00.
Promptly, this time,
if you don't mind.
What is it?
Venison?
Cow.
( snickering )
Well, maybe this time
you can manage
not to overcook it.
Last time we had beef, it was stringy,
tough, and - rather tasteless.
Maybe it's not the only thing,
round here, eh?
( sighs )
Man 2:
Come on! In my room,
there's a trouser press,
a coffee percolator,
sundry other electricals,
and then- and I don't know who's
train of thought we're on here-
I come across
this little beauty.
I mean, mints?
On the pillows?
This is not up-and-at-'em
team building, Fleming.
This is the generation game
in a gingham skirt.
Nigel, you're like a blind man
in paradise. It's wonderful here.
Lexie, aren't you
going to let him have it?
Defend this place?
Can't be bothered, Flem.
I can't believe
you think Lassel's
should keep bailing
this place out!
You've spent a lot
of the bank's money!
( clears throat )
They'll have
the house white,
I'll sip a bottle
of your chablis.
Soup?
Sorry.
Will you be wanting
a baked roll with that, sir?
Bally lout! Took me for a waiter!
A little misunderstanding,
that's all.
This isn't our home
anymore, is it, Molly?
Be with you in a sec. The nick
is just opening up for trading.
Hector, why can't you just
go with the flow a bit?
Don't be absurd! For my entire
life, the flow has gone with me!
It can't do you any good,
whingeing all the time.
"Shut up," is that what you mean?
I think I managed
to calm everyone down.
Now look here,
my girl,
many tyrants have tried to defeat
the MacDonalds of Glenbogle,
from butcher cumberland
to adolf hitler, and failed!
Hector, please,
you're overreacting.
I've been slapping down uppity females
for 40 years, not gonna stop now!
Molly: Oh, Hector, you
couldn't slap anyone down.
Even if you were holding a
large wet haddock in each hand.
Yeah!
Haddock?
Katrina?
Katrina!
What is it?
It's Justine.
She's-
Justine is working
her socks off.
I know.
But she's paranoid
about Archie and me.
I wonder how she got
that idea?
Look...
Katrina, could you
take some advice, lass?
Yes!
No...
well, maybe.
Okay.
Let's not heed to think
that I was one of those...
sad fellows that
can only discuss
painful human dilemmas,
and sporting matters.
But,
if I were you...
I would take my line
right out of the water.
If I know anything, there's
trouble brewing up there.
And I'd hate to see you
get the worst of it.
What are you doing?
Writing a list.
( sniffs )
Correction...
writing a list of all the
other lists I've got to write
of all the things
we need to do
to put this place
on its feet.
Don't worry about the little
scene I had with Hector,
it was just
a low level skirmish.
I just wish things
weren't so hard for you.
I came here
with my eyes open.
To work for
a very good cause-
us.
Come here, you!
( sneezes )
( groans )
I knew I shouldn't have turned
the heating off at easter.
I hope the bankers
are okay.
Don't worry, Lexie's fattened them up.
They'll need it.
What do you mean?
Come on, tell me.
I couldn't.
Mr. Brown is not a man
to cross lightly.
( door creaking )
( snoring )
Justine: Okay, I read a fax for Brown.
It's not a team
building course.
The bank are
cutting back.
Brown has to decide
which one of them
should get
the bullet,
according to
darwinian principles.
What?
The survival
of the fittest.
Oh, no!
Fleming.
Fleming?
Time for work.
Oh dear.
Come on!
Long ways to go.
Come on,
Mr. Fleming.
If it's
not hurting,
it's not doing you
any good.
No you don't!
Nice guys finish-
last!
- Mr. Fleming, are you all right?
- Yes, I'm fine, really.
Brown: Come on, Mr. Fleming,
where's your get-up-and-go?
Got up and went,
did it?
Now on this course,
I will be awarding marks
for effort
and achievement.
And the end result will be
used by your employers
for purposes of their own.
Who gets promoted,
you mean?
So, that's one point
for Mr. Fleming.
Three for Ms. Denning.
And 10 for Mr. Rutter.
Rutter: Bottom of the
pile, Fleming, great start.
( growls )
( air whooshing )
Valve.
Valve?! I don't want a bally
boat on my billiard table,
as well as everything else!
- Hector...
- ( snarls )
( chimes )
Hector:
Enough is enough!
Justine: Hector, please, calm down.
That is my office,
there...
( sighs )
I do all my research
in there!
It just won't do!
What's the matter?
There is nowhere
in this house
where a chap can find an
iota of peace and quiet!
That's not surprising with
you bellowing the place down!
Justine:
Hector, I'm sorry.
But we're running
a business here.
Sorry.
Right. That's it.
I've had enough.
I rather think
I have too.
I'm sorry to say this,
Justine,
but there isn't room
for the two of us.
It's not me
that's the problem.
I am trying very hard,
but you're just impossible!
Molly!
Pack a toothbrush and nightie-
we're moving out!
Monty, come!
Holly!
( barking )
Did you have to
say that?
Can you see
he was annoyed?
( air cartridge fires )
( metal clangs )
What are you doing?
Abseiling.
Oh... right.
Fleming: I'll go first, Mary.
( wails )
( growling )
Hector: Puppy! Come on. Go on, get!
Monty, Brummel,
fall in!
Quick run to the
retirement home, please.
It's so unnecessary.
Ah! Good man,
good man!
Molly!
Come on, boys.
Come on.
Something for your lunch.
And save me a bed.
I might be joining you
very soon.
This is absolutely
ridiculous.
Molly: Oh-hh, cheer up,
darling. It's for the best.
We're going to the end of the
drive, not the end of the world.
Mother-
Fleming:
Mary, that's it.
You want to get your legs
just slightly apart.
One foot on the top
and the other one on the stone,
and then- whoa!
Oooh! Ah-hh!
I love this place.
It's like something out
of Hansel and gretel.
Father, please.
Excuse me.
Mother, do you really
have to do this?
I'm sorry, I agree
with your father.
Can I at least give you
a hand settling in?
We can manage,
thank you.
What are you going
to do about supper?
We shall be dining here,
quietly and simply,
time at last to retire
from public life.
Goodbye.
( huffs )
Do you want
a sandwich?
Lexie!
Look what's happening.
Fleming's going to get relegated.
Well, he was no great shakes
at the abseiling.
His raft sunk,
and a bee stung him
at the end
of his initiative test.
Very painful.
( Archie sighs )
- Archie...
- huh?
Look, I'm really sorry
about this morning.
- your dad.
- We'll talk later.
I've got to do something
about Fleming first.
You can't interfere.
Justine-
look, we are knee deep
in debt here.
It's only thanks to Fleming
that we're still afloat.
Believe me, if he loses his
job, we will be finished!
But he's just one person. It's
the bank we have to keep in with.
I know what I'm doing. I'm
acting in our long term interests.
No, you're not! You're
threatening them. Stay out of it.
Oh, sorry! And here was me
thinking that I was in charge.
If anyone should
stay out of it-
well, I was going to ask your help,
but there's obviously no point.
Brown:
Come on, Mr. Fleming,
last chance today
to avoid the wooden spoon.
Oof!
Molly, that cell-like
chamber downstairs?
- The drawing room, yes?
- There's a hole in the wall.
It's called a hatch. I should be
conveying your supper through it.
Baked beans on toast,
and so on.
Breakfast and bourbon,
still... needs must.
Oh, not much storage space.
We'll have to share. You take
this side, and I'll take that.
I'll use the wardrobe
in my bedroom, can't I?
- No, you can't!
- Whyever not?
Because you haven't got
a bedroom. This is it.
We'll have to share.
Share a bedroom?!
Be rather cozy, won't it?
Man and wife
in the same bedroom?
It's not natural!
( car approaching )
Katrina!
Archie?
You've got to come
with me, now!
I can't. I've got to finish
this portrait for tomorrow.
I need your help.
I don't think
it's really a good idea.
Look, I've got a crisis
with Fleming and the bankers.
It's a long story,
but I need you, please!
Archie MacDonald,
you are maddening!
Yeah, so everyone tells me.
Brown:
Now, pay close attention.
This is an exercise
in intelligence,
teamwork,
and individual initiative.
You will each drive one of
those all-terrain vehicles
back to the house.
The only problem is-
there's no petrol
in them.
- So how-
- where is the petrol?
The petrol is in
those cans in front of you.
So you better start
by bringing them up.
There's got to be
some catch here.
- Hello?
- Hey, hey!
- Mr. Brown!
- excuse me!
We're gonna be needing that, I think.
Remember, in battle, your
greatest enemy is complacency.
- What?!
- Mary-
I'm getting a tad
hacked off with this!
- hello?! Mr. Brown?
- hello?
- ( engine starts )
- Mr. Brown!
Are you going?
All:
Mr. Brown!
More baked beans,
Hector?
Thank you, dear.
Lovely.
( dog whines )
Mary: Hello, is there anyone there?
- Any ideas?
- Where's all this water coming from?
- The lake. - Actually, it's
a loch- we call it a loch.
We'll climb out of here.
Fleming, you be the baseman,
Mary, you're next.
I'm a very experienced climber.
I've done a lot.
Don't worry, okay?
He can't hold
all of us.
You first, come on, Mary.
Get lower.
I'm ready.
I'm braced.
Ready? Okay,
up you go, hup!
Careful, Fleming!
Are you all right?
Steady yourself!
- Come on!
- I'm on your shoulders.
Whose idea was this?
Yours, you dolt.
Hold still.
Okay.
Are you all right,
Fleming?
Hold steady.
Here we go.
Hang on.
All right,
I've got that one.
Okay.
- Are you all right, Flem?
- Yep.
- Okay.
- Whoo!
For goodness sake.
Okay, got it,
got it, got it!
Yes, yes, yes.
- hang on, hang on.
- What?
We need the jerry can.
The what?! Can?
I'm gonna have to-
stay very-
very still.
I got it.
- Nigel, you come up now.
- yes, yes.
Okay, okay,
one, two, three.
On the left. Hold on!
I'm losing you on the left!
Move over!
Balance!
- Balance there.
- okay?
Yep. Okay.
Argh!
And... up we go.
Down!
Get down!
Both:
Throw the ladder down.
Mary: That's it, pass it
down. Pass it down, Nigel.
Keep coming, keep coming.
Nearly there.
Okay, hang on!
( yelling )
He's thrown
the ladder in!
( sighs )
What a rat.
- I'll head him off.
- I'll get the others.
Wee-haa!
Yeah! Losers!
- ( screaming )
- Hold onto the can!
Fleming! Fleming!
Throw me the ladder!
Come on!
- We can't!
- Throw it up!
Find something else.
- I'll get some rope.
- ( screaming )
Hold onto the can!
Grab onto the can!
There! There!
Tie it on, come on!
Okay, come on!
Here I come, okay?
Oh, what now?!
My boyfriend's truck shed a
load of timber up the path.
But if you're looking
for Glenbogle House,
you can reach it
up that track there.
Come on, buddy.
Okay.
- Come on, hurry up!
- Let's get going.
You better take it easy, Fleming,
there's not much
fuel here.
Keep your wig on, Arch,
it's only a game.
It's not just a game,
Flem, it's a test.
If you don't win this,
you will lose your job.
And therefore, we will lose our home!
Now go on!
( Rutter humming )
Mary: Come on, faster,
make it go faster.
Fleming: My foot's flat to the floor.
We're nearly there.
Careful.
Oop, oop,
hold it, Nigel.
- Mary: Whee!
- Flat out, we're flat out!
Mary: Come on, go faster.
Have we got enough petrol?
It's slightly in the red.
I'm sure it's fine.
Mary:
Whee-hee!
I think
we're ahead of him!
I can't see him,
keep going!
Yee-haw!
The winner!
Oh, look,
there he is!
Keep going,
keep going!
No! No fuel?!
Whoo-ooo!
Come on!
Yeah!
- Oh.
- Sorry.
( giggling )
Did you see
Fleming's face?
What about Nigel's?
Wah-hah!
( both laughing )
Problem solved.
Is it though?
Huh?
It seems to me, that
there's a big problem here
that no one's facing.
( sighs )
We only seem
to enjoy ourselves when
we're sneaking around
behind Justine's back.
Aw, come on.
And it's making me
very unhappy.
And what about you?
Are you happy?
I don't know.
No.
I want to go home.
All of a sudden,
I'm tired, hungry,
and- very miserable.
I'm sorry.
Why don't I give you
a lift to your car?
No.
You go home to Justine.
Now then...
ah ha!
Ah-hh.
Come in.
No-
you've left
something behind.
Oh! That's the trouble
with packing in a hurry.
Very thoughtful of you,
thank you.
Playing with
Archie's toy-
you surprise me,
Hector.
I'll have you know, I was
signals officer in my battalion.
Trouble is Archie's put the
cameras in all the wrong places.
If I'm going to stay here,
I have to do something about it.
And how is the new billet?
Marvelous! Should have
done it years ago.
Little house,
simple life, marvelous.
I'd like you
to come home, Hector.
Pardon?
You being here
makes Archie feel bad,
and I miss you.
Me?
You're like an itch.
Extremely irritating,
but without it,
one is denied the pleasure
of a good scratch.
Oh.
( chuckles )
I'm sorry if I've been
a pain in the neck recently.
I'm sorry too,
my dear.
You're not really
very happy here, are you?
Damn.
Sorry.
( piano playing )
I didn't know you
could play the piano.
I can't!
( melancholy music playing )
Oh,
I love this stuff.
Matches my mood.
Got the blues,
have you?
A slight case
of the darkenings maybe.
Things just aren't the same
around here, Flem.
Nor at Lassel's Bank,
I'm afraid.
There's something I've
always wanted to ask you,
how a nice girl like you
ended up in a place like this?
Me?
I came to Glenbogle
to forget.
Forget what?
Can't remember.
What were you saying
about the bank?
I don't know.
It was never that
exciting a job, but now-
ruthless young tykes like Nigel
trying to put you down,
new management's
forcing you to fight
for a job you don't
really want...
- pack it in then.
- Do what?
I don't know.
Play the piano?
Write symphonies.
( chuckles )
I'm not sure I've got
the courage for that, Lex.
Besides, old Archie
needs me where I am.
If I lost my job...
Flem, this is your life.
Not Archie's.
You've got to follow
your heart.
If you're not
happy in life-
what's the point in it?
( birds singing )
This camera's no good here at all.
I said it'd be
better off in the house.
All right!
Give me a hand.
Come on, come on,
come on!
Father,
you're back.
What are you
doing?
Nothing.
Archie?
Are you all right?
Just listen-
I came to tell you I won't
be coming here anymore.
What?!
Archie, let's be honest
with each other,
we're not just friends.
It's much more
than that.
You know it, I know it
and Justine knows it.
And not unnaturally,
she resents it.
Oh...
hi.
Lexie hasn't prepared
the banker's rations,
so I'm going
to sort it out.
And it's causing us
all a lot of grief.
So I've decided the only way
to make it more bearable
is just not
to come here,
and not to see you.
( Lexie's voice raised )
I think we'd all be
a lot happier that way.
- Katrina, you can't just-
- I'm sorry.
- Lexie: of course, she who knows everything.
- Justine: the games you play.
- I don't play games, darling.
- You've been against me from day one.
A little look here,
a snide remark there.
I fight battles and I'm warning
you before this one kicks off,
- I take no prisoners.
- Of course I know why.
Apparently yet another
female's after my boyfriend.
Well, don't even think
about trying it!
Despite your rather obvious
attractions,
you're not serious
competition.
( scoffs )
For you?!
You've got as much charisma
as a rolled up carpet.
Don't flare your nostrils at that, 'cause
you'll get house martins nesting in them!
Right, that's it!
What is the problem now?
- Her!
How are you feeling,
Mary?
I'm fine.
You know, you're really
very kind, Fleming.
Do you know that?
Girls are always
saying that.
I wish they'd call me a
filthy brute one of these days.
Brown:
Right.
Jump off at
the starboard side,
swim underneath
the boat,
and climb back on
board on the port side.
Right,
who's first?
I brought the garlic press,
the wooden spoons,
as for the pots and pans,
well, I think-
will you stop going on
about the kitchen utensils,
and tell me what
all this is about?
I am leaving Glenbogle,
due to personal differences
with Mrs. Laird, here!
She's got to go.
We cannot carry on like this!
You said it, girl!
Right. Fine.
I'll help you pack!
Will you both
be quiet!
Let me think!
Nobody does anything.
Nobody moves.
You- just stay here.
Justine, have you
got a minute, please?
This I have to hear.
Oh no, Lexie.
Lexie!
Just give them a bit
of privacy.
( sobbing )
I can't do this!
That might have
unfortunate consequences.
As you already hitched
a lift on Mr. Fleming's car,
you're now
in bottom place.
That's not fair. And
anyway, I can't swim!
Then you'll just have to shut
your eyes and think of England.
- Jump!
- ( shrieks )
Fleming:
Mr. Brown?
You may have heard of
a historical personage
called Captain Bligh.
He was the commander of a vessel
called "The Bounty,"
which also happens to be the
name of my favorite chocolate bar!
What?
Whoa!
Fleming!
Fleming: Sorry, I didn't
have a plank to hand.
And by the way,
Mr. Brown, remember-
in battle, complacency
is your greatest enemy.
And I'd say that's you
sunk as well, old man.
Oh-hh!
Hector,
I'm going shopping,
is there anything
you need?
Some hardtack biscuits
and the "Telegraph," my dear.
What are you doing?
These cameras are
in the wrong place!
I miss the hustle
and bustle of the house.
But with Duncan's help-
ah-hh!
- Got it sorted.
- Yeah.
- There.
- splendid.
- Oh, I say... - Justine: You've obviously
got something to say, so say it!
I know it's not
easy for you,
coming to a place that isn't
your favorite spot in the world.
No! It isn't!
It was a sacrifice
I made to be with you.
Argh!
Molly:
No, try again!
I wanted see what she
was going to say to him.
Give them a minute's peace.
It's their right.
Lexie, may I
have a word?
- What?
- Don't say anything.
I must say this quickly.
I've been thinking.
You said I should have
the courage to follow my heart.
Yeah?
Would you have the courage
to follow it with me?
Flem, the way
I'm feeling right now-
( whistling )
Golly! Lexie!
Come and see this!
Archie: I know it's not
easy working with people
- you didn't choose.
- Who can't stand me,
but have the hots
for my boyfriend, yes!
But you are
forcing them out!
People that
I am fond of, yes,
but also people who
could help us here!
Come on, Archie!
It's not about other people.
So why don't you tell me
what you really think?
Go on, Archie,
tell her!
I don't believe we
should be watching this.
No.
This isn't going to be easy,
but it has to be said.
Hector,
could you possibly
turn up the volume?
A smidgen?
Archie: I think you're taking over.
You're trying to do everything.
You're breathing
everyone else's oxygen.
- Yours as well, I take it?
- Yes!
Look, Justine,
this is my home,
my inheritance,
my challenge.
And there's
no room for me?
That's what
you're saying, isn't it?
No, I'm not-
of course, I'm not!
They're moving.
No, no, no,
Hector!
Right, so we just
click on Glenbogle. com,
and let's see
what we can see...
there's the loch.
We all know the loch,
don't we?
And remember, this is actually
happening, right now.
Archie: You've got it wrong,
sweetheart, and not for the first time.
Justine: Look, I know
I'm an outsider here,
Glenbogle isn't my home-
that's a long way south
and I miss it like hell.
My family,
my friends, my life-
I gave it all up so that
we could be together.
I know that.
But it's not working, is it?
I don't mean other people,
I mean us.
What do you think?
Tell me.
It's not the same.
It's different, you know.
We've changed.
Can we get it back?
What we had once?
I'm not sure
that we can.
I'm sorry.
What do you think?
To be honest, I think I lost you
the moment you came up here.
I curse this place.
Thank you for being honest.
I'll go and pack my bags.
Poor Archie.
( kids groan )
Poor Justine.
How distressing.
Duncan:
He needs neighbors.
Lexie:
Oh...
Fleming!
Fleming: Off to ring the head office?
Tell them to do
their rotten job.
He doesn't have to.
I'm your new boss.
Eh?
I take over as head of domestic
finance division next week.
You?
You lied,
you exploited us.
I had to look at the two of you
under challenging conditions.
To find out which of us
gets the job?
Downsizing
is an option...
as is flattening out
management structures.
I consider myself
managerially flattened,
and personally reborn.
Anyway,
I've made up my mind.
Eh?
Nigel, you are dull,
boorish, arrogant,
totally lacking in humor
or compassion, so you're fired.
- But I have-
- I said, you're fired.
As for you, Fleming...
you have shown courage,
leadership, loyalty,
and independence of spirit.
Hasn't he, Mr. Brown?
In other words...
Lancelot.
My perfect number two.
No, no...
no, you don't.
I quit.
I'm going to tinkle
the ivories for a living,
and she will be
my muse and manager.
Flem, have you
got a minute?
You don't have to run off
like this. I could drive you.
To the station?
No thanks.
Say goodbye to everyone
for me, will you?
Don't think I can
face them just now.
We did love each other once,
didn't we, Archie?
Yes, we did.
Be happy.
( engine starts )
( car departing )
So she's gone,
and not coming back?
Which means you're not
going anywhere.
I understand.
Lucky old Archie.
That's what I say.
You're a sweetie.
My mother use to say
something similar...
cough drop...
she use to call me.
Oh...
I suppose I better
go find Mary
before she offers that
promotion to someone else.
You know, Lex?
I rather think she fancies me.
Ah... good man.
It's lovely to be back in our home.
Fun though, wasn't it?
Thanks, Duncan.
Hugh, Monty, come on!
Come here.
Heel.
How're you doing?
Pretty strange
actually.
Justine has left.
I know.
It's weird.
We were together
five years.
I feel really sad,
but I also feel...
lighter, you know?
Is that terrible?
No.
Anyway...
I think I'm going
to need your help.
Why do you think
I'm here?
I've had this idea about
hiring someone
to help with
the tourist business.
What do you think?
Hmmm...
( deep sigh )
( whirring )
Duncan!
( theme music playing )
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0