( chainsaw buzzing )
- Morning.
( dog barking )
Lexie:
Whoo! who's that?
Nobody.
Duncan,
she's all body.
Is that your wee friend? The
one that sends you letters?
- No!
- "To Duncan,
from your pen friend,
Marie-Helene. "
Five kisses.
French kisses.
Look, it's not like that.
We're just good fr-
she's got a boyfriend.
- That can change.
- I've never even met her.
Mmm, that can
change too. here.
- Telemessage for you.
- You opened it?
Thought I'd save you
the bother.
What? that's
good news, isn't it?
- She's coming here!
- She can't.
- What's up?
- I cannot tell you.
Well,
we'll soon find out.
She'll be on the train
by now. ( giggles )
( theme music playing )
- Duncan: bonjour, ici-
- ( door slams )
Duncan,
the ami de stylo
of Marie-Helene.
En ecosse-
but I'm but here,
I'm going away.
- en vacancies.
- vacances, en vacances.
Sorry, en vacances.
( phone clatters )
Let me guess...
your friend, Marie-Helene.
Lexie told me all about her.
She's not there.
Just voicemail.
- You're going to see her in a couple of hours.
- No! I won't be here.
- I'm going to my mother's.
- No, Duncan!
When I was at school,
I had a pen friend
called Simone,
and I used to make up
all sorts of things,
just to entertain her.
And then one day,
I was absolutely terrified
she might turn up and visit,
and discover the real me wasn't
at all like I was in the letters.
But I'm sure you would
never do anything like that.
I would. I did.
I told her a pack of lies.
Now she's coming here
with her fancy boyfriend,
and I'm not sticking around to
look like a complete numptie.
Oh dear. how long have
you been writing to her?
Since I was 13,
Ms. Skinner's class.
So you'd really like
to see her again,
Marie-Helene, I mean.
Not Ms. Skinner.
I've always dreamed
of seeing her.
It was a silly kid's thing,
but when I was at school,
I was... kind of...
in love with her.
Right, Duncan.
Let's make it happen.
What?!
How come you've stopped
eating with the grown-ups?
( sighs ) You enjoy the
scintillating conversation with me.
What's happened?
( sniffs )
Nothing.
Is it bad news?
It's my divorce.
I never thought it
would be so fast.
It's not bad news at
all. It's great news.
I'm just being stupid.
- Look, if you want to cry-
- ( Stella laughs )
Just cry.
- It's your divorce.
- I don't want to.
Why do I let him
do this to me?
You're asking me?
( laughs )
Fat lot I know.
Remember Stuart?
If there's one thing
I do know,
it's that they're
not worth it.
None of them.
Oh, this is pathetic.
I should be cracking open
the champagne.
What me to go get you
some from the shop?
No, I'll get it.
Are you doing
anything tonight?
Me?
( scoffs )
- No.
- You are now.
- I'm not drinking on my own.
- Okay.
( dog barking )
( growls )
- Can I help?
- Those dogs should be kept under proper control.
Monty, Rommel,
come on.
I'm sorry, this garden isn't open
to the public. There is a sign.
I believe you'll find I'm within my
legal rights. I'm not causing any damage.
By the by, the internationally
accepted form for that sign
is a red-rimmed circle
containing a walking figure
struck through
with a red, oblique line.
- Would you excuse me?
- ( dog growls )
( Molly claps )
Now I've got you all here,
I've got some good news
from the hospital.
They say that Hector
is really improving.
That's not more
duffed news about him?
It may be some time before
he can sit down again,
but remember,
we don't talk about it.
Well, people are asking.
I need to tell them something.
I just say Glenbogle's
not the only ancient pile
that's been troubling him.
That seems to work.
- Sorry.
- Ah, here you are. We need you.
- Sounds ominous.
- not at all.
Duncan has a problem.
Just the one?
His friend Marie-Helene has clearly
misunderstood one of Duncan's letters.
French can be such
a tricky language.
You ask for a hairbrush,
they bring you a horse brush.
It's all too, too muddling.
Anyway, as I was saying,
dear Marie-Helene
seems confused
about what it is
Duncan actually does.
That's no surprise.
Half the time Duncan's confused
about what he actually does.
Duncan's worried that his French
friends will be disappointed.
So I thought it would
be easier all around
if just for a couple
of days,
Duncan became the laird
of Glenbogle.
You told her
you were the laird?
Kind of.
And as far as she's concerned,
he will be. everyone happy?
Just hold on
a wee minute.
Duncan has a job to do,
I rely on him.
Archie can do that.
You want me
to do Duncan's job,
- and Duncan to do mine?
- Very good, dear.
It would've taken me hours
to explain something like that
to your father.
Don't feel like
emptying that one, no?
- Didn't see it.
- "job's worth doing... "
I know, I know.
Give me a chance.
- Soon get the hang of it.
- Man: excuse me?
I have a complaint.
It concerns your equipment.
That lifebelt holder
would appear to be empty.
There's another one
just there.
What's more,
there's nobody out on the loch,
and we're not
expecting the Titanic.
You may not take the danger
of drowning seriously,
but I most certainly do.
A member of my family drowned in
that loch. I take it very seriously.
That doesn't run to supplying
adequate safety equipment?
Most slipshod.
You're doing this because I
threw you out of the garden.
No, I'm merely drawing
your attention to the fact-
perhaps you'd like
your entrance fee back then?
No, no.
Hey, easy.
You're talking
to the wrong person.
If you've got a problem,
take it to the estate office.
We arrive at the table like this,
and then-
- Duncan-
- oh, sorry.
Thank you.
Ahem-
would you like to taste?
Yes, please.
( fizzes )
( sloshing )
I don't know.
Hmm, not good enough
for you?
Perhaps the '92
would be better?
Mmm.
( giggles )
Not bad, wee man. He's more
like Archie than Archie.
I understand you
accommodate paying guests?
I'll require an inexpensive
room for the night.
That's no problem. We have
one with a view of the loch.
- I'm not here for the scenery.
- ( door opens )
- I've got to go to the station.
- This is Mr. Barr.
- Yeah, we've met.
- He's the assistant chief inspector
with the regional health
and safety executive.
I see.
He's here to carry out
a spot-check inspection
and he wants you
to help him.
- Me?
- You are the head ranger, are you not?
Umm... yeah, yeah.
Good. in that case,
we start tomorrow
at 9:00 prompt.
Go get the barrow.
She might have more bags
than you can carry.
Listen, you don't give the orders
around here. Duncan's the laird.
And you are Duncan. So that
means we can boss you around.
- She's not here. Let's go.
- No, no!
- Is that her there?
- No!
( giggles )
Ah, Duncan.
Is that Marie-Helene?
Ooh-la-la.
Duncan,
she's lovely.
- Maybe this isn't a good idea.
- Of course it is.
- courage, mon ami.
- What?
- bonjour.
- Duncan, hello.
( clears throat,
laughs nervously )
Bienvenue en ecosse,
c'est un tres
grand plaisir por moi,
et ma famille,
de faire votre
connaissance
merci beaucoup.
Tu es tres gentile.
Et Glenbogle,
c'est loin?
Non, non. c'est pas loin.
On habite au bord du lac.
C'est a peu pres
a 40 minutes d'ici.
By the way, I'm Molly.
Duncan's mother.
And this is Lexie.
- and that's Archie.
- He'll take your bags for you.
Molly: Are you alone? I thought
you were coming with a friend.
I'm sorry. I didn't say in the telegram.
Alain had to stay
in Edinburgh.
What a shame. anyway,
it's lovely to see you.
Archie!
Land Rover.
Where is
the Ferrari?
The Ferrari's...
got a burst...
thingy.
Lexie:
Yeah! I mean-
does that all the time.
You know,
bursts its thingy.
( forced laughter )
( bagpipes playing loudly )
( shouting ) Duncan,
this is unbelievable.
No, it's all true.
When you talked
about the house,
I didn't realize
it was so big,
and so old,
and so beautiful.
Just like you.
I mean-
- ( bagpipes stop )
- ( loudly ) not big and old-
ahem.
Now, where have
we met before?
We haven't.
I'm sure I know your face
from somewhere.
Tell me about
health and safety.
- It must be terribly exciting.
- No, it isn't.
But you seem to have
so much to do.
What were you measuring
just now?
The noise level's
over the limit.
Your piper should
be wearing ear defenders.
But it'll have to wait,
I'm on a scheduled
meal break now.
Oh, good. then we can talk
about the off-duty Mr. Barr.
I want to know all about you.
Do you have children?
I suppose if you did
they'd be called mini-barrs.
I don't.
And they wouldn't.
But there's a Mrs. Barr?
Yes.
What a shame she couldn't
have come with you.
My wife recently left me to live
with a chiropodist in Devon.
And she doesn't
return my calls.
Oh, I'm-
I'm so, so sorry.
Roast venison.
Lexie, you're meant to
serve the guests first.
And you're meant
to carve-
my laird.
( knocking )
- oh, hi.
- Not quite what you're used to, huh?
Right. did you manage
to find those books?
I reckon Duncan's got
most of what you need.
Right, what have we
got here?
"Working
with wild birds,"
"first aid, basic,"
"first aid, advanced,"
and a safety manual.
- Where's the important stuff?
- It's all important, Archie.
That's why I've been sending
Duncan on courses for the last year.
Don't you think
it might be a good idea
to tell this inspector chappie
the truth?
I don't want to spoil
Duncan's big day.
You know health and safety
can shut us down on the spot?
If he finds something wrong,
which he won't do
once I've read this lot.
I'm determined not to leave
anything up to chance.
- ( sizzling )
- Like your toast?
Like I said- why don't you
just tell this guy the truth?
I brought you something. It's
from the shop where I work.
- Wow.
- It's nothing special.
Oh! I've always wanted
one that does stunts.
It's brilliant!
May I look
at your photos?
Are they all
of your family?
Umm...
family and friends.
There are none
of Duncan.
No, he doesn't like
having his photograph taken.
( laughs )
- Lots of Archie.
- Yeah, of course.
Why?
Uh...
I'm very fond of Archie.
The chauffeur?
He's a sort of
project of mine.
Poor Archie, comes
from a very good family.
But he went to the bad-
drink, drugs, joyriding.
And the only way
to keep him out of prison-
or the lunatic asylum,
was to give him a job
on the estate.
You mean... he's mad?
If that's the head ranger
you're referring to,
he did strike me as being
somewhat on the unreliable side.
Oh, he does his best,
considering.
Poor lamb.
Ah, I see you're
admiring our roses.
Nothing wrong,
is there?
Dangerous thorns?
Excessive pollen?
No, no. it was
for my own interest.
- Are you a gardener?
- No.
These roses are
unique to Glenbogle.
There's quite a history
attached to them, actually,
very romantic.
I'm aware of that.
If you'll excuse me,
I'll bid you good night.
- Ta-da!
- ( both giggling )
Look what I made you-
it's a divorce cake.
- I burned the groom.
- That's great.
Will you put that down?
This is supposed
to be a celebration.
- But I've got this inspection tomorrow.
- that is tomorrow.
Whereas right now,
we have cham-poo,
we have cake,
and...
( sighs )
We have Russell Crowe.
So can we please
just start enjoying
ourselves?
Cheers.
Your sort of man,
is he? Russell?
Right now, any sort
of man would do.
- Duncan?
- No.
He's like a wee brother.
You must have thought about Archie.
- What about you and Archie?
- Not a chance.
Come on.
You're a free woman now.
So why would I want a man?
It's taken me years
to get rid
of the last one.
Anyway,
I asked you first.
Hmmm.
Given half a chance-
but he never does.
You've got to make
your own chances.
If you want Archie, he's not
going to make the running.
He doesn't know how.
- Your friend, Alain-
- yes.
It's a pity he
couldn't be here.
- Is he working in Edinburgh?
- Not really.
Oh, what happened?
Nothing to do with me, is it?
No, it's me.
I've been with Alain
for five years,
and now he brings me
to Edinburgh.
And we stay
in a lovely hotel,
and on Saturday
it was my birthday,
so we go
to a beautiful restaurant-
candles on the table,
and a view of the castle,
and what do you think?
He asked you
to marry him.
No.
He talked
about football.
- What team does he support?
- ( sighs )
He talked about football because he
didn't want to ask me to marry him.
Duncan, because
of your letters
I always dreamed
of coming to Scotland.
It's so beautiful,
so romantic.
Alain had arranged this
trip as a surprise for me,
and I knew where
it was leading to,
perhaps he was nervous.
It's a big thing, isn't it?
But I saw the ring.
It was in his suitcase.
There you go,
he was going to ask you.
That's the point.
I asked him why
he didn't give me
the ring, and he said-
he said that he changed
his mind.
He must be mad!
I mean- why would he
do a thing like that?
I don't know. he just said
all I could talk about now
was dresses and invitations
and churches,
and I didn't know
how to have fun anymore,
and I had changed,
and I didn't know what to say.
I just started crying.
I couldn't stay
with Alain after that,
and I didn't want
to go home alone.
I knew if I came here
you'd understand.
Well, you did
the right thing.
Stay as long as you like.
Although I do think
you ought to phone Alain.
He's bound to be
worried about you.
I know I would be.
But, Duncan,
you're different.
I wish Alain was
a bit more like you.
Good night, Duncan.
Aw, all on your own?
Here. Don't go getting used to this.
It won't last.
Lexie, can I
ask you something?
Ach, no chance.
Breakfast is the only thing
you'll be getting in bed.
No.
It's about Marie-Helene.
Mmm?
She's split up
with her boyfriend,
and, well...
it wouldn't be right
for me to-
you know-
take advantage?
Hmm, so you do
fancy her.
It's more than that.
I've never met
anyone like her.
What?
French, you mean?
No, I mean beautiful,
and kind, and funny.
- Thanks.
- What I mean is,
she could be
the one for me,
the one I've always
dreamed of finding.
Then go for it,
wee man.
- It wouldn't be fair.
- Well,
life isn't fair. Else I
wouldn't be fetching you
breakfast in bed.
- All ready?
- Yeah, I think so.
One thing, can you try
to be polite to barr?
You're the head ranger,
not the laird.
Yeah, I'll try.
But this guy's a real
jumped-up little jobsworth.
- Good morning.
- Hello. did you have a comfortable night?
- Adequate.
- Where do you want to start?
I noticed from
your literature
that, quote, "Glenbogle House
offers chainsaw sculpting
for beginners under instruction
from our trained head ranger. "
Unquote.
I'd like instruction.
My turn now?
Sorry?
I said, is it
my turn now?
Yes, of course.
You've forgotten
something.
Safety helmet,
ear defenders,
gloves,
safety boots. what?
Petrol.
Yeah, it's
correctly stored.
It should be
in the chainsaw.
That's why it
won't work.
- Where do we keep the oysters?
- In the fridge.
We've not had any
in weeks, though.
What're you doing?
I found this-
the ultimate recipe
for a night of love.
Aye, and it says oysters
are a- a aphro-something.
That's a hairstyle.
No, no, no.
The love thing.
Duncan, these magazines
are rubbish.
No one ever does this.
What am I supposed to do?
What do you usually do
when you take a lassie out?
I don't know.
What'd you do
the last time?
Went to the sweet shop.
We were 10.
Look, Duncan, there's no
secret. Just be yourself.
Now that could
be a problem.
Marie-Helene thinks
he's the laird.
Aye, and I promised her
a big special day out.
How do you think Marie-Helene
would like to spend the day?
I'm not sure.
Well, then do what
you want to do,
not what it says
in some magazine.
The most exciting, romantic,
magical thing that you can think of.
No!
( laughing )
- So far, so good.
- You think so?
It's nothing that can
close us down.
That's the hard bit. Next
two miles are downhill.
( barr groans )
Oh, my word!
Help me!
Oh, fantastic!
You've killed him.
- He stopped breathing.
- What do we do?
I'll give him heart massage,
you do mouth to mouth.
I'll do the heart massage.
Oh, all right.
- You got a handkerchief?
- No. quick!
- Aren't you going to check my pulse first?
- What?
A registered first-aider needs to
brush up on his cpr skills, doesn't he?
( laughing )
Duncan: Hold on, I've
got a present for you.
This is traditional
Scottish.
( laughing )
You're so pretty.
- Are you enjoying yourself?
- Of course.
Is this all yours?
Uh-huh.
It's so much
for one person.
I hope it won't
always be for one.
You've got girlfriends?
Well, no,
actually.
I've always been waiting
for the right one.
Where have I seen
Mr. Barr before?
Your worst nightmares.
Oh, is the inspection
not going well?
( alarm sounds )
That must be him.
Is there a fire?
No, just another one
of his safety tests.
Oh.
Oh, Archie-
you've got
to leave the house.
But you said
there isn't a fire.
The house is in flames, you're
going to be burned to a frazzle.
Oh, why didn't
you tell me?
You know how
panicked I get.
Stella, get
the fire engines.
No, our fire engine.
Bring it round the front.
- Me?
- I've got to check the rooms.
The fire drill is one thing
that I can do.
Mother!
Your father would never forgive
me if I didn't save the imperial.
( alarm continuing )
What's that noise?
That'd be the fire bell.
Shouldn't we
do something?
No, it's no bother.
There's something
I've got to say.
Marie-Helene,
I've always dreamed
that one day
I would meet someone
who would change my life.
You think you have
found her?
I know I have.
Oh, Duncan,
I'm so happy.
Marie-Helene-
Stella:
Duncan!
Duncan, I need you!
There's a fire. We have
to leave the building now.
You sure it's not
a false alarm?
You'd know better than me,
wouldn't you? We have to go.
- I need to get dressed first.
- I have three minutes to evacuate the house.
I'm not leaving
without my trousers.
- Sorry, but rules are rules.
- ( tearing )
Put me down!
Put me down, I said!
( sirens blaring )
We need to check
the water tanks.
There's no time for that, get the hose.
I do hope it's not
a big fire.
Hector will be terribly
disappointed to miss it.
Put me down!
Okay!
Is this
the fire brigade?
By my watch the house was completely
evacuated in under three minutes,
which is well within
the required time.
You want to put that
in your safety report?
Fire precautions
are out with my remit.
What?
I didn't set off
the alarm.
And I thought you'd
fully evacuated the house.
I'm terribly sorry,
but I tripped one of the
detectors with my blowtorch.
You can all
come back in now.
Great.
In the course
of my inspection,
I have found no fewer
than 73 contraventions
of health and safety
regulations.
That doesn't include
the failure to ensure
the house was evacuated
during the fire alert.
I shall not require
the premises to close down...
thank you.
...until tomorrow a. m.
I then recommend that Glenbogle
House should remain closed
until all improvements,
as listed, have been made.
Finally, I should
strongly suggest
that you dismiss
your head ranger forthwith.
However admirable your equal
opportunities policies may be
in regard to his
mental health issues,
he would appear to be
not only incompetent,
but positively
dangerous.
That's the summary
of my findings.
You'll have my
full report tomorrow.
Thank you.
Did you enjoy today?
Oh, it was fantastic.
There was something I
wanted to say to you earlier.
I think you know
what it is.
We've only been
together for a day,
but in a way we've known
each other for years.
I've always thought
of you as my best friend,
but now that we've met,
you could be-
you are more than that.
Marie-Helene... I love you.
Duncan, you're teasing.
This is one of your jokes.
No, no, I mean it,
I know that you're beginning
to feel the same towards me.
Duncan, I'm sorry-
no, you don't have
to decide just now.
I know I'm not great
looking or a big genius,
but I could look after you,
I could make you happy.
Duncan, I really like you.
You're my friend,
my best friend.
The one person I could
always talk to,
but... you're not
Alain.
But you said
that was all over.
It might be for him,
but I still love him.
I miss him so much.
I'm sorry.
I didn't want
to hurt you.
No.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
No, I need to speak
to him now.
( knocking )
( softly )
I'll come back.
No, it's okay.
It's the lawyers.
I could be
on hold all week.
Which do you think?
This or this?
Where are you going?
You said to give it a go
with Archie,
tonight's the night.
Well, he might not be
in the best of moods.
Well, he might need
a shoulder to cry on.
Look, I couldn't borrow something
of yours, could I? I'm sick of these.
Sure.
Oh, it's really nice.
- That's not very me.
- It's very Archie.
All right,
I'll give it a try.
Thanks.
Wish me luck.
( knocking )
Archie: Lexie.
Were you expecting
someone more exciting?
I wasn't expecting
anyone at all. come in.
I'm not
disturbing you, am I?
No, I was just looking
through this safety report.
Can't seem to find
a way around it.
Stella's been on to the lawyers,
I've tried to pull strings.
When it comes down to it,
we have been shafted.
That guy came here
looking to do that.
How sad does your life
have to be to end up
as bitter and twisted
as he is?
I'm well on the way
to finding out.
No, I can't blame him.
It's my own fault.
I make a lousy Duncan.
Well, he makes
a pretty good you.
Certainly knows how
to put me in my place.
- Is that what I do?
- All the time.
So, now that I've traipsed
all the way over here,
the least you can do
is offer me some dinner.
Okay.
Is that a new dress?
- Do you like it?
- Yeah, you look fantastic.
How are the eggs?
Not bad.
You should cook
more often.
Thanks.
Forgotten how much
I missed all this.
Scrambled eggs?
No, this.
Supper without
dressing up.
And my father banging on about
El-Alamain or the 10th hole...
and your cooking.
What's wrong
with my cooking?
There's nothing wrong with
your cooking. It was a joke.
And that was a lie.
You're welcome
to cook anytime.
So, you still nervous
about this inspection?
Thanks for reminding me.
Well, if there's
anything I can do.
No, you've already
done plenty.
I hadn't thought about it
for at least a half an hour.
It's funny, being down
here away from the house
helps put things
into perspective.
It's very easy to lose sight
of what's important.
So, what's important
to you?
Scrambled eggs,
mainly.
- Be serious.
- My family,
the estate, friends.
Is that enough?
For what?
To... you know,
make you happy?
Don't really know.
What about you?
The same.
I mean, I guess
I want a family...
and kids.
That does usually require
some sort of a male input.
Well, you males think far
too much about your input.
- Me?
- Yes, you.
( laughing )
Sorry, I hope I'm not
interrupting anything.
Look, I know it's late,
but I really need
to speak to Archie
about what the lawyer said.
Right, yeah.
Why don't I make
some coffee first? Lex?
Please.
That would be great,
thanks.
So, how's it going then?
( knocking )
Molly: Mr. Barr?
Hello.
Your trousers- oh.
I did my best, but needlework
has never been my forte.
Thank you.
Oh, is that
Mrs. Barr?
Yes.
That's the Glenbogle rose.
When was it you were
here before?
- A very long time ago.
- May I?
Oh, she's a very
attractive woman.
She was then-
and she still is.
Was this a special
occasion?
You could say that.
It was for me, anyway.
Good night, Mr. Barr.
Duncan...?
Tell me.
What is it
about me?
I thought that
if I had a better job,
or a big house, or a fancy car,
then I'd get a girlfriend.
I'm the laird of Glenbogle
and she's still not interested.
- What is it?
- What happened?
I told her how I felt about her.
She thought it was a joke.
- What's wrong with me?
- There's nothing wrong with you.
You'll find
someone else.
I don't want someone else. I want her.
Well, sometimes
that just can't happen.
You know,
you love someone,
and they just
can't see it,
or they want
other things.
And other people
get in the way.
You're just
saying that.
No, I'm not.
It takes two to tango,
and one half
fallen in love...
just isn't enough.
Tell me all about it. We'll
try and work something out.
Is that a new dress?
Do you like it?
Yes. you look great.
- Morning, lass.
- Good morning.
You're not going to need
that at breakfast.
- I'll take that.
- No, no, really-
- it's too heavy.
- Thank you.
Not at all.
- Hi.
What are you
making?
Eggs.
You should do it.
You're the expert.
It's different
down here.
I noticed.
Thanks for
last night.
Look, I'm sorry it ended the way it did,
but, you know,
Stella was worried.
So she should be.
Her timing's terrible.
Hmm. we had fun,
didn't we?
I wish things could always be like that
- just simple.
Who are you
calling "simple"?
The girl that just broke
an egg into a mug of tea.
Is it there?
I can't find it.
Let me look.
Get away.
- Here it is.
- I cannot do this.
I'll make the call.
All you have to do
is keep Marie-Helene here
as long as you can.
- Lexie's going to help too-
- what if it doesn't work?
You have to make it work.
You've lied to that girl,
in your letters,
and ever since she came here.
Look at the mess
both of you are in.
Now you owe it to her
to do the right thing.
This seems pretty
comprehensive.
Congratulations, Mr. Barr. You've
almost certainly closed us for good.
Well, that's not
my problem.
Not until you've closed every
business in the highlands.
Then you might find
yourself out of a job.
I'd say you were in more
danger of that than me.
Good day.
Mr. Barr, I need
to talk to you.
I was arrogant
and inexcusably rude.
I also haven't been telling
the truth about things.
I am, in fact,
the laird of Glenbogle.
I swapped jobs
with my head ranger
because his French
pen pal had come to visit.
And the whole thing
with the lifebelt,
my brother drowned in the
loch, so I get very angry
if anybody suggests that
I don't care about safety.
The truth is that my
father has had an operation.
My mother took the lifebelt
so he could sit on it.
Mrs. MacDonald told me
about your condition.
- I do understand.
- What condition?
The mental health issue.
You think I'm crazy?
No more so than
anyone else around here.
Would you excuse me?
Thank you.
I want to leave
as soon as possible.
You have to have
breakfast first.
I don't want
to see Duncan.
I can't explain.
There's a train at 10:00.
I'd like to take it.
Don't worry because if you miss
that one, there's plenty more.
Not on the timetable.
Oh!
You don't want to go
looking at that, do you?
Now, come on,
eat up.
Because we've got
kidneys still to come.
Oh...
and toast.
Molly: It would be
easier with secateurs.
I can explain.
No need.
I know already.
You were planning
a trip to Devon,
and you wanted to take a bunch
of Glenbogle roses with you.
- How did you know that?
- Because we've met before, Mr. Barr.
It was exactly 25 years ago
in this garden.
I took the photograph of you and
Mona that you have by your bed.
- You know her name?
- It's all here, in my journal.
I wrote about how
a young man
proposed to his girlfriend,
Mona, in our garden.
During one of our
open days.
She told me all about it when she
asked me to take the photograph.
I guessed that you wanted to take
your Mona a reminder of that day.
Here, let me.
Did you think your wife
might change her mind?
Come back to you?
- It sounds pretty stupid.
- Not at all.
I think it's the most
wonderful, romantic gesture.
A crime of passion.
And I know how you feel.
With respect,
you don't.
Mona walked out on me
without a word
after 22 years.
You have no idea.
I do-
of course, I do.
The same thing
happened to me.
My husband, Hector,
he- he left me...
for an upholsterer
in Lossiemouth.
He's probably pumping up
her cushions as we speak.
I'm sorry,
I spoke out of turn.
I love my Hector,
I still do.
He was a colossus mentally,
physically, spiritually,
and when he left, I-
I couldn't cope.
The house went
to wrack and ruin,
the staff out of control,
but Hector loves this house.
And if I can just keep it
going, maybe one day
he'll return to the place
where he was truly happy.
Wouldn't it be
wonderful
if we were able to help
one another in some way?
Can't that wait
a minute, dear?
- I've got to tell the bank the estate's closed.
- There's no need to.
Mr. Barr has given us
six month's grace.
I simply found the words
to make him feel better.
And in a way,
your father helped, too.
Mother,
you're a genius.
Marie-Helene:
When is the train?
There's something
I've got to tell you.
Duncan, I already
told you.
You know how I feel
about Alain.
So you did.
There's someone going in
the same direction as you,
someone to share
your journey home with.
Alain?
I phoned him.
He was worried sick.
You did this for me?
What do I say
to him?
Tell him you don't care
if you get married
in a church
or a kite shop,
life's no fun
without him.
Tell him
you love him.
I borrowed this top.
Is that okay?
No worries.
Where are you going?
Out for a drink
with Archie.
Now we're not
closing down,
- we need to talk about a business plan.
- In that top?
Well,
it's very pretty.
Then you won't mind
if I come too, then.
Go on then, girl.
Age before beauty.
( theme music playing )
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0