Archie: This ball is going to
be the biggest day of the year.
Lascelles are bringing
some major investors here
to show them how they've
turned the place around.
How we've
turned it around.
Duncan, you'll organize
the parking.
Golly, the Americans
love the pipes.
Molly, our foreign
visitors
are expecting something
between the Queen
- and the brunette in "Braveheart. "
- Leave it to me.
Archie and I will be front
of house pressing the flesh.
Oh, Lexie.
- You're in the kitchen.
- Surprise, surprise.
Archie: Now the next
three days are going to be
the most seamless,
well-oiled
and least accident-prone
in the history of Glenbogle.
If we pull together,
Lascelles could get
some really good P.R.,
and we can have a good time.
- Could you list my duties?
- Yes, father.
The stone ceremony.
Concentrate on that.
It's what everyone's coming
to see and it's in your hands.
You can
count on me.
Why does that have a
slightly hollow ring to it?
( theme music plays )
Stone of the MacDonalds? I
thought that was just a legend.
An ancient symbol
of MacDonald power.
It was carried into
battle at Bannockburn,
Midsummer's Day, 1314. When
we sent the English packing.
Not before the stone was cloven
in three by an English ax.
Oh, I say,
bad luck.
At Midsummer Ball, the three
fragments must be joined.
About the ball...
the Glenbogle
fragment.
- You've got one?
- The largest, naturally.
You sure it's quite safe
to keep it in a cake tin?
My dear Kilwillie,
I guard this with my life.
If lost, my family name
is blackened forever.
Jolly serious.
As is the guest list,
I hear.
Captains of industry?
Captains? generals.
They're sending generals.
My invitation seems
to have gone astray.
Generals of industry and
MacDonalds only, I'm afraid.
I, Kilwillie, shunned?
My dear Kilwillie, the bank
is lavishing money on Glenbogle
because it wishes to bask in
our ancient ties and traditions.
I suggest you organize
some of your own
should you require access
to the upper echelons.
Good day to you.
It's been 10 years since
the last Midsummer Ball,
and guess what?
Lexie is in the kitchen.
And I'm probably
expected.
We've 20 of Lascelles'
top clients
and 40 MacDonalds to feed.
I need you here.
And you think he needs
you at the ball?
This is our night.
Mine and Archie's.
You'll do a wonderful
job down here.
True.
I suppose he'll be more impressed
by the food on the table,
than the tart
on this arm.
I don't see him bursting a
blood vessel to get you invited.
You are going because
the bank is paying you.
You don't think he
wants you there, do you?
And he wants you here
out of his way.
Out of whose way?
You better
watch her, Arch.
She's trying to get her
claws into you for the ball.
Tell her she's
just a bank manager.
- That's not entirely true,
- don't be hard on her.
She's hoping you'll waft her
out of here on a white charger.
Tell her she's just
a housekeeper.
I'd never say that.
I'm flattered to have
cropped up in conversation,
but we have to work
together, remember?
For the bank, for the estate.
So cease fire?
Of course, Archie.
Fine by me.
Aye.
I can't stand
around here having fun.
My ball gown
is arriving this morning.
Well, make sure you
enjoy your night of glory.
Archie and me will still be here
when you'll just be a bad memory.
( door slams )
Stella,
good to see you.
Archie MacDonald,
Laird of Glenbogle.
Toby Winslow, head of
corporate affairs, Lascelles.
You know what we've got
riding on this event?
Yes, you're planning
a big expansion
into leisure finance
and management.
Worldwide. From this little
acorn a mighty oak will grow.
- The chairman not with you?
- His flight's delayed.
The old boy usually swans
in to take the plaudits.
It is his train set,
after all.
He's planning to hand the
estate back to you, Archie.
- at the ball.
- What?
- That's fantastic.
- I did say planning.
His changes of heart are
legendary. You've been warned.
Stella?
Looks like it's just
you and me now. Eh, boss?
Golly:
Archie. Archie.
It's about the music
for the ball.
- A band from Inverness. - The Bogle Boys
will be mightily disappointed.
They played at the last ball.
You probably wouldn't remember.
Yes, of course.
The Bogle Boys.
Voted the best band in the
glen four years running.
Even cut a waxing,
I believe.
The Inverness lot
come highly recommended.
They're brilliant,
but they're not your people.
The Bogle Boys are.
Look, Golly,
I know the laird
has responsibilities,
but isn't this
going a bit far?
There's 39,000 acres and all
the folk that live on them,
that's how far it goes.
Winslow:
300 grand.
Double it
with bonuses.
And your own empire
to build.
This is a huge step.
You won't be wasting
your talents
on the Archie MacDonalds
of this world.
Big league, Stella.
Do I get time
to think about it?
Straight after the ball,
you're out of here.
A couple of days and you're on
a plane to meet your new team.
- Toby, I-
- your star is rising.
As I always said
it would be.
I hope that nothing
goes wrong.
I mean, I'd hate to be stuck
here for another six months.
Oh, don't worry. Things
would have to go badly wrong
for me to leave you
at Glenbogle.
How badly exactly?
Boys.
This is Archie MacDonald
from the big house.
Archie, this
is Graeme.
This is his
kid brother, lain,
and that's
young Alistair.
Gents, how would you
like to perform again?
We've got the Midsummer Ball coming
up and we'd like you to play at it.
I'll no more play
for that family
than fly to the moon.
Aye. your father laid him
off like the rest of us.
But Graeme's
a proud man.
Knocked the stuffing
out of him.
Hasn't had the heart
to play a note since.
Well done, Duncan.
Well, we want
to impress him, right?
This chairman,
lord what's-his-name?
Cranthorne, yes.
You collect him, Duncan,
in the Land Rover.
What?
And come back
the scenic route.
He'll like that.
I haven't come
to fight.
Well, don't go against
ritual on my account.
Dinner tonight
for Lord Cranthorne.
Wild salmon with
all the trimmings.
Smoked duck to start.
That sounds
wonderful.
But...?
Lord Cranthorne.
He's a bit of an oddball.
When he's
in Scotland...
go on.
He makes a big point
about a simple supper.
Bit of old scrag end,
a few turnips.
Crofter's stew?
Yeah, terrible
if you ask me.
Well, I'm cooking for Lord
Cranthorne, my girl, not you.
And what
the man wants,
the man gets.
I take it
you knew about that.
I can't lie
to you, Archie,
but people like Graeme used to
be proud to live in this glen.
They will be again once the
estate is back on its feet.
You can't restore a man's pride
by showing him the bottom line.
That's what the bank
wants to see.
There are better judges of
a man than the moneylenders.
Like Graeme?
Oh, look, Archie.
You asked me
if I thought you could run
the estate and I said yes.
You never asked if I thought
you could be laird of Glenbogle.
And?
You've got a wee bit
to go yet, son.
Duncan!
Here's Lord Cranthorne now.
His family were at Bannockburn.
What?
On the other side, obviously.
But it's such a long time ago.
In the history
of the MacDonalds
the merest blinking
of an eye.
Just a little
high spirits.
Not one step further.
- This is Lord Cranthorne.
- Of Bannockburn infamy.
- Who's this lunatic?
- The father.
Oh, god.
Midsummer Day, 1314.
Ring any bells?
Perhaps you two
could catch up inside.
- You shall not pass!
- Archie: father! father!
Come, Cranthorne,
let's grapple hand-to-hand,
as our forefathers did
in that bloody field.
The truth is,
the Cranthorne family
were more into catering
at that particular skirmish.
Catering?
Ha!
Archie MacDonald,
Lord Cranthorne.
I apologize
for my father.
Mr. MacDonald, you're part
of a great tradition.
Turn it to profit,
not doorstep confrontation.
Toby.
Catering.
Stella: This is a wooden
copy of the Glenbogle stone.
Yeah, most of this stuff's locally made.
Comes cheaper from Taiwan.
Who'd know the difference?
Well, Archie's loyal
to the local people.
Narrower margins, but the
local economy benefits.
I can't recall agreeing to the financing
of the whole
of highlands.
My lord?
Archie?
You've cleared my things
off the billiard table.
- I thought our guests might like a game.
- I might have been consulted.
You weren't around. There wasn't
anything important, was there?
No. no. Where did you put it all?
I told Duncan to put it
in the back cellar.
Ah, the back cellar.
So Lascelles give the keys
to Arch, and Stella's gone.
- You sure?
- Hm-mm.
After the ball is over,
you, sister,
are up, up,
up and away.
Alexandra.
Duncan,
you removed
certain personal effects
of mine to storage.
Ah, the train set. aye.
It's in the back cellar.
Not quite.
You will recall
a Dundee cake tin?
Where are
the contents, lad?
- I didn't eat it.
- Of course you didn't eat it.
It's got raisins in it.
I don't like.
- They get stuck in your teeth.
- Don't play the slippery eel with me.
- Maybe I had a wee peek.
- Where did you put it?
- There was nothing in it.
- Duncan...
I swear to you, boss,
it was empty.
Archie:
Yes, it's tragic, really.
They were one of the best bands
in the highlands in their day.
You can't cling
to the past.
No, no, of course. But
I still feel responsible.
Your responsibilities
are to the bank.
500,000 of them
at the last count.
You're not going
to go soft on us?
- No.
- ( bagpipe playing )
Molly:
What's this, Lexie?
Crofter's stew.
Scrag end.
Here we are.
Mutton, neeps,
and tatties-
a simple highland supper.
How... very authentic.
Oh, thank you,
your lordship. enjoy.
( low groan )
Cranthorne: I don't know what that was.
I doubt his mother
knew, either.
I take it you've hired
a real chef for the ball?
- Archie: Er, no.
- I suggest you do.
- I can't do that.
- Oh, nonsense.
I've hired and fired more
chefs than I've had hot dinners.
Almost as many,
come to think of it.
It's no big deal, Archie.
The bank's paying.
It's not the money, it's
Lexie. She'll be mortified.
I admire loyalty, but
Cranthorne has spoken.
You want the keys back?
Do as he says.
If Archie finds out
I've lost it, oh, Molly-
if I don't produce it
at the ball,
our boy will be deposed as
head of the clan. The shame.
Oh, come on. think.
I'm sure I put it back in the
tin when that ass Kilwillie went.
Oh, don't tell me that you two
have been falling out again.
He was begging me for an
invitation to the ball.
I told him it was
rather exclusive.
- And then he left?
- No, damn it, I left-
I left.
I left Kilwillie alone
with the Glenbogle fragment.
Molly, you're a genius.
But how can we
get him to confess?
Leave it to me.
I'll make him squeal.
We'll be "mutt and Jeff. "
"Good cop, bad cop" to you.
Splendid, woman. We'll collar
the rotter tomorrow. yes!
Hector? Molly?
Now squeal, Kilwillie.
Or I'll put the arm on.
We're only here
to help you, old man.
What's the matter
with you both?
Nice place you've
got here, Kilwillie.
Yes, shame if it
was smashed up.
- Now steady on-!
- 'Fess up, Kilwillie,
unless you'd rather bat
the blab with the pigs.
Is this some sort
of Esperanto?
- What have you done with it?
- Oh, all right. I did take it.
But Hector was
damnably rude to me.
Oh, save it
for the social worker.
Hector, if you were rude
you must say, "sorry. "
- ( mumbling ) sorry.
- Speak up, dear.
- Sorry. now I will use my
considerable influence- - Hector!
- I'll get you an invitation.
- Well, then...
to Glenbogle, friends,
where the ancient fragment
rests in complete
security.
- I sincerely hope so.
- It's better than a Dundee cake tin, Hector.
I thought it went well last
night. Lord Cranthorne's right.
It's nice to have something
authentic for a wee change.
It was certainly
a change, Lex.
So have you come
to help me dry up?
No, it's about
the ball, actually.
I've decided
to hire a chef.
- You said-
- I know what I said.
- I was the only one you could trust.
- And I meant it.
- "I depend on you, Lexie. "
- I do, I do.
So now you drop me
like a dirty rag?
I did it so you could
come to the ball, Lex.
Oh, Arch...
you're such a sweet man.
- Come in.
- Morning.
Now...
drama schools,
draft proofing...
ah- dress hire.
Should I be
curious?
I shall go
to the ball.
You're going to a lot
of trouble for nothing.
So are you. Going as
a packet of wine gums?
I'm going as
Archie's partner.
- Who's cooking?
- Ask your partner.
He fixed it for me.
Penny for them.
That is a derisory offer,
Stella Moon, and you know it.
I gather Lexie isn't
cooking for the ball.
Any special reason?
Yes. Cranthorne took
against her crofter's stew,
but I thought it best
not to mention that.
Oh. your management skills
are improving.
- Problem?
- Finding a chef.
"Jeff Ramsden. "
Any good?
Yeah. and at a loose end
as far as I know.
I saw it
in a cinema film.
A burglar
placed his swag
in the lavatory system
for later collection.
Get on with it.
Any more of that, you can fish
the bally thing out yourself.
It's been removed.
The fragment
isn't there.
What?
I swear to you, I put it
there myself yesterday morning.
But now it's gone.
Ooh-hh...
I'm guessing
it's some years
since a MacDonald
last knocked on your door.
It's a few.
We were loggers-
myself, brother lain,
young Alistair.
30 years we tended
these forests.
10 years ago your father
laid us off.
Truth to tell, it was
at the Midsummer Ball.
- His timing isn't perfect.
- We played,
whilst the nobs danced
and cavorted before us.
Dancing this fine estate
into oblivion
with great grins
on their faces.
Look, Graeme,
I can't help the past,
but I'm running it now.
The estate's back
on its feet.
It staggers a bit from time
to time, but it's working.
And I want you
to feel part of it.
That's a fine
sentiment.
It's more than that, Graeme.
Glenbogle's back,
and it wants to hear
its own music again.
Haven't touched this
in 10 years, mate.
Do you want to play?
We'll give it a go.
Before you start,
I'm going,
and there's nothing
you can do to stop me.
Can we talk normally
for once?
Look, I know
you're fond of Archie,
and he's lucky
to have you.
As his housekeeper,
no doubt?
Whereas you've got
the great business mind.
You say the right things, hang
about with all the right people.
You think Archie's just some
tasty lad from down the street?
He's the laird of Glenbogle.
How could you live up to that?
- I love him.
- that's not hard.
The rest is.
Keep what you've got
with Archie right now-
his affection and respect-
but don't dream
of anything more.
Well, he fixed it for me
to go to the ball.
Cranthorne didn't like
your cooking, Lexie.
Archie was just trying to
spare your feelings. That's all.
You ready?
I'm not going
to go.
- What she been saying to you?
- Nothing.
That you're just some little
skivvy, and she's what,
god's gift
to banking?
Well, I thought
you fancied her.
I did.
Oh, come on, Lex.
You're worth
10 of her.
Duncan, will I make
a fool of myself?
Dressed like that,
you will.
Ahem...
I feel like
a Christmas tree.
Well, say something.
Really?
Wow.
Can you have a look
at the price tag for me?
I can't get at it.
Oh.
I wanted to hire the dress,
not buy the shop.
Oh, well.
Nice while it lasted.
Don't be such
a fool, girl.
I can't take that.
Yes, you can.
- Duncan, that's all-
- take it.
Thanks, Dunc.
I owe you one.
Hector:
Duncan!
Have you been messing about
with the thunderbox?
Oh, I fixed it
like you said, boss.
- Some loon had put a rock in the system.
- What do you mean, loon?
- "Rock"?
- And where would the "rock" be now?
Shouldn't we come back in
the morning when it's open?
The future of Glenbogle
is at stake.
We have to get through
this wire now.
But look at me. I can't go
in there in these clothes.
I don't think
there's a dress code.
You boys go in.
I'll keep watch.
I'll help Molly.
Where's your sense
of moral fortitude, man?
What is the matter with you?
Get through the hole.
- Hector: Go on.
- Really-!
( playing off-key )
Well, you know what they
say about a bad rehearsal.
You've managed to find the musical
equivalent of crofter's stew.
- Authentic?
- Unpalatable.
They haven't
got loose yet.
Oh, yes they have.
I don't know where from.
Wherever it is, send them back
and hire some musicians.
Give them a chance.
I owe these guys.
If we're talking what
you owe, Mr. MacDonald,
I think my bank
has precedence
over this bunch
of tuneless amateurs.
Fellows, please-!
We'll not embarrass
you further.
You bring me in a bone shake
driven by a madman,
to be greeted by your father
spoiling for a fight,
you serve a bowl of gristle
swimming in fat,
and now you have
no musicians.
Jeff Ramsden.
Archie, chef.
Am I glad to see you.
- What's he doing here?
- This is Lord Cranthorne.
- I know who he is.
- Have we met?
Yeah, just the once. He's fired
more chefs than he's had hot dinners.
Did he tell you that?
Proud of it, his lordship.
I'm sure we can
sort this out.
Only one thing to sort out
- who's cooking tomorrow.
- Jeff, please.
- I'm sorry, mate.
I'm not hanging around to get the
push again, not from that creep.
Now you have no chef, either.
Cancel the ball.
Kilwillie: Oh, Hector, I'm so tired.
Can't we just
call it a day?
We'll call it no such thing.
I'll leave no stone unturned.
- Duncan: got it! -
Don't interrupt. No stone-
got it!
Bravo!
Well done!
Like so many
of your plans, Hector,
this one was a corker
until the moment
of catastrophic failure.
Oh, shut up.
I won't have
Lascelles
associated with
a catastrophe like you.
Your guests will already
be on their way.
Tomorrow morning everything
will be ironed out.
It'll all be running
like clockwork.
If there's
a disaster-
there won't be any more
disasters. I promise you.
Merely assisting
in certain inquiries.
We picked up these four
at the municipal dump
sorting through
the rubbish.
Claim some
connection with you.
Yes, officer.
They're mine.
Try and keep your nose
clean, Lord Cranthorne.
Archie: Lord Cranthorne
seems upset for some reason.
I can't think why.
The thing is, tomorrow is one of
the most important days of the year.
And everything is
hanging in rags.
Is there anything
we can do?
Well, I wonder,
just for tomorrow,
if you could all try to pass
yourself off as normal human beings.
It's not your fault,
you know.
No, but it's my
responsibility.
I used to think Glenbogle
was my future, you know?
- It still is.
- No, no...
you see, I am Glenbogle's
future. There's a big difference.
35,000 acres and all
the people on them-
I am their future.
I can't even organize a dance.
It's just a setback.
Hm - the Bogle Boys,
they didn't believe in me, either.
I believe in you.
But if things do go wrong,
and I have to stay,
would that be the worst
thing in the world?
No, of course not.
But the way things are going,
I wouldn't pack just yet.
- ( knocking )
- Come in.
Hi, Arch.
What's wrong?
Do you not
like it?
No, it's beautiful.
- Then why the long face?
- My new chef's done a bunk.
You cannot
be serious.
Well, who else
can I ask?
Good old Lexie,
resident doormat.
Is that how you feel?
One minute I'm going
to the ball,
the next minute
I'm stuck in the kitchen.
Stella's right.
I'm just the housekeeper.
You know I don't
think of you like that.
- You don't think of me at all.
- I do.
I do, Lexie. a lot.
Well, you've got a funny way
of showing it, Archie MacDonald.
Just go now, please.
The Glenbogle fragment
retrieved
from Bannockburn.
Tonight we rejoin
the stone
which the English
broke asunder.
The ball is now
an assured success.
Hmm...
( door closes )
( chuckles )
Nothing changes, Golly.
You saw how we were treated.
Not by Archie.
lain: His heart's in
the right place, man,
but Glenbogle is gone.
It'll never rise again.
Our ancestors thought that
about the sun.
In the winter they built fires,
made music, danced,
so the pounding of their feet
would awaken the earth.
They didn't sit in a pub,
waiting for someone else to do it.
Young Archie's put his neck
on the block for you.
It's time you stood up
and were counted.
What's this?
You didn't honestly think you
could manage without me, did you?
You know
that I can't.
It's not your fault
the chef walked out,
so Lexie
to the rescue.
Now away and do
some lairdly duties.
Let me to my kitchen.
- I can help.
- I can manage.
I'd like to,
if that's okay.
Go start
on the potatoes.
I don't deserve you,
you know that?
What's to deserve?
Where would I be
without you?
Probably doing the meat
as well as veg.
Duncan.
Just the man.
I hate to put this on you,
but our guests want to see
something of the estate
before the ball.
No problem.
Meet the cars at the gate.
You can walk from there.
Walk?
Take them on one
of your nature trails.
Show them - oh, you know so
much more about it than I do.
Use your... imagination.
You really should be
somewhere else.
Go on. your guests
are arriving.
Amazing, all this time and
effort for just one night.
Arch, it's what
you were born to do.
Same as this is
what I was born to do.
Each to their own, eh?
I wish you were going
to be there, Lex.
I'll be here,
where you need me.
Now, go. Stella will be
wondering where you are,
and I have
work to do.
Welcome to Glenbogle.
And I'm pleased to offer,
as requested,
a short walking tour
of the estate.
The theme of this
evening's tour will be,
"a day in the life
of a head ranger. "
Ah, Hamish, with
the Ochtaglen fragment.
It's a proud day
to be a MacDonald.
And Robert, with the Kalpochie
fragment. All are safely gathered in.
'Tis as well.
We none of us
want our families
blackened for all eternity.
- Quite so.
- Absolutely.
Ah, Lord Cranthorne.
I've strict instructions-
no wallflowers.
So this is Melissa,
your buddy for the evening.
Wonderful idea,
this buddy system.
Now, you two get to know each
other. I've more matches to make.
Come along.
( playing off-key )
Get that woman
away from me.
You didn't hit it off?
Oh, dear.
Never mind, there's a nice
young man over here
who's simply dying
to be your buddy.
Mother, I don't think Lord
Cranthorne needs a buddy.
Lexie would like
some help in the kitchen.
Oh, excuse me.
- All going very well.
- Do you think so?
No, a disaster,
as predicted.
Not that it matters.
There are very few guests.
The others will be
along soon, I'm sure.
How do you maintain your relentless
optimism in the face of doom?
Practice.
Hmm.
I was only trying to help. I thought
this buddy thing was all the rage.
- Who told you that?
- Stella.
And so here we are.
I can't accept
gratuities, gentlemen.
What have you done to
them, you great white loaf?
Duncan:
Just following orders.
Ha- I'll bet you
I know whose.
I say, old man.
You've bad news?
Of the very worst kind.
The fragment has vanished again.
To lose the fragment once,
Hector, is unfortunate-
- to lose it-
- spare me the claptrap.
I locked it in the sideboard
this morning.
- Are you certain?
- Cranthorne watched me.
Ask him if you don't
believe me.
Cranthorne? Whose forbearers
were defeated at Bannockburn
by your own, which we
celebrate this very night?
- The same.
- Who had the means, the motive,
and the opportunity to steal
the Glenbogle fragment?
That Cranthorne?
Archie: The estate and the
bank are working hand in glove.
Villain!
I denounce you...
as a thief
and a blackheart!
This man has stolen
the Glenbogle fragment!
Gentlemen, please! Please,
I'm sure we can sort this out.
On with the ball.
There's nothing to see here.
Music! dancing!
I'd say we've got to the end
of the road, wouldn't you?
You give us just enough rope
to hang ourselves
and Archie
along with us.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Hector's greeting?
- The crofter's stew?
- You cooked it.
The disappearing chef?
And Duncan's walking tours?
- Well, you know Duncan-
- yeah, and so do you.
Which leads me
to- "the buddy system. "
Lexie, I didn't mean
any harm.
Yeah, right.
I just wanted more time
here... with Archie.
I never thought I'd fall
for anyone again...
after Graham.
And then
being here, I have.
Lexie, please
don't hate me for it.
For loving Archie?
How can I?
Oh, god- bring back
the old Stella,
the hard-nosed bitch you
could have a good scrap with.
You're going
to tell him?
I think that should
come from you.
Golly, do you think the Bogle
Boys could manage another dirge?
It's not entirely inappropriate
under the circumstances.
I'm sorry, boss.
Okay. ah-!
They're not for you.
Molly, take these
to the patrons, please.
Hector, go and apologize
to Lord Cranthorne.
Grovel, beg, crawl.
I don't care what you do,
but make sure he's here
in the next five minutes.
Golly, go and tell
the Bogle Boys
if their fingers aren't loose
in the next six minutes,
I'm going to pull them off
one by one.
- Duncan, kitchen.
- I know you're trying to help-
you go and find Stella. She's
got something to tell you.
( knocking )
You wanted something?
The last few days have been
a bit of a shambles-
Duncan, Hector,
the crofter's stew-
yes, I don't know
what go into them.
It was me.
I told Duncan
to use the Land Rover.
I told Lexie that Cranthorne
likes plain cooking.
Ah.
I wanted to stay here
because...
I think I've fallen
in love with you, Archie.
Look, Stella, I'm-
I thought you might feel the
same... if we had more time.
Now I've made a real fool
of myself. not like me, eh?
You're fond of me,
aren't you?
Actually, I think
there might be someone else.
( softly )
Lexie.
She found me out
tonight.
She didn't say anything.
She just put it right for
you. Like she always has.
Like she always will...
if you let her.
The last throw
of the dice.
Poor Hector.
Come with me.
I want you there when it
all fits together at last.
Man:
Present the stones.
Hamish:
Hector MacDonald...
a dark duty
befalls me,
for a part of the stone
that was broken has been lost.
Just mislaid.
Oh, Archie!
Fellow MacDonalds,
honored guests,
we've had a sassenach
in our midst.
A sassenach we thrashed
at Bannockburn.
Lord Cranthorne,
you have witnessed us
at our worst.
I'm so glad you were able
to remain long enough
to see us at our best.
Our unity...
our pride in who we are
and what we've achieved,
and our confidence
in the future.
Lord Cranthorne...
would you be so kind?
I'd be honored, sir.
What was broken,
is now restored...
like this
great estate.
There's a spirit
in Glenbogle,
and I share Hector's faith
in the future.
Archie... Laird...
Glenbogle is restored
to you again.
( applause, cheers )
Graeme:
Now that's worth a tune!
( playing in tune )
I've scheduled five meetings.
They're all panting to invest.
They seem to think this was
a sort of themed evening.
All this chaos,
then Lascelles sweeps in
- bringing success and happiness.
- One travels in hope.
Toby seems to think
you can manage without me.
He's offered me
South America.
Not all of it?
If it was, it would come
in a very poor second.
You'll be missed.
I'll always carry this
place in my heart, Archie,
wherever I am.
Goodbye, Archie.
Goodbye.
Well, that went
okay, didn't it?
Better than that.
You are a wonder.
Get away.
Bet you'll never get
another housekeeper like me.
You know,
all this time,
there's been something...
working away
at me inside.
These last few days,
I realize what it is.
Crofter's stew,
probably.
Lexie, I love you.
I think
I always have.
This isn't
a fairy tale, Arch.
We don't get
a happy ending.
We do if we
love each other.
But you're the laird.
I'm still the housekeeper.
I want you
to be my wife.
I couldn't live up
to that.
I'd let you down.
I couldn't bear that.
You wouldn't let me down.
You never let me down.
That's different.
This- this is
what I know.
- This is where I belong.
- You belong with me.
Don't.
I'm not right for you.
There are all kinds
of excuses
for letting happiness
slip through your fingers.
Let's not do that.
Let's take our chance.
Look at this place.
If it's clean for breakfast,
it'll be a miracle.
( footsteps )
( music plays )
Take a chance?
I don't have
a ring.
No excuses.
( theme music plays )
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0