( thunderclap )
I can feel a presence.
That would be Duncan.
He's outside the door.
And he's supposed
to be fixing the generator,
- not earwigging on his Auntie Liz.
- Duncan: all right, Lex.
It was very sweet of him
to arrange this for me.
You really shouldn't have put
yourself to all this trouble.
No trouble.
A wedding anniversary
is a wedding anniversary,
in this world
and the next.
Hector was never very good
at things like anniversaries.
Try calling him.
He wasn't much good
at listening, either.
We've made contact.
S...
O...
A...
P.
Does that mean
something to you?
( Lexie giggling )
Sorry, that was me.
Shopping list.
Oh thanks, Duncan.
Hector MacDonald,
are you there?
Probably gone fishing
or something.
No, no, there's someone
trying to get through.
He has a message,
an urgent message.
A warning.
( rattling )
What is it?
I don't know.
( theme music playing )
Archie?
( door closes )
- Hi.
- ( gasps )
Was that just you there?
No, this is me.
Why, what's wrong?
I've just got
this feeling that some-
oh, nothing. Why are
you not in the office?
Well, I thought I'd take
a couple of days off.
Ooh, what's brought
this on?
Well, the death duties
are paid,
the wolf park's doing okay, we all
seem to be talking to one another.
There's not a cloud
on the horizon.
So... what are we
gonna do then?
Come and see.
Jamie's room?
Yeah, we did the right
thing clearing it,
but we can't leave
it like this.
It's neither one thing nor the
other. I want to redecorate.
Archie, we can't afford
decorators just now.
No, I'll do it myself.
- ( laughs ) you?
- Any objections?
You don't know your Artex
from your elbow.
- Thank you.
- And what about the estate?
And the village art show?
They don't run by themselves.
Well, I had hoped that my
beautiful and talented wife
might do that. This'll
only take a couple of days.
And the rest. And you can't have
Duncan and Golly to help you.
- I'll need them.
- No, I'll do it on my own.
There is no way that
you're gonna be able
to decorate this
without any help.
I'd put money
on it.
All right,
you're on.
Let's say dinner for two at a
restaurant of the winner's choice.
I'll start looking
at the good food guide.
Okay.
You don't have
to run away.
I'm-
I'm not.
Yes, you are, and you have
been for the last week.
If you'd give me
a chance to explain.
What is there to explain? My
so-called girlfriend's pregnant
and won't tell me who the father
is. Seems pretty clear to me.
Duncan, I understand
how you feel.
Oh, do you? that's good,
because I don't.
In fact, right now, I have
absolutely no idea how I feel.
All I know is that I don't even
want to be in the same room as you.
I'm sorry.
Are you all right?
I'm gonna be sick, so
unless you want to watch...
morning.
I'm sorry if I've
interrupted something.
No, you're
all right, Golly,
we're finished.
- What are you doing?
- Tidying up.
Your painting things.
I haven't managed
to finish a single thing
since I did that portrait
of your father.
So I'm hanging up
my brushes
and turning in
my turpentine.
You can't give up painting.
You've always loved it.
I'm not giving up painting.
Painting's giving up me.
I sometimes think I only did
it to get away from your father.
No need to do that now.
What about the art competition?
you've entered that for years.
There'll be plenty
of entries without mine.
Did you want something?
Oh, yeah, I wondered if you
might go and see Andrew Booth.
You know, welcome him
to Glenbogle.
I'd go myself but I'm
gonna be busy redecorating.
Redecorating?
Are you sure that's
a good idea?
Oh, hi, Lexie.
- Have you got a minute?
- Uh-huh, come in.
- That was some show.
- Sorry?
That banging outside the
window, it was quite scary.
How did you do that?
How did I do what?
You know,
the flash of light.
I'm sure that I saw someone
or something out there.
So there was a ghost.
Oh, Lexie.
There are no ghosts
at Glenbogle.
Have you never heard
of Robert MacDonald?
Yeah, but that was a story
just made up for the tourists.
The ghost of the first laird
always appears
at times of trouble
for the family.
So where has he been
for the past few years?
- Do you not know the story?
- No.
Robert MacDonald married
a serving girl, Mhari,
who worked
for the family.
A year and a day later
he disappeared.
All his young bride found
was a charred corpse.
You're making this up.
No, I've a book somewhere
that tells you all about it.
I'll lend it to you
if you like.
Oh, Lexie, would you
do me a favor?
I'm secretary for the Highland
Spiritualist and Clairvoyant Circle.
I'm up for re-election,
and if I could just show
the girls Robert MacDonald...
okay, okay, why not?
Bring them round for
dinner tomorrow night.
Oh, thanks.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Is anyone actually
serving here?
Gordon runs
the post office as well,
so you never can tell.
We haven't met,
I'm Archie MacDonald.
Andrew Booth,
pleased to meet you.
You must be the one who's
moved into Golly's croft.
You've probably no idea how much
of a favor you've done us all.
- Really?
- Mmm.
I hope you'll be throwing
yourself into village life.
Come to the art show-
my family organizes it.
Might even enter it.
Oh, really?
Are you an artist?
No, enthusiastic amateur.
You must enter it. There's
no shortage of space.
- I'll get you the details.
- Thanks.
And if there's anything
else we can do just ask.
There is one thing. I'm looking for
someone to do some cleaning for me.
Duncan- he works
on the estate-
his aunt sometimes
does some cleaning.
- I'll get her to come and see you.
- Thanks.
Morning, Gordon.
( car horn honking )
Oh, he runs
the garage as well.
If you're looking
for the walking trail
you're in the wrong
direction.
Oh, you're joking,
aren't you?
- Back that way is it?
- It is.
I'm only trying to get
a shot of a waterfall.
I work for a postcard
company
and I'm putting together this
new Highlands Collection for them.
If you're interested in giving us a
hand, there's a drink in it for you.
I've already got a job,
thank you.
You don't work
at Glenbogle House, do you?
- What's it to you?
- I want to get some pictures there.
Ah, well, you need to speak
to the estate office for that.
Oh, right, that'll be
Irene Stuart, isn't it?
No, it isn't.
It's Archie MacDonald.
You sure? I spoke to
a guy in the village
and he gave us
Irene's name.
Oh, well,
my mistake, eh?
Found a fella looking
over the loch today.
Mm-hmm.
Said he
was a photographer.
That someone had given him
your name as a contact here.
- Why would they do that?
- You tell me.
What's he look like?
About 40,
dark gray hair,
pretty good looking
I suppose, Glasgow accent.
- You sure?
- Somebody you know?
No, no, it was probably
a mistake.
Yeah, yeah,
that's what he said.
So there's no reason why somebody
should be looking for you?
- No, of course not.
- So what's wrong?
I just haven't been feeling
too well, that's all.
Ah.
Sorry to hear that.
Well, I hope you'll
be feeling better soon.
Thanks.
You're not allowed
to interrupt.
I've just come in to see
how you were getting on.
Lex, you're in the way.
Did you choose
the wallpaper?
- It's over there.
- Let's see.
( laughing )
What's this?
Sheep.
And who'll be sleeping
in here? Little Bo Peep?
This has always been a child's
bedroom, it's tradition.
You must know
something I don't.
No, but if this is going
to be the nursery
we'll need to redecorate
sooner or later.
And I don't get
any say in this?
What, you don't
like sheep?
I don't have
a problem with sheep.
- It's you, getting all broody on me.
- I am not.
Right, so why else do you spend the
only time that you've had off in months
building
a wee nest?
Fine, don't tell
me then.
I want this to stop
being Jamie's old room.
I suppose this is one
way of doing it.
And besides, we're bound to
have children sooner or later.
Well, later
would do me.
I'm not in any rush.
I guess I always thought
that once we were married,
then maybe we'd be ready.
You might be.
Just don't go ordering
any cot just yet.
( thumping )
Hi. come in.
I'm Molly MacDonald,
I'm your neighbor.
You must be Mrs. Booth.
Oh, no, Andrew's
in the bedroom.
Maybe this isn't
a good time.
No, no, it's okay.
- Andrew!
- ( water running )
He's washing,
he got ever so dirty.
Oh! I'll come
back later.
Andrew, how do you
want me?
Are you all right
with that?
I've just got to move it
so I can paper behind it.
Do you want me
to give you a hand?
No, no. I told Lexie I'd do
all the decorating by myself.
That's not decorating,
son, that's plumbing.
Are you sure you
don't want me to help?
No thank you. I want to prove to Lexie
that I'm not
completely useless
when it comes to doing
something practical.
I think you'd
better go
and turn the water
off then.
Yes.
- How's it going?
- Great.
Are you managing
all right by yourself?
Yeah, no problem.
Yeah, little accident.
Oh, I do have
one request.
Could you paint
"Wayne" on the door?
Why?
You get
to choose the wallpaper,
so I get to choose
our baby's name.
Wayne?
And if it's a girl, then we
can cross out the W and put J.
You know, it'll be dead classy.
It'll be like Jayne with a Y.
Oh, listen, and while you're at it,
could you decorate a few more rooms?
I mean, why stop at one kid? I'm
thinking more seven, eight, or-
( thumping )
What was that?
I thought
I heard someone.
Maybe it's the ghost
of Glenbogle.
Forget it.
I wish I could, but Duncan's
aunt gets out her Ouija board
and all of a sudden we're in the
middle of the Blair Witch Project.
- Okay, okay, there's no one there.
- Thank you.
I met Andrew Booth
earlier.
I thought we should
invite him over to dinner.
I'll be busy of course,
but you could look after him.
Are you going to invite
his little friend?
Golly thought he seemed
to be on his own.
Not if you count
nubile brunettes.
Oh, Archie, she could sit beside you,
you could talk
about sheepy wallpaper.
You mean you haven't
actually met him?
No. he was
otherwise engaged.
You know, if it wasn't
for him and Golly,
then we could have
lost everything.
Fine, if you really
think it's that important,
I'll go and see
him tomorrow.
Unless you'd rather
I went tonight?
Before you start, there's
something I'd like to say
and I'd prefer to tell you
all together.
Some of you do know
this already but...
I'm having a baby.
I've thought
things through
and I think it's best all round
if I leave here.
I'd like to do that
as soon as possible.
Enjoy your meal.
This is crazy.
If you and Irene
are having a baby
we should be celebrating.
- It's not Duncan's.
- Oh. right.
Thanks for that.
What was that all about?
They're my employers.
They've got a right to know.
How can you let them know
when you don't know yourself?
I do, I've made a decision.
I know what I'm doing.
- But you can't leave.
- I can.
The baby's father, he's coming to
look for me. I'm not ready to see him.
That's running away. If you're
not interested in this guy anymore,
- why don't you just tell him?
- It's not as easy as that.
Ah, so maybe you
are still interested.
I'm sorry, I should have told you first.
but we can't go on like this, can we?
No.
So that's it.
Good night, Irene.
So what are you
celebrating?
Life being so great.
I know what you mean. I haven't worked in six months
- still.
What is it you do?
- I'm the red danger.
- Eh?
I'm the head ranger.
Oh, yeah, and where
do you do that then?
At Glenbogle.
Irene Stuart works
there, doesn't she?
How's she doing? I
haven't seen her in ages.
- You know Irene?
- Oh yes, we go way back.
So why are you
here now?
Kind of personal,
you know?
Look, I'll get you
another drink.
Hang on!
You turn up, and Irene
says she's leaving.
Oh, I get
the picture, pal!
How did I get here?
How do you think? I scraped
you up off the floor.
I'm not hungry.
Put it on the bruise.
( moaning )
- How are you feeling?
- Stupid.
Well, it wasn't exactly
your finest hour.
Anything we can do
to help?
I don't want help.
I want some people
to show some respect.
- We do that.
- Irene?
She does, too. She's just trying
to not make things worse for you.
She's going away
with that bloke.
No, no, no she's going to her
parents. That's what she told us.
I don't want her
to go anywhere.
I know, Dunc.
Why's she going?
Maybe she doesn't want to
bring up a baby on her own.
It's gonna be hard enough for
the kid not having a father.
( door latch rattles )
Archie?
( crashing )
( electricity buzzing )
- What're you doing?
- ( gasps )
The stag's head
fell off the wall.
Well, you probably banged the
bedroom door once too often.
- Why are you not in bed?
- I had to finish the undercoat.
It's the middle
of the night.
I was getting
behind schedule.
Look. Where did they come from?
I probably walked through
some plaster or something.
But they stop
dead here.
You don't think
that's odd?
No, I think it's a couple of
minutes work with the hoover.
Archie, something's
going on.
Something weird.
Yes, it's the middle
of the night,
we're standing in the hall
talking about stag's heads
and dust on the carpet.
Let's go to bed.
You know all of this
hearing things?
Maybe you're
imagining it
because you're upset.
Why would I be upset?
Because of what we were
talking about earlier.
I mean, children.
I'm sorry, but I thought it was
something that we both wanted.
Yeah, it is.
From as early
as I can remember,
I grew up with
my mother telling me
about all the things
I stopped her from doing.
I know she loved me
in her own way but...
I knew she resented me being
there almost just as much.
I want to choose
when I'm ready.
Okay.
I brought you some tea.
So... what was
the fight about?
You. it was your ex.
What did he say?
I can't remember.
Do you know something?
You're the first man ever
to get into a fight over me.
I would anytime.
- What, so you can get beaten up?
- no.
So we could be together.
I love you, Irene.
Duncan, you know
I have to go.
You don't. You don't have
to keep on running away.
You could stay
and have the baby here,
and I could be the dad.
We're great together,
it'd work.
I don't know
what to say.
Well, you don't have
to say yes just now,
but you could just think
about it.
I will.
I promise.
By the way,
I'm Molly.
Yes, Archie told me
all about you.
Pleased to meet you.
Come in, come in.
You've got quite
a lot to sort out.
Well, it'll be easier
now you're here.
Could you unpack those,
put them on that shelf?
Oh, is this
your daughter?
No, that's my wife.
She'll be joining
you here?
I shouldn't think so,
she died five years ago.
Oh, these must be
your children.
- Yes, some of them.
- How many have you got?
Four or five. Look, perhaps
it's best if I did this.
Perhaps you could make
a start on the bathroom.
I'm afraid it's in
a terrible state.
You want me to clean
the bathroom?
No, I want you
to do the whole house.
We should talk about terms. I
could offer you four pounds an hour.
I've got to dash now, I'll
pay you when I come back
and then we'll talk
about references, okay?
Good, thank you.
I'll see you later.
- From Golly.
- Thank you.
Do you want
a hand in here?
No, no. No need.
Have you got time?
Well, Lexie wants me
to set up the art show
but she's not here,
so I don't have to.
How do you fancy
a spot of redecorating?
Lexie, she doesn't
need to know.
- Okay.
- Great.
- So how are you feeling?
- great.
You know, what you
said last night
about Irene not wanting to
bring up the baby on her own?
You were right. I talked to
her, so I'm gonna be the father.
Oh, great,
so she's staying?
I've been thinking
about it all morning.
I think I'd be
a fantastic dad.
Good at all
the important things.
You know, pulling faces,
comics and-
so Irene
is definitely staying?
That's not what
she said last night.
Oh yeah, yeah, definitely
thinking about it.
I mean, why would she
not want to stay?
It's a great place
to bring up a kid.
Yeah, it's pretty good,
yeah.
How many
- how many people have you told about this?
You, Auntie Liz.
If I were you, I wouldn't
tell too many more
until it's a little bit
more definite.
Oh, it's definite.
It's gonna happen.
I'm gonna make
it happen.
Lexie: So the stag's
head falls off the wall
and then there's these ghostly
footprints that lead to nowhere.
That's not usually
a good sign.
What can I do?
I can't speak to Archie about it
'cause he thinks I'm mad already.
If it's Robert MacDonald, he'll
be telling you someone's in danger.
But who?
Why not ask
the tarot cards?
They'll tell us for sure.
I don't believe
in all that stuff.
But the day
before yesterday
you didn't believe
in ghosts.
So do you think you'll get
this finished by tomorrow?
Should do, if there
aren't any more problems.
- ( electricity crackles )
- Aah!
- You all right?
- You know, these wires are still live.
They shouldn't be.
I'll go and check.
Be careful, we've had
enough shocks for one week.
The fool.
That must be me then.
No, that's not a person
in that position.
It's a prediction. It
means expect the unexpected.
The wheel of fortune.
That means there's gonna be a
change in your life, a big change.
Everything turned
upside down.
And could this change
maybe involve having a baby?
- Not you, too?
- No, no, not at all.
What about
the other cards?
The emperor, now that means a
ruler or a figure of authority.
Like a laird?
So that must be Archie.
Well, maybe,
but you have to remember
the cards never have
just the one meaning.
But something's going
to happen to Archie.
What is it?
Dunc, can you turn
the power off?
- You seen Archie?
- No.
Is he upstairs working?
Yeah, on his own, without
any help from anyone else.
Where's Archie?
He's doing something
in the attic.
Oh, right.
Oh, not again.
- I'll go and check the fuse box.
- Thanks.
Archie?
Don't.
- What?
- It's too dangerous.
It's a simple piece
of rewiring, Lex.
Duncan:
The power's off, Arch.
No!
He said the power
was off.
It doesn't look
like it, does it?
Auntie Liz read
my tarot cards.
- You were going to die.
- Well done, Liz.
What's the point trying to
finish a nursery for your children
if you're gonna kill
yourself doing it?
All right, all right,
I'll be careful.
Anyway, I thought
we weren't having children.
Golly:
Yep, there he is.
Do you want a look?
I suppose I'd better
get it over with.
It's not him.
Does that help?
I don't know.
You know, Duncan's asked
me to stay here with him.
He says he'll
be the father.
What about you?
I just want what's best
for the baby.
You don't sound too sure.
I'd love to do that
but it just doesn't
seem right somehow.
Oh, I don't know
what's right anymore.
You know that-
you know that none of us
want to see you go.
Thanks.
If we finish the windows
and the ceiling today,
then all we have
to do tomorrow
is the rest
of the wallpaper
and the second coat
of gloss.
And the radiator
and the cleaning up.
Yeah, but that won't
take any time.
This bet
is as good as won.
Ladies, would you
like some wine?
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
- Some wine?
- No, thank you.
Did they leave all their
broomsticks by the door?
- Shh, they'll hear you.
- Ooh, they might turn me into a toad.
You're halfway
there already.
I shall be upstairs
finishing the gloss.
Archie, is there
any sherry?
One of the ladies
is asking for it.
I'll go and get it.
Duncan. Duncan,
this is Mrs. Munroe,
she's a water diviner.
Could you possibly show her
where the loo is? She's
having trouble finding it.
Good evening.
Oh, hello,
you work here as well?
- All the time.
- Great, thanks.
- Sorry.
- Clumsy.
Hi, Andrew, I'm Lexie,
Archie's wife.
- Hello, how are you?
- Hi, I see you've met Molly already.
Yes, yes, yes. I hope she'll
be doing some cleaning for me.
Molly's useless
at cleaning.
Well I did wonder, but
Archie recommended her.
Said Duncan's
aunt needed-
ah, no, Molly
is Archie's mother.
Oh, I'm sorry,
I'm so sorry.
I've made rather
a fool of myself.
Never mind, I'm sure
it's not the first time.
So I assume you won't be taking the job?
No, though from what
I've seen,
you're not short
of willing scrubbers.
I'm so glad
you two have met.
Only wish I could
say the same.
Sherry?
- How's it going?
- Another five minutes.
This probably isn't
the best time to ask,
but Duncan seems to think
that you'll be staying here.
I haven't made up
my mind yet.
Okay, okay, just let
us know when you decide.
Maybe I should stay.
If you do,
there'll be no going back.
If you change
your mind,
then you'll
break his heart.
'Caused a lot of trouble hasn't
it, for something so small?
Yes, but it'll
be worth it.
I nearly forgot. Somebody left
this for you on the doorstep.
Oh, thanks.
What were you watching?
The world's worst
wedding video.
This is my wedding.
That's Ian.
What happened?
Couldn't go
through with it.
I ran away
and ended up here.
- is he the father?
- yeah.
And he's found out
that I'm here.
This arrived today.
Does he know
about the baby?
No. No.
Well, he
doesn't have to.
Maybe you're right.
I humiliated him in front of
his family and all his friends.
I'm really not very
good news, you know.
I seem to mess up
people's lives.
Not mine.
I hope you left
some for me.
They've finished what's on their
plates and all the leftovers.
You mean my dinner's
in the coven?
They're a bunch
of happy mediums.
So how's your entry for the
art competition coming along?
Slowly, but I hope
it'll be ready in time.
Oh, do you paint?
Sculpture's more my thing.
How about you?
A little. In between
cleaning assignments.
She's brilliant. She's won the
competition for the past five years.
Let me guess,
watercolors.
Oh, and what is
the matter with watercolors?
Nothing
as long as they're not
those insipid,
wishy-washy landscapes.
My specialty.
That's better than
those sad people
who paint portraits
of their pets.
Do you often have
spiritualists to dinner?
Oh, no,
this is a one off.
Lexie thinks we've
got a ghost,
so she's invited Liz and the
weird sisters to frighten it away.
There is a ghost.
We keep it with the fairies
from the bottom of the garden
and the leprechaun we found
at the end of the rainbow.
- Don't listen to him.
- We don't have a ghost.
I think we all
have ghosts-
things that keep
us awake at night,
those private troubles that we
don't talk to anyone else about.
Yeah, but they don't walk around
with sheets over their heads
getting conjured up
by ladies of a certain age
with too much time
on their hands.
In my experience, you can never
be too sure what form they'll take.
( thunderclap )
Well, it's been
a most...
memorable evening.
I hope we meet
again soon.
That may be difficult
to avoid.
- Good night.
Archie, Archie, I want to
enter that art competition.
You said you'd
given up painting.
- I have, but I've taken it up again.
- Why?
That is one
of the most boring,
annoying men I have ever
met in my life.
Come on, we can't stand by
and watch him win that prize.
Quick!
( floor creaking )
You know,
I sometimes think
you're the only one
I could paint.
Oh, do stop licking
your thingies.
Much too
Francis Bacon for me.
Lexie: It was there again last night.
Great.
Great?
No, it's not great.
It's terrible.
I want you to get rid
of this thing
that's moving around
the house all night.
There's only
one option left.
We'll have to repeat the
seance exactly as it was before.
That will allow
the spirit
to return to rest.
Have you room
for one more?
Sure, Molly. Where would you like it?
- Over there?
- Okay.
But be careful,
it's still wet.
So, where's Andrew's
sculpture?
Oh, it's over here.
It's quite good, really.
He was telling me
how he works from life,
and he's had this model coming
round to his house every day.
Right.
So what do you think?
Shame there are no
pigeons around.
I've brought some
stuff from Auntie Liz.
Toys, games, whatever.
Now I've made a list of
things that we need to do.
Have you registered with
Dr. Brown in the village yet?
- Yes.
- Great.
Now, something else
we need to decide.
Are we gonna stay here
or move into the village?
Because if we're gonna move in there,
Auntie Liz has got a room we can have.
And have you seen the school
yet? we need to talk about that.
I think we can probably
leave it for a few days.
Yeah.
Now, something else.
Ah, yeah, are we gonna get
married? You know, for the baby?
That's not a good reason
for getting married.
No, you're right,
but we could anyway.
I'm not very good
at weddings.
Of course.
No wedding just yet.
Duncan, hold on,
we need to talk.
Not now though,
I promised I'd help Archie.
And Lexie, and-
I don't know whether
I'm coming or going.
"Useless"?
Being a bit hard on
yourself, aren't you?
"Useless" is the name
of the dog.
What's your piece
called?
"Bust of a Young Girl. "
What a lot
of bust she has.
Lexie told you the winner
has to make a speech?
Yes, she did
mention it.
That's why you're making notes, you're
that certain you're going to win.
I make no great
claims about my work
but I am absolutely certain
I'll be making a speech.
I'm not sure what is worse, your
false modesty or your smugness.
Lexie:
Andrew, are you ready?
( banging )
Ladies and gentlemen, can I have
your attention, please?
Thank you very much
for coming
to the Glenbogle
art competition.
Unfortunately,
Mrs. Mackay,
who was going to be
our judge today,
had a bit
of an accident with her easel.
So at the very
last minute
Andrew Booth very kindly withdrew
his entry from the competition
to take her place.
- Andrew.
- ( applause )
Thank you. I'd like
to congratulate
all the exhibitors
here today.
I'm enormously impressed by the
very high standard of all the works.
However, we have
to have a winner.
Now there is one picture
that stands out for me.
It's a beautiful
composition,
it's got a real
life to it.
It's "Useless"
by Molly MacDonald.
- You won.
- ( applause )
I hope you will accept
my exhibit as the prize.
Oh, thank you
so much.
Congratulations.
- No.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
there's tea and refreshments
at the back of the hall.
Well, you've changed my
mind about pet portraits.
Good,
because, in a way,
it was because of you that
I started painting again.
You stopped when
your husband died.
- How did you know that?
- A guess.
And I saw that portrait
you did of him.
The odd thing is,
since then, every time I
try to paint, I see his face.
Still, I suppose
I cheated with "Useless. "
There is quite
a strong resemblance.
So I inspired you to pick
up your brushes again?
No, with you it was more
irritation than inspiration.
Don't forget your prize.
Why don't you
finish it first?
What?
I didn't say anything.
( thunderclap )
Thanks, Molly.
I know this doesn't make any
sense but I had to give it a try.
Well, anything if you
think it'll help.
Robert MacDonald,
can you hear me?
Lexie,
speak to him.
I know you've been
trying to reach me.
What do you want?
( creaking )
( knocking )
- ( banging )
- Hey!
- What's going on?
- Found your ghost.
So it's you that's been
creeping round the house.
I'll explain everything
to Irene Stuart.
You can tell us or you
can tell the police.
Okay, look,
I'm a private detective.
I was hired
to find Irene.
It was supposed to be
a straight-forward job-
find Irene, take
a couple of pictures.
Duncan: He tried to work
me over in the pub, I know.
Detective: Yeah, well,
didn't get much, did I?
Just had to listen to you
droning on and on and on.
So I didn't feel too bad
when I borrowed your keys.
Now I've installed
covert video surveillance
in some
pretty heavy locations,
but they were a piece of
cake compared to this gaff.
It's a death-trap.
It was a test of nerve.
But still, nothing
I couldn't handle.
...dust on the carpet.
Let's go to bed.
Archie: What was your
plan for this evening?
You were going to bug
the suits of armor,
hang some listening devices
from the chandeliers?
No. My client wanted me to
deliver a letter to Irene.
With all this surveillance
you didn't notice
that we do actually have a
letterbox? I'm calling the police.
No, this is all
my fault.
I don't want anyone
else involved.
My coming here,
hiding,
it's caused enough
trouble already.
- We can't just let him get away with it.
- Please, Archie.
Make sure he doesn't
get lost on the way out.
No worries, boss.
Come on.
This is for you.
From Ian, obviously.
- Irene?
- Just let her read it first.
( knocking )
Duncan:
Irene? you there?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm here.
You okay?
What are you doing?
Nothing. can you
just give me a minute?
Okay.
I'm here if you
want me.
I know, Duncan.
( giggling )
Okay.
Open your eyes.
Oh, Archie.
What happened
to all the sheep?
Well, it's like you
were saying last night.
We spend far too much time thinking
about the past and the future
and what we should be doing
is enjoying what we've got.
So I've made this room
a kind of blank canvas.
We decide together what
we want to do with it.
And what about carrying
on the family line?
- It doesn't really matter.
- Of course it does.
What would I know?
I don't have a family tree.
I don't even have
a family pot plant.
You need to tell me what you
want, I can't read your mind, Arch.
I want you. And I want you to be happy.
Oh, and by the way,
I won the bet.
Ah-ha!
That is not finished.
- It was finished.
- Thanks to Golly and Duncan.
Okay, so I cheated
and it's a mess
but it's still a kind
of moral victory.
Okay, then I can take you out
for a kind of moral dinner.
I wouldn't mind
staying in.
You know what
we could do?
What?
We could start thinking about
something to put in here.
What do you
have in mind?
Curtains.
Curtains?
Is that you away then?
Yeah.
Can you tell Archie
and Lexie for me?
I'll call them,
but I really hate goodbyes.
Yeah, I gathered that.
What about Duncan?
I'm sorry, I just
can't face him again.
I wish things hadn't
worked out like this.
Me too.
Will you tell him,
after I've gone?
Sure.
Thanks.
- I'm coming with you.
- No.
Yes. We can go
and talk to Ian
and then we can
come back home.
- This isn't my home.
- You're running away again.
No, for me, staying
here is running away.
Why?
Why are you doing this?
Because every time I look at my
baby's face I'm going to see Ian.
I can't run away
from that anymore.
That's why it can't
work for you and me.
Irene, I love you.
Duncan, this isn't
about us anymore.
This is about my child.
And I know you
want to take on
the responsibility
of being the father,
but you're not,
Ian is.
And he's the one with the
important job, and the big money.
Don't-
don't do this.
You're so kind.
I'm fed up
with being kind,
because kind means
being the nice guy
who smiles and waves goodbye and I'm not doing that
- not anymore.
I'd have given anything
to spend my life
with you.
And however you
look at it,
you just don't feel
the same.
You never did.
This isn't what I want.
Oh, Duncan, please,
can't we be friends?
No. I've got friends.
Come on, son.
Come on.
I'll drive.
You come here to talk
to father, don't you?
Silly, isn't it?
But I always feel a little
closer to him when I'm out here.
But he's gone.
And we miss him.
Yes.
Knowing father, he's on some
big celestial golf course,
stuck in a bunker
probably.
It would be nice
to think so,
but I really don't believe
in that sort of thing.
You go in.
Useless, you silly dog.
( barking )
( golf club swooshes )
( whining )
( whimpers )
( theme music playing )
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0