Golly:
He looks in a bad way.
Of all the beasts
in the world,
it had to be you,
Big Eric.
Duncan: He's well off the beaten track.
Where's he come from?
Duncan, bullets.
- Bullets?
- Bullets.
- You've got them.
- If I had them would I be asking you for them?
Do you want me
to get some?
No, son, I'm going to sit here and
wait till the beast comes to me.
Then I'm going to put him out of
his misery with a few harsh words.
- ( laughs )
- Go.
( theme music playing )
What on earth
are you playing at?
No, I think
it's all right.
Lexie: Okay, back,
back. Back, back, back.
Back, back,
keep coming, keep coming.
Oh, stop, stop!
Stop there.
Have you ever
reversed in before?
One very big haggis.
Do you know how much this
fridge unit's costing us?
And he nearly
slams it into the wall.
- What are you grinning at?
- You...
and how deep down I know you're
enjoying every minute of this.
Could you plug this into
the kitchen for me please?
Be careful
with the haggis.
I quite like you when you're
in your organizing mode.
- Who's that?
- Don't know.
Are you lost?
Can we help at all?
I'm looking
for this man.
Lexie:
It's Golly, isn't it?
( chuckles )
Golly's up in the hills somewhere. it
might be some time before he's back.
Where?
They headed to Raglan Glen,
up there.
Thanks.
It'd be nice to know
who's asking for him.
Paul... Bowman.
And how do you
know Golly?
I don't.
- Archie, I need to get a number off you for the band.
- Hang on a minute.
Morning, Archie.
Morning.
- Morning, Archie.
- Morning.
I've been helping you organize
the Ghillie's Ball for years now.
Ah, but this year
you're the host.
And with Irene gone-
it's just a traditional ball.
So it's going to be
the same as it was last year and the year
before that, and the year before that.
Don't worry, it'll be fine.
Oops.
Right here...
would be good.
And then the waitresses can serve
drinks as the guests come in.
Would you like any
help in the kitchen?
Things aren't
that bad just yet.
Don't worry, everything's
in hand. Honestly.
- Morning.
I thought the boarders of the
old jardin might need a haircut.
That's very kind of you
to offer, Kilwillie.
Oh, no.
I didn't mean-
I meant you could
borrow it, that's all.
Really no need. Andrew lent
me his just the other day.
- Oh.
- Trust it did the job.
It certainly did.
Now you're here.
Kilwillie, do you want
to stay and be a helper, too?
Could you define helper
a bit more clearly?
Well, to begin with,
all those chairs have got
to be moved round the tables.
- And then-
- thing is I've got a very-
oh, well,
you know me.
Always ready to lend
a helping hand.
( chuckles )
I'm sorry, Molly-
who the dickens
is he?
Andrew,
as I said.
Andrew.
Right!
You should leave a few
of these unshelled.
It really sets
the plates off.
( clears throat ) Isn't there something
else you could be getting on with?
No, no, no. I've got the
whole day clear for you.
I even told Golly and Duncan I
couldn't go stalking with them.
( car approaching )
Huh, I wonder
what he's doing back.
Give me
one minute, okay?
Take your time.
I thought you were
up on the hill.
No, boss,
I'm here.
I was just wondering why.
Saw Big Eric...
injured pretty bad.
Are you sure it was him?
Yeah, I think one
of the younger stags
gave him more than he
bargained for in the rut.
Golly thinks we should
put him out of his misery.
So why didn't you
just take the shot?
Um...
Dunc, what are you
looking for?
Ammunition.
Boys, I've got
a job for somebody.
Both:
Certainly.
There's a box in the attic
with all the table decorations.
Both:
I'll go.
On second thought,
it's really a two-man job.
What sort of box?
I'm not sure, really.
A small box I think.
But it's very heavy.
We'll find it
I'm sure, dear Molly.
It could be
under some things.
We'll be back
in a trice.
So it's a small box
under some things.
Yes.
- Molly.
- Yes?
I just wanted
to be absolutely sure-
everything in the garden's
rosy, isn't it?
Well, apart from
the rosa mundi having a touch-
no, no,
I meant between us-
after the proposal.
- Of course.
- Because we did agree that we wouldn't
let it stop us being chums,
didn't we?
As far as I'm concerned,
Kilwillie,
nothing will ever change.
Where is the attic?
Top of the house,
dear boy. it usually is.
Okay.
Good.
Okay, give me your hand
and I'll pull you up.
I'm fine.
I have scaled Ben Nevis.
I think I can
manage this.
I was in the Himalayas about five
years back. You ever climbed there?
Well, not recently.
Well, pull, man, pull!
So he definitely
has to be culled?
From what Duncan says.
It's silly, but it feels
like losing one of the family.
I better get going.
The sooner I'm gone,
the sooner I'll
be back to help.
She so wants this evening
to be a success,
but honestly, Archie,
I could have never coped
on my own like she's
trying to do.
Just do what you can. She'll
thank you for it in the end.
Molly, did Archie leave
the number for the band?
Was he supposed to?
( sighs )
Fine.
Do you know,
I think our search would be
more profitable at the other end.
- Perhaps we should admit defeat.
- Nonsense!
If you knew Molly
half as well as I do,
you'd know that defeat is
not a word in her vocabulary.
You're rather close
to Molly, aren't you?
Perhaps none so close,
though I say it myself.
And she never
mentioned me to you?
No.
Good grief!
Oh, I'm sorry. I was just-
I'm sorry.
Yes, well,
perhaps we should concentrate
on the matter in hand.
Not that one.
So now what?
Simply have to open it
from this side.
- Help! Help!
- Help!
There is a track, you know,
if you want to stay on it.
I'll bring him up
once we've got Big Eric.
Do you think
we're a bit stuck?
I think there's
a distinct possibility.
- Thanks.
- 20 cases- 10 red, 10 white.
And I don't actually
want it here, though.
That's fine.
Just put it-
thanks.
I need this wine lifted
to the marquis...
Molly?
- ( explosion )
- ( Molly screams )
( Molly groans )
Woman:
Anybody home?
Oh, Molly,
I know we're early,
but I-
I'm afraid
the haggis is off.
Archie:
How bad is he?
He'll not make it through
another winter, that's for sure.
And we need
to do it today.
I'll not let
the beast suffer.
I'd like to be the one
who takes the shot.
Of course.
Right,
let's get started.
Archie:
Oh, before I forget,
you don't know
a Paul Bowman, do you?
Never heard of him.
Well, I met him earlier.
And we just passed him
in the Land Rover.
Where is
the Land Rover?
It's a wee bit stuck.
Duncan,
if you were a stag,
we'd have you
culled by now.
- Bowman, you said?
- Yeah.
No, never heard of him.
Have I got it all?
Yeah, yeah.
Look as good as new.
( laughing )
You know, I always remember
the first time we came here.
Zara and Archie
racing through here,
her in her best frock
and him in his short trousers.
- Mother-
- what was it you used to play?
"Kiss, chase. "
Oh, aye,
did he ever catch you?
He was the one
running away.
( chuckling )
There we are.
My late husband
Gerald and I,
we always hoped that Zara
and Archie might have...
never mind.
How is your husband?
Still running. But he lets
me catch him sometimes.
( chuckles )
Zara, bless her,
has given up chasing.
Haven't you, poppet?
Sorry about
the early arrival.
It's fine.
Isn't it, Lexie?
Absolutely.
Zara may have given up
on the manhunt,
but I thought if I was finally
going to find a new husband,
I should get along early
to avoid disappointment.
We're not in your way,
are we?
No, not at all.
I know from all the functions
I've arranged
it's when you think
it's all in hand,
that's when the little problems
seem to pop up out of nowhere.
Don't they just.
( sighs )
We do so always love
coming to visit Glenbogle.
And we love having you. You
mustn't leave it so long next time.
I can see Archie's done well
for himself with you, Lexie.
Perhaps you should have
a word with Zara later.
Pass on your
secret for success.
Well, then it wouldn't
be a secret anymore.
And now, if you'll excuse me
I've got flowers to sort out,
wine to move
and a kitchen to de-haggis.
( sighs ) One can
never have too much time
to get ready
for these occasions.
Clearly not.
And as you can see, Molly,
Zara is not blessed
with Lexie's
natural beauty.
Look, if a girl is going
to catch the right chap
she's got to have
the right face to do it with.
And if you haven't
got one of your own,
paint it on.
Well, I think that Zara has
a very nice natural look.
- Help!
Can I hear
someone calling?
Just the wind.
( chuckles )
Help! Help!
Maybe bouncing around
isn't such a good idea.
But somebody's bound to cross
the landing sooner or later
then they'll hear.
Or maybe they'll see you when you
come crashing through the ceiling.
- What exactly are you implying?
- Nothing.
I may be a little stout,
but it think it's a bit off
to point it out.
That's not
what I meant.
Nanny always said I was built
for carrying responsibilities.
Nanny?
Ow.
And just for the record,
I am only
a few pounds heavier
than the official
national average
for my height
and build.
I just happen to be
three inches shorter.
We have guests
and some assistance
would be appreciated.
Ah, that box there
I wanted.
Oh, and I thought-
wait! Ahh!
I do hope that isn't
too painful.
Worse things
in the world
than being guardian
to all this, wouldn't you say?
I can't believe I ever thought
I could live away from here.
Golly:
Sometimes in our lives
we're after
different things, son.
Archie: Remind me never to take
all this for granted, Golly.
Caring, gentle,
understanding-
- You could have been a nurse, couldn't you?
- Me? I doubt it.
You have all the qualities.
( gasps )
Sorry.
Didn't feel a thing.
Molly,
I've got
a jolly large splinter.
- Where?
- Just there. It's huge.
Oh, Kilwillie,
don't be such a baby.
- It broken?
- Just bruised.
Oh, well,
never mind.
Would you like me to take
a look at your splinter?
Okay, son,
a good clean shot
to the heart.
- ( grunts )
- ( gunshot fires )
What are you doing?
I had the perfect shot.
I'm told you're
looking for me.
If you're the man
in this photo, then yes.
- Megan.
- My mother.
- Duncan.
- Aye?
Go and see if you
can drive Big Eric
up to the point
in the hill there.
In 10 minutes we'll
cross the trees
and see if we can
get a clear shot.
You'll be upwind
of him there.
Just do it, Duncan.
I knew there was a chance you
would come up here someday,
but not this way.
I found this
in mom's things.
Three weeks ago, I came home
from leave to find her dying...
alone in her flat.
I'm truly sorry
to hear that.
It's from
your solicitors.
Read it.
"We acknowledge your desire
to keep independence
and sole responsibility
for the child.
The Glenbogle estate, representing
the interests of the father. "
He's your son.
My mother didn't want
anything from you back then
and neither do I.
- It's not that simple.
- All I came here for was to see my father.
See the man who walked into my
mother's life 30-odd years ago
and left her with a son.
- I said it's not that simple.
- Then tell me you're not my father.
Tell me that and I'll
leave here and not come back.
We've got a stag
to shoot.
Golly, you have
to deal with this.
There's a storm
away in the mountains.
I want us finished
and off the hill
before it decides
to blow.
Thank you.
There you go.
- Here we are.
- Ohh...
- Help yourselves.
- Oh, that's splendid.
An army marches
on its stomach.
You shouldn't have
gone to all this trouble.
You have enough
to do as it is.
I feel dreadful
about the haggis.
- The best thing you can do is take care of our guests.
- Roger.
Making the haggis is
the last thing I needed.
Don't know when I'm going to
have time to decorate this hall.
I knew I was right
to get here early.
Please, tell me
he's single.
- I'm not sure.
- You must know.
Widowed, I think.
Now he would fit rather
nicely alongside my fireside.
I shouldn't set your cap
at just the one chap
until you've seen all
the available candidates.
Yes, I'm sure
you're right, dear.
You seem to have
forgotten my lemon.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'll forgive you...
just this once.
The last ball we gave
had a Damien Hirst theme.
It looked
absolutely fabulous.
Oh.
I'm sure it did.
You've got quite a gift
for interior design.
Oh, thank you, Molly.
I meant Zara.
One doesn't like
to blow one's own trumpet.
If I didn't blow mine
nobody else would.
( Kilwillie
and Molly chuckle )
Would you come
into the hall for a moment?
I've had an idea.
Excuse us, Kilwillie.
I know things have
to be dealt with,
but not up here.
Not like this.
Why are you so scared
of admitting the truth?
I'm not planning on
claiming the family jewels.
Talk to me.
Now I got the answer
I came for.
- Golly, you can't just let him go like this.
- Get out of my way!
- No.
- I've never had a father and I don't want one.
- Not one like him, that's for sure.
- I'm not your father, Paul.
Hector MacDonald was.
You and Archie
are brothers.
( Kilwillie wheezes )
Kilwillie, could you go down
to the cellar for me please
and see if you can find
something special for the toasts?
Of course.
Andrew:
Warm work, that.
If you get too hot, you could
always take your shirt off.
I think perhaps
he needs a hand.
These bottles
can be heavy.
( laughs )
You do realize that the
hunting season finishes today.
Oh, don't worry, dear.
I plan to have my stag stuffed
and mounted by midnight.
As far as Hector
was concerned,
Molly had left him.
Poor woman felt
trapped up here.
No friends, nothing.
Different world.
She felt she had to get away-
she went back to London.
Hector had no idea if she
would ever be coming back.
Oh, so he ran off
to my mother?
Look...
I'm not trying to excuse
Hector's actions.
No more did he.
He lived with the shame
of it all his days,
but the man was shattered.
Molly had left.
He disappeared.
I tracked him down
to Edinburgh.
That's where that photo
was taken.
Anyway,
by the time
he got back here
it was all over between them.
And then... Megan discovered
she was pregnant.
He wanted to do
the right thing by her,
wanted to make sure that
she wanted for nothing, but...
she found out
that he was married,
she- she didn't want
to know him anymore.
I was sworn to secrecy.
The family solicitors
drew a line under the matter
with that letter.
I don't believe this.
Hector made me swear,
Archie.
My father owned
all this?
So everything I've ever known
is a lie, is it?
You are still
Hector's son.
And so is he.
If I hadn't come here,
no one would
ever have told me.
That was the way
your mother wanted it to be.
( panting )
What are you doing?
I got him around to exactly
where you wanted him.
You had the perfect shot.
Why didn't you take it?
I came up here
to shoot Big Eric
and that's
what I'm going to do.
Archie.
Does somebody want
to tell me what's going on?
Not now, Duncan.
I can't believe the girls from
the pub aren't even here yet.
( hammering )
- Lexie: What have you done?
- Oriental chic.
This is my hallway.
Molly asked
if I could help.
Molly: You said you didn't
have time to decorate the hall.
- so I asked Zara to do it.
- This is very now, I can assure you.
When the guests arrive, this
will be the first thing they see?
Mm-hmm.
This isn't Glenbogle.
This isn't me.
I suppose we could
lose some of the candles.
Lexie.
We should try and drive him
across the glen.
Keep ourselves
well below the skyline.
Nah, he's heading
for cover.
He'll not leave
the herd.
He's hurt.
He wants cover.
I think Duncan's right.
( bellows )
If he makes it through those
trees, you'll not get a shot.
Nah.
We've been keeping him
moving all day. He's tired.
We should let him
make it to the trees.
Then we can take
the shot on our terms.
Okay.
Let's do it.
Can I talk to you?
We're losing light.
( sighs )
Oh dear, no.
Far too demure.
- Oh.
- ( laughs )
Oh, he's obviously seen
a thing or two.
But I like
worldly men.
I'm surprised you've not
taken a shine to him, Molly.
- Me?
- Now that you're a free agent
it must have
crossed your mind.
Go on, admit it.
No.
Well, I mean-
just don't go trying
anything this evening.
I've got first dibs.
Ah-ha,
the black.
The black, the black,
the black...
( growls )
No, the booking
was for today,
not for next week.
But, Dougal,
I've got over 100 guests.
I need those girls.
A wedding.
Oh, right. Well, you're
sorry and I'm stuffed.
Oh, Lexie.
( sighs )
I remember my first stag.
I was 13.
I didn't want
to come.
There was no way my father
was going to have a son
who couldn't stalk.
I was never supposed to be
the oldest son.
This isn't my place.
Jamie should be here,
not me.
Someone has unplugged it.
I can't risk serving food to guests
that's been lying around unchilled.
Where was it plugged in?
In the kitchen.
- By the food mixer?
- Yes.
W- w-w-well, I'm sure
it will be all right.
Okay,
there you go.
Just don't come blaming me
when the salmonella kicks in.
No chance of a snack,
is there, to keep us going?
( tray thuds )
( bellows )
Okay, just breathe in,
hold it,
and let it out slowly
when you squeeze the trigger.
Archie.
Okay, son,
take the shot.
( gunshot )
Clean shot.
Perfect shot.
I'll go and get
the pony from the shelter.
We may share a father...
but I only have
one brother...
and he died
16 years ago.
Lexie?
Okay, okay,
you were right.
I took on too much.
Lexie, darling,
this evening isn't
about the food we eat
or the decor.
It's about you and Glenbogle
and saying thank you
to everybody
for a wonderful season.
I just wanted it to be
as good as it always is.
Well, things don't always
have to be the same
to be good, do they?
No, I suppose not.
Well...
maybe it's time
for something a bit more...
Lexie MacDonald.
Shall I gather
the troops?
This is going to be one Ghillie's
Ball Glenbogle will not forget.
Okay, Kilwillie, could you clear
the front of the house please
of any vehicles
that are there?
Andrew, could you set up some
car parking spaces in the field?
- Mm-hmm.
- I- I could help him.
But hadn't he better
go with someone
who knows the layout
of the estate?
Okay, yup, well,
Marilyn and Zara, could you
both come with me please?
Keeping an eye
on me?
Duncan: Eric ended up in the
woods after all, eh, Golly?
Golly:
Yeah, well done, son.
You were right
and I was wrong.
But if you tell anyone,
I'll just deny it.
Duncan: ( laughs ) So does this mean
you're going to tell me
what's going on?
Golly: You'll find out soon enough.
I don't want my mother
knowing about this.
I don't think it's something you're
going to be able to keep from her.
You kept it
from me for long enough.
And that was wrong.
Look how hurt
you've been by it.
It was wrong,
Archie.
I want him
away from Glenbogle.
It's late, son.
He's nowhere to go.
The least you can do
is sleep on it.
( siren wails )
Listen, Archie,
let the women
have their night.
No need to rush in
and ruin it.
- What do you think?
- You are so clever.
I should have
thought of it.
I want your word that you
won't cause any trouble.
Lexie: Hi!
( laughs ) While you've
been out having fun all day,
we have been
working very hard.
- Yeah, Paul.
- Lexie.
I see you got Golly.
So are you going to come
and join us, Paul?
- I don't think so.
- No arguments.
I'd better be off.
Lexie!
Archie, tell Paul he's got
to come and join in the fun.
You know it's compulsory
at a Lexie MacDonald event.
And I have my ghillie
for the ball.
You know, this day just keeps
getting better and better.
So that's your wife?
Listen, I just wanted to find my father.
But I'm too late.
- So- - you won't find
a room in the village.
You can stay here.
Thanks.
Just for tonight.
( bell rings )
Merilyn:
Andrew, save me a place.
Molly!
Oh, there's one.
- Sorry.
- Lovely.
I'm in pole position!
I'll take that one.
That one here. thank you.
This is the highlands, not
some English seaside resort.
Oh, Zara,
come and have some fun.
- Come on!
- ( bell rings )
- ( ripping )
- Ahh!
Oh no,
it's ruined.
Here comes Kilwillie!
( laughing )
Where's the- aah!
( ride siren blaring )
- Ahh!
- ( laughing )
( door opens, closes )
This way.
Thank you.
Come on, Kilwillie. I need
some help with the catering.
Catering?
17 fried rice,
18 beef and oyster sauce,
19 sweet and sour prawn.
Eh, 20 sweet and sour prawn.
20 sweet and sour prawn
and 16 chicken chop suey.
- is there anything else?
- Prawn crackers?
You didn't order any.
Well, I though we might get
some complimentary ones.
( speaking Chinese )
Compliments
of the Lucky Star.
( cash register beeping )
( bagpipes playing )
Ladies and gentlemen,
dinner is served.
( cheering )
And of course, this would not
be the Glenbogle Ghillie's Ball
without...
the monster haggis.
Okay everyone,
tuck in.
Help yourselves.
I suppose now you're
going to tell me
that you don't like
chicken chow mein and haggis?
It's fine, though given
the choice, I'd prefer Japanese.
I want you just to have
a good time, Zara.
That's what I want
for everyone.
Seems I've fulfilled
mother's prophecy
and ended up on
the shelf yet again.
Why don't you come
and meet some people?
Like this?
Oh dear.
We'll try something new.
Come with me.
So Archie was a bit
of a heartbreaker
at age eight,
was he?
I rather like the way
you do things at Glenbogle.
Lexie's done
a wonderful job.
In fact,
I've got to like
a lot of things
since I've been here.
Shall we?
( bagpipes finish )
( applause )
One of those, perhaps?
Prawn balls?
No.
Oh, would you
like that?
You look great.
Now, let's get
you a drink.
Here we are.
Can't we have
some music for dancing?
I forgot the band.
Well, I'm a bit rusty but I could
give you a quick burst on these.
Why not? You can do everything else.
If I dare say so,
I have had a bit
of an idea on that front.
( pop music playing )
I love it.
Doesn't she
look beautiful?
Shall we dance?
( laughs )
Ooh!
Andrew: It's great.
I'm really having fun!
Ooh!
( laughs )
Hey, hey.
I used to love this!
It's fine, it's fine.
No, no, don't worry.
Oh my. oh.
( tango music plays )
You look a bit rusty,
old boy.
Bravo!
- Well done.
- You were wonderful.
- Wasn't he good?
- Wonderful.
Kilwillie: The storm never
came to anything then.
Well, that's
the thing about storms.
You know they're
out there...
but you never know when
they're gonna let rip.
Well, I hope it holds off
until I get home.
You have a rather
splendid woman in Lexie.
Do you know that?
I do.
Glenbogle's lucky to have
the pair of you.
( engine starts )
( traditional Scottish
dance music starts )
Come on, Andrew.
One squashed toe,
you're mine
for the entire evening.
Isn't this fun?
Even your father
would have enjoyed it.
A dance, Mr. Laird?
It's a very easy dance.
- Archie, who is he?
- Molly: Keep spinning! Keep spinning!
Molly:
That's it.
( theme music playing )
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0