( wolves howling )
( growling )
Archie: Don't forget, Dunc,
these are wild animals.
- they're unpredictable.
- Duncan: I always think how harmless they look.
Reminds me of that dog my granny
had, great brute of a thing.
Golly: He's a west highland terrier.
Yeah, but I was only a wee
boy so it seemed huge to me.
Harmless or not, these wolves
keep bringing the visitors in.
Golly, you know you should take
a leaf out of Duncan's book.
Would that be his Beano Annual
or his computer game magazine?
- You can't, I haven't even read them yet.
- Show a bit of enthusiasm.
If it wasn't for Dunc we wouldn't
have this party of naturalists coming.
This could be the start
of big things. Well done.
- I'll leave you to it, yeah?
- Okay, boss.
You see that? I saw an
opportunity and I grabbed it.
No, son, the phone rang
and you picked it up.
I've left my gloves
inside. You take the barrow.
I'll finish up here then we'll
both get something to eat.
Okey-dokey.
Oh, and Golly,
you've got to make hay
while the iron's hot.
( theme music playing )
Another spoonful of beans?
No, that's plenty
for me, thanks.
- Duncan?
- No, I'm fine, thanks.
As long as you're
keeping your strength up.
Lexie:
Lunch plates.
Just toss them
in the sink.
Did you hear about the
naturalists I booked in, Lex?
Archie says it could
be the start of big things.
I know, it's amazing.
You'll be tying
your own shoelaces next.
Irene:
Were the fishcakes okay?
Very nice, best I've
ever tasted in fact.
- You're just saying that.
- Absolutely not.
It's a rare gift you have with
the seasoning there. hasn't she?
Um... yeah?
I didn't really notice.
How could you
not notice?
I just whacked
the ketchup on and ate them.
- No change there then, eh?
- Go on, he's a growing lad.
- Anyway, it's time we weren't here.
- Another five minutes?
You can have
another five minutes.
I've got the feed
figures to do.
Oh, Irene, don't let him
take advantage of you.
Arch, did he find you?
- Who?
- Kilwillie.
- When?
- So you haven't seen him?
Not today, no.
( laughing )
I knew it.
- Lex, what are you talking about?
- Well, he's here again.
- Kilwillie?
- Yes.
- So?
- So, he made out
that he was coming to see
you, but obviously he wasn't.
So he was here to see someone else
and no prizes for guessing who.
Why don't I go back outside and
we can start this all over again?
He's after Molly.
- After her for what?
- well, for anything he can get.
Oh!
He fancies her, Arch.
Ah!
- You almost had me there.
- I'm being serious.
Yeah, of course you are.
( horn honking )
Welcome to Glenbogle.
- Lovely spot. Secluded, too.
- It'll suit then?
It's perfect.
Sorry, you're...?
Duncan,
campsite manager.
- I'm Ian.
- Hello.
- Gail.
- And this is our daughter Heather.
- hello.
Ian: It's good of you to have us.
There's lots
of places won't.
- why's that then?
- Think we're a bit strange.
- I don't understand.
- No, neither do we.
So, are you in tune with
nature yourself, Duncan?
Every chance I can get.
Ian: Which must be quite
often I would imagine,
living and working
in a place like this.
Well, you know, it's one of
the reasons I love the job.
You get so much time...
outside.
And work uninhibited.
I'd say I was pretty
much my own boss, yes.
Heather: I'd say you're
all as sad as each other.
Because I like what I do?
Because you have
to boast about it.
Ian:
Take no notice,
this is just because we wouldn't
let her stay at home by herself.
Listen,
once we're settled,
come back and have
a drink and a proper chat.
- Are you sure?
- I insist.
It's always nice to meet
a fellow enthusiast.
And if you'd like
to see the wildlife center,
- then I'm your man.
- Ian: thanks for the offer,
but I think it's best
if we stay out of the way.
It's no trouble,
honestly.
Gail: Now that's what
I call open-minded.
Aye, I wish we'd found
this place years ago.
Yes, this call came right out
of the blue from Stinky Perkins.
He's a very old chum of
mine, disgustingly rich.
He's bought himself
a villa
just outside a little
greek fishing village.
Anyway, here's the nub,
I can have the run of the
place whenever the fancy takes.
Lucky old you.
Nice bit of Mediterranean sunshine
will do you a power of good.
( stuttering )
I was just wondering
if you might like
a little break?
That's very
thoughtful of you
but he's your friend,
you must go.
Well...
I was thinking
both of us together.
Well not
together-together.
Everything
above board, naturally.
So, does the idea
appeal- at all?
Well, it would
be lovely.
Marvelous! Let's synchronize
diaries then, shall we?
The thing is, though, I can't
leave Glenbogle at the moment.
There is so much
going on.
Perhaps another time.
I see.
Quite understand.
I'll tell stinky
"no" then.
You could still go though.
No. it wouldn't
be the same.
Besides, if it's
getting a bit hectic,
you never know when
you might need me.
What?
I think you were right.
I usually am. About
anything specifically?
Kilwillie making
advances to my mother.
He's only gone and asked
her on some exotic holiday.
Well that might be
what she needs.
It's exactly what
she doesn't need.
Anyway, she said no.
- So what's the problem?
- I'm not having it.
Neither's Kilwillie,
by the sounds of things.
I'm going to have
a word with him.
My mother
is out of bounds.
Archie, she's got a lot
of years ahead of her.
You can't expect her
to spend them alone.
Hi, it's me, Duncan.
Hello there.
Come on in.
I'll come back
when you're dressed.
- How do you mean?
- You haven't got your shirt on.
I haven't got anything
on, have we, darling?
Just my flip-flops.
Have you lost
your luggage?
No.
You've been for a swim?
This is how we unwind.
But you knew that.
You are the naturalists?
Close.
We're naturists.
You mean you...
walk around...
in the bufty?
You can't.
Oh, I think you'll
find we can.
- Fancy a beer?
- Ah!
( whimpering )
Kilwillie?
- You wanted to see me?
- Did I?
According to Lexie.
- Oh, yes.
- So, what is it?
( stammering )
It was just the-
the Landowners Association
annual dinner.
I was just wondering how
many tickets you might need.
- That's months away.
- Best to get in early.
Which is why there were only
seven of us at the last one.
I'll put you down as a
"don't know" then, shall I?
It's the most natural
thing in the world, Duncan,
letting your body
soak up the sun's rays.
I'm not sure
that it's for me.
I can promise you,
there's nothing like it.
I think you'll be seeing
more of us up here
once I start spreading
the word.
- What word?
- Suitability.
I'm president
of the Highland
and Western Isles
Naturist Society
so I always like to check
out a new site first.
But Glenbogle gets
the big thumbs up so far.
You got the sun cream
out there, dad?
Aye, come and join us.
Is that your daughter?
Very careful not to
get burnt. Here she is.
But you've got
your clothes on.
Sorry to
disappoint you.
No, no, I just mean
what with the sun cream.
My arms. Not feeling the
urge to get them off then?
I was just explaining about
the benefits of the lifestyle.
That's not what
I'd call them.
I thought you were one
of the great undressed anyway.
Misunderstanding.
What, you mean you're
normal? Thank goodness.
Hello!
Hello yourself.
Hi, Lexie.
There's no need
to look so disappointed.
I was not.
So, was it Irene
you were after?
Maybe.
You know if I didn't
know any better,
I would say you
were soft on her.
I am no such thing.
- If you say so.
- yes, I do.
You know she's
a fine-looking woman.
That is as may be, Lexie,
but that doesn't mean...
I know.
I just think you'd be good
for each other, that's all.
But, it's none
of my business.
It's inspiring,
isn't it?
Mmm, it is.
I've found the answer
to many a problem
just looking out
over the water.
Is that what
you're doing now?
Seeking solutions?
More guidance, really.
Not for myself, mind,
but... a friend.
Can I help?
Maybe.
He- this friend
of mine,
he's reached
a certain age.
Haven't we all?
There's nothing we can
do about it, I'm afraid.
No, but the thing is
that there's a-
there's a woman
that he's become fond of.
Has he told her?
No, no.
Not in so many words.
Just bought her flowers,
that sort of thing.
This chap,
would I know him?
It's not beyond the
realms of possibility, no.
Anyway,
he's asking himself
is he too old to be
considering
a relationship.
And how would you
advise him?
Well...
I think I'll be
telling him-
I think I'll be telling him
that it is never too late.
What would you say?
I agree.
Absolutely.
Good.
Excellent.
( chatting )
- ( growls )
- ( Lexie screams )
( growls )
Hey!
Found yourself
a new friend then?
- Eh?
- A young girl.
- Oh, Heather.
- first name terms already.
I was just being chatty.
Oh, really?
She's from
the campsite.
- Perhaps you might like
to introduce me. - Oh- that-
perhaps that wouldn't be
a great idea, probably.
You wouldn't have anything
to hide, would you?
How are the naturalists?
Settled in all right?
He made sure they got
a very warm welcome.
Well, one of them
anyway.
Actually, there are a couple
of things we should talk about.
They haven't got
any complaints have they?
Them? No, everything's perfect for them.
That's all that matters,
isn't it?
Exactly.
Apart from-
whatever you're doing,
stop it.
This is more important.
Come on.
Archie: That's impossible,
one can't have got out.
- I only knew what I saw.
- Maybe it was a dog.
Maybe, but it must
have been a pretty big one.
You've been in there today so the
enclosure must have been opened.
- Yeah.
- Well, did you lock it properly?
Yeah, course I did. Well,
actually, I left Golly and Duncan-
Golly,
you know how some people
get on with certain people
better than
other people?
Would these be
any people in particular?
Well, Irene,
for example.
- Irene and-
- and?
- And-
- another person?
- Exactly.
- Why don't you just come out and say it?
Well, yes,
but the thing is-
you think I should
say something to her?
- Yes.
- Yes?
- No. no.
- No?
- Archie: I thought I could trust you two!
- What do you mean?
It looks like one of the wolves
has escaped from the enclosure.
- That'll be my fault.
- I left both of you to take care of it.
Golly: There's no need
to go blaming Duncan.
I had to go back inside.
I'm sorry.
It's a bit late for that. We could
have a situation on our hands.
Are you sure one
of them is missing?
Does anybody know why
these are all over the lawn?
I think that answers
your question.
Look, there's no good
in going after it now,
we'll lose the light in half
an hour. We'd have no chance.
First light then. Let's
hope it's not too late.
- But that means it'll be out there all night.
- Just make sure you're not.
We'll evacuate the naturalists
camp. I'll have a word with them.
What are you going
to say to them?
I don't know-
poachers.
We've got a band of
poachers, armed and dangerous.
No, I'll do it.
After all,
like you said,
they're my
responsibility.
Dunc, we'll get
this wolf back.
It'll be too late by then.
Everything's going wrong.
And they were
my big chance.
- Who?
- The naturalists.
Only they're not naturalists
because, well, they're something else.
- And on top of that I haven't told Golly yet.
- Told Golly what?
If I tell you and you
tell somebody else,
I'd have to kill you.
Oh, so it's really
serious then, eh?
I'm seeing someone.
Oh, that's good,
Duncan.
- It's Irene.
- Oh, not so good.
You do know how
Golly feels about her?
Oh, and I've been
encouraging him.
- What am I gonna do?
- You need to talk to him.
- I've tried.
- Try a bit harder.
Aye, but I've got to see
these naturalists first.
Ian:
Hello there.
Can I help you?
( bird crying )
Duncan, what are you
doing behind here?
I just heard a noise,
checking it out.
Not hiding then?
- Why would I be?
- so I don't catch you
sneaking down to see
your little girlfriend.
She's not my-
you are.
And you wouldn't keep
anything from me, would you?
Like what?
Like the fact that they're
prancing around without clothes on.
I've just been
down there.
You don't suppose we can
just keep that between us?
You think no one
else is going to notice?
No one else is gonna know. I'm on my way
down there to tell
them to leave now.
Why?
Because there's a gang
of poachers on the loose!
- You're kidding.
- Yeah, I am. It's a wolf really.
- Evening, Duncan.
- Hi, Ian.
Do you not recognize
me with my clothes on?
It's a bit chilly to be wandering
about without them, even for me.
But tomorrow's
another day, eh?
Ah, well, that's just-
not for you.
I don't suppose you could
translate that for me?
You've got to go.
Oh, I know what this is.
It's victimization.
- You think we might lower the tone, do you?
- no!
- No, it's not that.
- yes, it is.
We've been thrown off sites
before and I promised myself
- it wouldn't happen again. We're not
going anywhere. - Please, just listen. it's-
we think there might
be poachers on the estate.
Oh, I see.
Well, it's your
lucky day then.
Did I not tell you?
I'm a policeman.
( wolf howling )
Golly: It won't roam too far,
not to begin with, anyway.
So we start the search, say,
within a mile of the house.
- Yeah, that should do it.
- Then we'll widen out from there.
( knocks )
Nice of you
to join us.
I didn't sleep
so good.
Ta.
As long as you've got your
wits about you this morning.
We can't open the place but at least
we're the only ones on the estate.
Ah, I was going to talk
to you about that.
You did tell the naturalists
they had to leave?
- Oh, aye, absolutely.
- Good.
The only thing is...
they wouldn't listen.
So they're still here?
There is something else
perhaps you ought to know.
Yes?
What's going on
there?
It looks like Duncan's got
his wires crossed again.
Ah, well he might
not be the only one.
What do you mean?
Well, you know, I just don't
think you should push it.
You know, with Irene.
Do you think I'm gonna
make a fool of myself?
- Oh, no, it's not that.
- What changed your mind?
It's just that we don't
know her very well
and I wouldn't want you getting hurt
on account of something I've said.
Thanks for your concern, Lexie, but I
think I'm old enough to look after myself.
( softly )
Great.
- Molly: spotted anything?
- Yes, unfortunately.
Kilwillie:
Morning, Archie.
I hope you haven't
had breakfast.
Trout, fresh from
the Kilwillie smokery.
No time I'm afraid,
Kilwillie, bit of a crisis on.
- I did rather wonder. What's going on?
- We've got a runaway.
Irene: Archie! Archie, I've seen it
- the wolf.
Where?
It's just outside
the enclosure.
Molly: Wild animal to recapture.
Don't worry, Archie,
Kilwillie will give you a hand.
Of course I'd love to,
but I've got-
rather an important
business appointment.
Kilwillie, we need all the help
we can get and I would consider it
a personal favor
if you would volunteer.
Oh, well... in that case,
I'd be delighted
to offer my services.
Duncan!
Oh no, it's him.
- Who?
- Ian.
But he's dressed.
Yeah, well, you know, they don't always
- do it with...
the man that runs this show,
I want to see him.
That's me.
Oh good, 'cause I thought we'd
found quite a little paradise,
but judging by your man Duncan
here's attempt at eviction, it seems
you're just as prejudiced as the
rest of the so-called moral majority.
Sounds like a public
relations matter to me, Ian,
and that's very much
my department.
Duncan, come on.
- I may call you Ian, mayn't I?
- It is my name.
Suits you.
Strong, manly.
You don't have to come
if you don't want to.
A Kilwillie's word
is his bond.
I know my mother sometimes
likes to take advantage.
Nonsense.
Glad to be of service.
I often wish I'd been called
Marilyn. So exotic, don't you think?
Where are we going?
Tea, scones
and a good old chin-wag.
Tranquilizer guns.
There are still people on the estate,
so speed is what really matters.
Nothing the matter is there?
We've practiced this often enough.
- It would be quicker and cleaner to shoot to kill.
- No!
And less dangerous. We don't know
how it'll react to being darted.
It'll be unconscious
in no time.
When an animal's cornered, there's
no telling what might happen.
They do everything they can
to avoid contact with people.
- Oh, I do hope so.
- Golly: that's just textbook stuff.
Now it's got a taste of the pheasant,
who knows how many it's gonna take?
Knocking it out solves
the problem as well.
It wouldn't have been a problem
if we'd stuck to what we know.
The wolves have been a
mistake from the beginning.
If my memory serves correctly,
the mistake was made
by the person who let one out
in the first place!
Aw, that's not fair. It was my fault,
too. I should have stayed with him.
Maybe, but it doesn't
help much now.
- no, but I was-
- have you heard yourselves?
This doesn't solve
anything.
Just go and get
the job done.
She's right.
Well, I'm ready.
Are you feeling lucky,
wolf? Well, are you?
Just remember this is a wild
animal we're dealing with.
We've all seen what wolves
do to their prey.
They always go for the soft,
vulnerable bits, Duncan.
So watch the wind
doesn't blow your kilt up.
- More tea?
- No offense,
but when the sun's shining I
don't like to be sitting indoors.
So why don't we go and see if
we can't find that son of yours?
Please, as I said,
any grievances you have,
you can air them with me.
I want to speak to the
organ-grinder, not his-
- monkey?
- Now I was going to say mother.
Duncan:
There's Carlin.
Yep. rhis shouldn't
be too difficult at all.
I reckon all it takes is
for one of us to nip down there
and let her back in.
- It's safer to be sure.
- That gets my vote.
Wait, wait, wait.
Duncan might be right.
( radio playing )
- Brilliant.
- Come on.
( techno music playing )
are you feeling so gay?
( screams )
Hey, hey, no need
to panic.
- So what are the guns for?
- We're on the trail of an escaped wolf.
( Heather screams )
Thank you very much, Duncan,
that is just what we needed.
This whole wolf hunt thing
is a training exercise.
I just thought we ought
to let you know that.
- Thanks.
- But if you'd feel better away from the place
then we'd be happy to
refund your camping fees.
- I don't think that'll be necessary.
- Why not?
Well, it's not as if
we're in any danger, is it?
A bit of a slippery customer,
your boy, isn't he?
Difficult to pin down.
Archie's a very busy man.
He always has something on.
Aye, that's as may be,
but there's no excuse
for poor service, eh? The
customer's always right.
Of course, why don't I
show you round?
Ah, Lexie, this is Ian,
you know from the campsite.
He's looking for Archie. You
haven't seen him, have you?
Uh...
no, no, no,
not for a while.
I mean, he's probably halfway up
that mountain or something by now.
Why don't you stay here, you know,
and wait for him until he gets back?
What a splendid idea.
If you don't mind, Mrs. MacDonald,
I think I'll just go after him.
Then why don't I show you what
Glenbogle has to offer on the way?
- Come on.
- Right.
Now, this is...
( mimicking gunfire )
Duncan!
- Where have you been?
- To fetch this.
You're not gonna
use it, are you?
It will be better
this way.
Come on.
I wish I'd brought
my sandwiches.
- Focus, Duncan.
- I'm hungry.
No doubt Irene will have something
hot waiting for us when we get back.
- Now you mention it, I meant
to say- - don't say a word.
- No, sorry, but I've got to-
- shut up.
( gunshot )
You missed.
What happened?
The sights must have
taken a knock or something.
I thought I said
tranquilizers only.
Don't worry, Arch,
he missed.
That's the whole point. You're
putting other people in danger.
I'm not gonna say this again
- you either do it my way or not at all.
Okay.
But if it's my fault she's
on the loose
then it's up
to me to get her back.
Right.
Which way did she go?
- Through the trees.
- Duncan, you circle round. I'll take the other side.
Golly, you make a slow
approach with Kilwillie.
Wilco.
- I would be better on my own, Archie.
- No.
You can keep an eye
on each other.
Everyone's nervous
the first time.
It's a strange attitude we have
to nakedness in this country.
- Molly: But once you've tried
it- - you'll never look back.
Why don't you come down to
the camp and meet the others?
Who knows, you might
even get the urge.
It's a bit close
to home for me.
Not so sure your boy
would approve.
My daughter's the same.
See, where we live,
no one knows.
Heather would be mortified if
we were the talk of the town.
She has enough to put up with
with me being in the police.
So what do your colleagues think?
I haven't told
them either.
You can imagine
the jokes, can't you?
"So where do you keep
your truncheon?"
You're very wise.
( growling )
This way, I think.
Wait a minute.
- Have you seen what I've just seen?
- No, no, what is it?
Now let's not
play games.
This.
Broken glass
and bare feet don't mix.
Safety, safety, safety.
It's the first rule
of the naturist's bible
and I'm a stickler for
what's right and proper.
It doesn't always
make me popular,
but somebody has
to make a stand.
Thank goodness you were there.
I hadn't even noticed it.
You've got to keep
your wits about you.
It's all part of the training.
There's not much gets past me.
We'll have to find a
wee bin to put this in
and put notices up,
Mrs. MacDonald.
We don't want glass
left anywhere around.
It's very,
very dangerous.
- ( Irene growls )
- Ah!
( Irene laughing )
I suppose you think
that's funny, do you?
You could have given me
a heart attack.
Get away with you.
Here, I think these
are yours.
No prizes for guessing
what you were up to, then.
Looking for Carlin.
Or having a little squint
down at the naturists.
See if you can catch that
girl with her kit off.
- I was not.
- If you say so.
Aye, I do.
I'm surprised you're
not down there with her,
getting a bit
of sunshine.
Or are you one
of those who goes
all red and blotchy
when you expose yourself?
My family tan
very quickly.
- We're known for it.
- Is that right?
And what else are
you good at?
( sniffing )
Look, I'm gonna go on
up the hill.
A sighting is more
likely from the top.
Good idea,
old boy.
Why don't I take
a look over there?
Golly!
Golly, I was gonna
tell you.
I tried, but I knew
how hurt you'd be.
I didn't do
it deliberately.
Irene and me
just sort of happened.
Please, Golly,
I'm really sorry.
We've still got
a wolf to catch.
Maybe you'd be more
comfortable speaking to my wife.
Oh, I'd really rather
not bother her.
Mrs. MacDonald, I don't think
you're interested in naturism at all.
This is some wild goose
chase you've got me on.
I am not gonna let you
waste any more of my time.
Ian!
- Did you find her?
- No.
Then you'd better be quick
'cause if he gets
so much as a whiff
of what's really going on-
perhaps if we didn't have
kilwille holding us up...
- you really shouldn't encourage him, mother.
- Whyever not?
If you give him reasons to stay, he'll be
here all the time. Not that he isn't anyway.
He's a very dear, old friend and as far
as I'm concerned he has an open invitation.
Well, you- you've got
the estate to run,
you've got Lexie,
you're a busy man.
Me?
I miss your father.
Now go and make
Glenbogle safe again.
I'll take over
if you like.
Ah, where
have you been?
- Sidetracked.
- Eh?
Have you ever had the feeling
you're missing something?
That it's happening right under
your nose but you just can't see it?
You're imagining
things.
Am I?
Now the important thing-
is not to panic.
So what do we do?
You're the ones that wanted
to get back to nature.
Not this close.
On my signal.
Everybody ready?
- Run!
- ( whining )
Nothing here.
Hang on, Archie.
- ( gunshot )
- ( howling )
Bull's-eye.
I think it's good news.
( groaning )
On the other hand.
So the two of you
just let Golly catch you?
Of course not. We
didn't mean it to happen.
We were just having
a laugh, that's all.
And how was he?
- He could do with some practice, but not bad.
- I meant Golly.
Oh, he didn't
look too happy.
- Duncan should have told him.
- Or I could have.
Why didn't you, instead of
driving a wedge through them?
Because for the first time
since I don't know when
I just wanted to cut loose
and have some fun.
Nothing heavy, nobody getting
hurt and nobody getting upset.
It didn't work out that way, did it?
Irene:
No, and I'm sorry.
Oh- never mind.
I think that's the least of
our worries right now. look.
- I'll get some help.
- Yeah, quick as you can, eh?
( growling )
Duncan!
Over here.
How serious
is this accident?
I guess that's what
we're about to find out.
He's gone,
and it's all my fault.
Molly: Keep calm. That's
not going to help anyone.
Molly? is that you?
Yes, Kilwillie,
it's me.
It's all right,
we're going to get help.
It's too late for that.
No, no it's not.
I just wanted
to hang on
until you got here
so that I could
tell you
how much I care.
Kilwillie, please. There
are people listening.
Then let them
all be witness
to my total devotion.
I knew it.
- He's delirious.
- Kilwillie: Only with happiness,
that yours will be the
last face I lay my eyes upon
before I shuffle off
this mortal coil.
Archie, please,
can't we do something?
How long is it since
you fired the shot?
10 minutes.
Then I'm afraid not,
mother, no.
( growling )
Look, it's the tunnel
of light.
Does anybody else
hear a harp?
When I pop my clogs, I hope
it'll be quicker than this.
- I've had a good life.
- Oh, please.
Archie, try to show
a little compassion.
He's not going to die.
It's just a tranquilizer.
- Oh, Kilwillie!
- I didn't know, did I?
It might make you feel a
little drowsy, that's all.
Well, I've got a pretty
robust constitution.
I dare say, I can
survive a little-
( snoring )
What are we
gonna do with him?
Leave him here. It's one
less thing to worry about.
The wolf, it's down
by the house.
( softly )
Lexie, get clear.
( growling )
Nice one.
We still have
to dart her.
Golly?
( wolf growling )
( growling continues )
Golly, don't go in there.
Stay back.
( wolf whining )
It's okay.
I'll take her back
to the enclosure.
- Well done, Golly.
- What sort of set up are you clowns running here?
Look, I can
explain everything.
Save it for the authorities. Oh, yes,
I'm gonna have them all down here.
Zoo inspectors, health
and safety, local council.
I'm sure we can
sort this out amicably.
I doubt it.
If I wanted to walk
amongst wild animals, I
would have gone on safari.
Think of the publicity.
The more people that know
about this the better.
But your name will
be attached to it
and then it'll come out
as to why you were here.
The questions, "where do
you keep your truncheon?"
I know a man of integrity such
as yourself can cope with that-
- of course.
- But think of Heather.
The embarrassment
for her.
We both have children who'll
be affected if this comes out.
But what if this
was to happen again?
I think we've learned
our lesson.
Our two heroes,
you were so brave.
Archie: And you're sure
Ian won't say anything?
He gave me his word,
and I believe him.
Carlin seems happier now
she's back with the pack.
So, all's well
that ends well, eh?
It's not though, is it?
Somebody could have got badly
hurt today because of me.
That fella was right to be angry.
We were lucky to get off so lightly.
In future we'll be
taking no more chances.
Are we getting rid
of the wolves?
- no, I'm sending you on a course.
- What sort of a course?
Just to brush up
your basic skills.
Look, if you don't mind me saying so,
even your numeracy is questionable,
judging by those figures
you did for the feed.
- What's numeracy?
- Adding up.
Surely you don't
mean that, Archie?
Yes, I do. If I'm going
to run this estate properly
then I need to make sure
that I can rely on everybody.
I would hate to be a drain
on your resources, Archie.
So you just keep
your money.
I don't need a course.
It's not my mind that is
feeble, it's my eyesight.
That's why I didn't lock
the enclosure properly.
That's why I missed
my shot and that...
that's why I can't
do my sums.
So you need glasses.
- It's not that simple.
- Of course it is, I wear them myself.
Molly, I've got
this rare condition.
It runs in my family.
My father was
complaining about it just
before he had his heart attack.
By the end you
can barely see at all.
I suppose you could
say he was spared.
So, Archie,
you can consider
my resignation tendered.
I'll not be a burden
to you anymore.
Golly!
Archie.
You should stay,
as well.
Well, no one's
stopping me.
Golly.
There's no need
for this.
I can't see
any other way.
Glenbogle's your home.
- All your friends are here.
- Friends?
Is that what they are?
Then how can they
treat me like this?
Every one of them-
Archie, Duncan, Irene.
Even you.
Don't say that.
Come on, Lex,
it's the truth.
You knew about
those two all along.
That's what you were
trying to tell me earlier.
You're not
really leaving?
Yeah.
Give this to Archie
for me.
I've no further use
for it.
Golly, please.
Not like this.
My mind's made up.
I hope you're happy.
I'm sorry.
I really am.
I was just wondering how
many it would be for dinner.
Four.
Lord Kilwillie
won't be eating then?
Both:
Kilwillie!
( snoring )
( theme music playing )
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0