( wolves howling )
( growling )
My father's dream was that
Glenbogle would be great again.
One way would have been
to avoid saddling us
with a mountain of death duties,
but never mind.
So, we are gonna give
the paying public
what they most desire-
a glimpse
of the dark side.
Lexie:
The Glenbogle wolves.
They'll be the biggest
draw in the highlands.
We'll get visitors
by the coachload.
Take more than a few wolves to
raise the kind of money we need.
How does "the Glenbogle
Wildlife Center" sound?
Bison, wild horses,
native birds,
brought back
to the highlands.
Well, I hate to think
what your mother'll
say when she gets back.
Oh dear, is my hair
a terrible mess?
( theme music playing )
My dear brother
sends his love.
- Especially to you, Lexie.
- How is Jolyon?
He's doing rather well.
He's broken into green beans.
I think he's going to
stay in Kenya for good.
Not that I saw
much of him.
White-water rafting,
elephant tracking,
there is so much to do
for the lone traveler.
And the journey?
I bought an old Jeep
and drove to Morocco.
But that's across
the Sahara desert.
You'd hardly expect
me not to notice.
And what happened
to the Jeep?
Oh, it got stolen in Tangiers along with the money
- everything.
Then an old friend who'd moved to
the Costas for professional reasons
gave me a lift
in his tiger moth.
You flew all the way
home in that?
Well, very nearly.
But the coast guards
fished us out of the drink
and here I am.
Oh, I've missed
this old place.
And you.
It's your home, Molly.
It's where you belong.
Come on, Lexie, you must
fill me in on all the news.
Lexie: Well, nothing
much has been happening...
you ready for the big day
tomorrow, Golly?
- Duncan: Do I have to sit an exam?
- No, just the head keeper.
The guy's name
is Burns,
and we only open
on his say-so.
Glenbogle's future in the
hands of a zoo inspector?
The new wolf's
arriving tomorrow.
She'll need collecting
at the station.
That sounds like a job
for the head keeper.
( barking )
That's the alpha female,
the only one with cubs.
She's magnificent.
Why don't you away in
and get a closer look?
( growls )
We're not supposed
to get too close.
- It frightens them.
- Ah.
You know,
Archie's right.
Loads of people are gonna
come and see these.
- Trippers, yes.
- As long as they pay the entrance fee.
Is that all anyone
cares about anymore?
Like the boss said, this
estate's going to be great again.
No, Duncan, it might be a rich
estate. There is a difference.
Where's mother?
Probably up to her
neck in hot water.
She really
is something, eh?
So are you.
Don't.
What's the matter?
Now that Molly's back,
it just feels like
I'm taking over.
Well you are, Lex.
You're gonna be the next
lady of Glenbogle
and mother will be only too
happy to pass the mantle on.
Molly's always been
really good to me.
It can't be easy
for her
just watching
a new model moving in.
I just don't feel good
about it, that's all.
Well, I do.
Are you sure that you
should be cuddling
the housekeeper,
your lairdship?
- What?
- Oh, nothing, nothing.
Just reminded me of a
little surprise, that's all.
Oh, will I like it?
I thought we said
no secrets.
Yeah, but that's
once we're married.
Look, you know I don't want
to rush you into anything.
But?
But, um...
no, nothing.
Nothing.
Oh!
Can I help you?
- I was looking for the kitchen.
- Why?
Are you Mrs. MacDonald?
- No, not yet.
- I'm sorry for just walking in.
There was no one around
and the door was open.
So, who are you?
I'm Irene Stuart,
the new cook
and housekeeper.
What is that woman
doing in my kitchen?
Who? Oh, she's arrived. Good.
- This is your surprise?
- I really appreciate
how you've looked after us
over the last few months.
- Appreciate?
- Carrying on as if nothing had changed.
- I really had no right to ask.
- I'm the housekeeper.
I've hired Irene to run
the wildlife center catering
and I thought she could do
the housekeeping as well.
( laughing )
Over my dead body.
Why, what's the matter? I
thought you'd be pleased.
You never even thought
to ask me first?
Then it wouldn't have
been a surprise, would it?
- If we're gonna be married-
- if's right.
When we're gonna be married, you
can't be the housekeeper, can you?
It was the housekeeper
you proposed to.
And it was the laird
that you accepted.
So this is a taste of what
being Mrs. Laird's like?
I think I'll stay as I am,
thank you very much.
I need you with me.
We've an estate to run,
staff to look after.
And this is how you
look after your staff?
- But you're not staff.
- Then what am I?
You're part of
the management team now.
I want to share
everything with you-
the running of the estate,
the hiring, the firing.
Right, okay, I'll start off
with what's-her-face then.
I can hire and fire with the best
of them, Arch. Especially fire.
- Lex.
- Only if it's important.
I'm management now.
Well, that's that sorted.
Seems to be some
misunderstanding.
- Oh?
- See, the post's filled.
But I've come
all this way.
- It was agreed with Mr. MacDonald.
- Sorry.
- I'd better take this up with him.
- No need.
If he's given the job
to someone else.
He didn't. I'm the cook
so there's no vacancy.
Mr. MacDonald made
me an offer in writing.
You might want to brush up
on your employment law
before you go
any further.
See, I don't think you
would like it here anyway,
they're a right
difficult lot.
Most of the chefs I've
worked with are on a good day.
I mean, they're on
your back day and night.
You've obviously never
worked in a top hotel.
- And I suppose you have?
- The Grand Lothian.
( laughing )
Not the Grand Lothian?
Did you get tired
of peeling veg?
I was the sous-chef. That
means I was in charge of-
yes, I know
what that means.
You've come down
in the world.
I needed a new challenge.
Right.
You see, people
only come to Glenbogle
for two reasons:
One is to deliver
a final demand
and the other is to
get away from something-
- I told you.
- -Or someone.
- I needed a new-
- challenge, right.
Well, Irene Stuart, you've
completed your first challenge.
You have found
the kitchen.
( chuckling )
I thought this would be for the
tourists, "how we used to live. "
No, this would be for us,
the way we live now.
It has character.
So does the Bates Motel but
you wouldn't want to cook in it.
If you show me to my
room I'll get changed.
Your room?
Okay.
Archie: I'm asking
you to set a few traps.
They're only rabbits.
It would help the
feeding budget go further.
They'll just have
to catch their own.
On this estate an animal dies
either from a clean shot or old age.
You and Duncan,
you both do the training.
You know what has to be
done. What's at stake.
I will help you
- but as a ghillie, not as a butcher.
Fine.
Before you walk away we have a
season's shooting to start planning.
Look, I respect
your principles.
I'm not gonna ask
you to go against them,
but I really do believe
that the wildlife park
is the future.
That's your plan,
is it?
To phase out the traditional
sports in favor of a zoo?
We make decent enough
money from the game parties,
I'm not arguing
with that.
But, if and when the
wildlife park takes off,
then yes, the emphasis
will change.
- I see.
- As I said-
yes, yes, ideas develop,
yes, you said.
This is a far cry from a few
wolves to please the punters.
What you're talking about is
the slow death of a way of life
that this estate has
depended on for generations.
I'll not be
a party to that.
What about the inspector?
The head keeper's exam?
Let me ask you
something here.
Would your father have
gone along with this?
- Nope.
- no.
Then how in all
good conscience can I?
Well, that all depends where your
loyalties lie, with him or with me.
I'll have Lexie liaise with you
over booking the shoots.
How's it going, Dunc?
One electric fence,
fitted and working.
- Have they been fed today?
- Golly does that.
Not anymore.
That exam.
Head keepers only
you said.
As of 10 minutes ago,
you are the head keeper.
That's Golly's job.
- He won't do it.
- Why not?
He has his reasons, but it's
you that I'm interested in.
I don't know.
It's a big promotion.
More money.
Company PlayStation.
It wouldn't be right.
There's no one else I can ask,
believe me. If there was I-
I wouldn't put you
in this
morally ambiguous
position.
What about
the exam though?
It's your big chance.
- Head keeper?
- You'd best start work.
- I won't let you down.
- I know you'll do your best.
Ahh!
( knocks, door opens )
I shouldn't have gone away
at a time like that but-
no, no.
You did absolutely
the right thing.
I totally understand.
And those beastly death
duties still to face.
Yes, 200 grand.
You'd think they'd
name a hospital
after him for that.
A ward at the very least.
Um...
I thought we might eat in
the dining room tonight.
Where have you
been eating?
The kitchen.
Oh, you'll have your father
haunting you as a class traitor.
I wanted you
to be here before we-
reopened
the dining room.
Don't stand on ceremony
for me. Eat where you like.
The dining room then.
As you wish.
I missed you,
Archie.
I missed you too,
mother.
- Who are you?
- Who's asking?
- And what are you doing in my freezer?
- Your freezer?
Can't you say anything
that isn't a question?
Can't you?
I'm the housekeeper.
No, you're not.
I'm the new housekeeper.
Which brings us back to you.
I'm Duncan.
The head ra-
the head keeper of the
Glenbogle wildlife center.
Hmm... pleased to meet you,
Duncan.
It's Irene.
Head keeper. That's quite a
job. You been doing it long?
Aye.
Now, what can I
get you to eat?
You wouldn't have a few rabbits
kicking about, would you?
- A few?
- Yeah, say 20?
Golly normally feeds
the wolves
- and I don't know where he gets it.
- Ask.
I can't ask-
I have to work this
out for myself.
I doubt he feeds them
from the kitchen freezer.
There must be
a local game dealer.
Yeah, and I can
afford his prices.
Aren't there any poachers
left in the highlands?
Well, yeah, there's old
Tommy the Shepherd but...
your chance remark
might have saved the day.
My dear Molly.
Kilwillie.
Home at last
from Africk shores.
Oh, Molly,
what a hollow shell
the world can seem when the
sweetest nut has been removed.
Yes... dear Hector.
Hmm?
Oh, Hector, yes.
Glenbogle will feel
rather lonely, I dare say.
Well, I've got Archie
and Lexie and the boys-
- and you of course.
- At your service.
Who could possibly
be lonely?
I've been admiring
Archie's wolves.
Mmm, so many changes.
Too many, perhaps?
Well, I intend to make some
myself starting tomorrow.
- Oh, can I help, extra pair of hands?
- Would you?
I'll be around first
thing in the morning,
shall we say 11:30?
Yes, quite early
enough for a gentleman.
No rabbits,
I'll grant you,
but I doubt your wolves'll
turn their noses up, eh?
Well, it doesn't say
they can't eat fish.
- fresh are they, Tommy?
- Aye.
- They're not ours, are they?
- No.
You'll want to watch
that water.
- It could scald you straight from the tap.
- I will.
And that oven runs
at 10 degrees cool.
Only nine, I checked.
You'll find the silver
cutlery in the dresser.
It was in dire need of a good
clean, as was the dining room.
This ring
- you'll find it a bit slow if you're used to cooking with gas.
I've cooked
on everything.
So, any more questions?
No, thank you. Dinner will
be at 8:00. Until then.
( door slams )
( electricity crackling )
Fetch.
( sizzling )
They like salmon, Dunc,
but not grilled.
I just thought I'd
try something different.
I know this
is controversial,
but why not use
the feeding tube?
I was just away to.
Where did you get these?
I've got my sources,
Archie.
I've got my sources.
- They are fresh?
- Oh, aye.
They are ours, yes?
Yes.
( growling )
Oh, Badger.
Lay out my dungarees
for tomorrow, will you?
I don't imagine we possess
dungarees, your lordship.
Then something appropriate
for manual labor.
Very good, m'lord.
- Oh, Badger.
- M'lord?
I may have a guest for
dinner tomorrow night.
Make sure the dinning
room is well set out.
What hour can we expect
the gentleman, m'lord.
The gentleman is a lady.
Golly: I'm sorry, but
I can't get excited
over a bunch of howling
dogs taking over the estate.
They lived here for centuries before
they were hunted into extinction.
I think it would be nice for
people to see them back in the glen.
In a pound though, eh?
So be it, and seeing how they're native,
surely they can survive
without my assistance.
You look the part.
Golly:
That you do, lass.
Well, looks
aren't everything.
They certainly help,
though.
I think I'd be
more use in the kitchen.
You know,
in a managerial sense.
No, I'm quite certain
it's all under control.
Do you want a drink?
I'm not in the mood.
Something the matter?
No, Molly,
you look great.
Thank you.
Golly, the pipes.
As you say, Molly.
Oh, I am absolutely
starving.
Mother, please.
Sweetheart.
Duncan, would you?
Thank you.
( bagpipes playing )
Oh, no, no, Lexie,
you must sit here.
But that's
your place, Molly.
I'm so hungry,
I've lost the will to argue.
Archie, you must
sit here, of course.
Come on.
Come on, boys.
Don't stand on ceremony.
Sit down, join us.
Duncan, I'm dying for
a drink, would you pour?
You won't believe this,
but that helicopter
didn't even have
a drinks trolley.
Ah, that's better.
We're all here,
dear friends.
We must count
every blessing
and cherish
every moment.
Thank you.
Good choice, Archie.
Ah, supper.
Ooh, and what treat have
you got in store for us,
Irene, isn't it?
Yes, Mrs. MacDonald.
It's seared sea trout
with a chicory flavored
tender sauerkraut
and a red wine jus.
It looks absolutely...
fine.
Bon appetit.
( sighs )
Well?
Very good.
Of its kind, of course.
- Is everything all right?
- Excellent, Irene.
Mmm, aye.
Yeah, well,
if the main course
is as good as that,
I'll be well satisfied.
That was the main course.
( muffled snickering )
I'm...
I'm terribly sorry.
I meant no offense.
Well, I'm full.
Will you give it a rest?
The exam's tomorrow.
I want to be the head
keeper even if you don't.
What brought this on?
I've always played
second fiddle to you
ever since I can remember.
It's not that I'm
complaining, mind.
I don't have your
experience. I'm not a ghillie.
But I could
be a head keeper.
You don't think being scared
to death of the creatures
is just a wee bit
of a disadvantage, no?
I'm not scared.
I'm in the process
of forming a relationship
based on mutual respect.
Well, they haven't
eaten you yet, I suppose.
Why don't you put that down
and get something inside you?
You must be
as hungry as I am.
I thought dinner
was very tasty.
That kind of modern fanciness
has no place round here.
You could give
her a chance.
You might get
to like her.
If her heart's
as big as her portions,
I seriously doubt it.
- She's good looking, though.
- Mmm.
Too old for me,
eh, Golly?
Old?
That makes me prehistoric.
Get away.
You're in your prime.
- Where are you going?
- The wolf pound.
It'll be dark soon.
A head keeper's place
is with his charges,
not stuffing his face
with bread and cheese.
If you were going
to go behind my back,
you might as well have hired someone
that could turn out a decent meal.
You're her manager, why
don't you take it up with her?
'Cause I didn't
bring her here.
I had hoped that you
might give her a chance.
What, like you hoped
Golly would welcome
your grand plan with
open arms? Get real, Arch.
I am getting real.
I'm about the only
one around here who is.
If those wolves don't pay off then
we're sunk. That real enough for you?
And you don't care who you
tread on in your progress march?
I offered Golly a job,
he turned it down.
No, you asked
Golly to change
his whole way
of life overnight.
Now we're getting to it.
At least Golly had
a chance to say no.
- Meaning?
- Meaning you can't ask people to be something
that they're not, Arch,
just because you want it.
Look, Lex, things are
bound to be different.
We're talking
about marriage.
No, you're talking
What are you doing?
I'm just gonna move
back into my own room.
Just for now, eh?
- Hi.
- Oh, are you starving, too?
No, not really. Here,
sit down. I'll get that.
Poor Irene.
She'll have to beef up our
portions or we'll all fade away.
It's the modern way
and you can't teach
a new dog old tricks.
Isn't it an old dog
new tricks?
Works both ways.
Now, here we are.
Here, now back
your cart in.
Oh, pardon,
bon appetit.
Would you like some?
No, I'm fine.
You know, Lexie dear,
it takes time to get used
to a new role. It isn't easy.
When you've been
the housekeeper.
All families need
new blood.
Life used
to be so certain.
I used to be able to read
all the signs and now,
now I can't
even see one.
Golly's finding it hard
too, and so is Archie.
He's lost
his father remember,
and I've been useless.
Hector didn't cast
a giant shadow
but he did provide a little
shade, and now he's gone.
Archie's feeling
the heat.
Everything depends on
him now, and his plans.
Are things
all right between you?
What?
Yeah, yeah.
( knocking on door )
Lex?
What time is it?
I'm on my way out, just thought
I'd see if you were okay.
- I'll get you some breakfast.
- no, no, no.
You can't go out
on an empty stomach.
I'm fine, really.
It'll take me
five minutes.
Irene was about.
She did me some eggs.
Oh.
So you don't need
me then.
Of course I do.
I'd better go see
to the wolves then.
Duncan:
She's not eating.
She hasn't
moved in ages.
You sure about
that salmon?
He said it was fresh.
Well, something's
troubling her, poor thing.
Perhaps-
perhaps she knows that
the new female's coming
and she's feeling
a bit not wanted.
They're not people, Dunc.
Don't anthropomorphize.
I'll try not to, boss.
You'll have to get your
skates on after the exam.
The handler will meet you
at the station with the wolf.
She'll be in
a traveling box.
Aye, right.
No problem.
They don't attack people,
you know that.
Not in the pack,
but this one's on her own.
The lone wolf is an
entirely different story.
She won't be alone,
will she?
You'll be there.
- Morning.
- Did you sleep well?
Eventually...
whilst someone
was up and about
frying sausages.
Don't take it personally,
it's just the way you
were taught how to cook.
I was taught the basic
good manners
of not invading another
person's work space.
I'll bear that in mind.
That's...
that's me away.
I thought maybe I'd bring back
a couple of rabbits.
Would that be
a peace offering?
It is the finest food
in creation if it's...
if it's cooked properly.
Hmm. And what are you
going to treat us to?
A wee slice of rabbit
on some bruschetta
with a drizzle
of vinaigrette?
How would rabbit pie
be for lunch?
Would that get us off
on the right foot?
Aye, that would
suit me fine, Irene.
Well, you off and do
your job then,
and I'll do mine.
Don't try and cook native.
Just stick to what you know.
You think I can't manage
a simple rabbit pie?
A complicated one, maybe.
A simple one, I doubt it.
We'll see
about that, won't we?
I'll cook lunch.
I'll not see good food ruined.
- Ruined?
- yes, ruined.
- ( door opens )
- What's going on?
( dog barks )
- Just girlie talk.
- Talk? I could hear it in the hall.
This person seems to think
she's a better cook than I am.
I only suggested
I cook rabbit pie.
- I am the cook.
- were the cook.
- Are you firing me?
- No one's firing anyone.
So, who's to cook lunch?
Irene, perhaps under
the circumstances-
you hired me to be
the cook, Mr. MacDonald.
She's right, Lex.
That's it,
take her side.
Do you know, there are too many ifs
and maybes in my life at the moment.
This one gets
sorted out right now.
I'll tell you who's going to cook
- you both are.
For the title
housekeeper/cook of Glenbogle.
Irene, if you lose, there's still
a job at the wildlife center.
Lose? in her dreams.
- Who'll judge?
- We all will.
Democracy rules.
Rabbit pies at 10 paces.
The laird has spoken.
Come on, dogs.
( dogs barking )
We can't have
all this clutter.
There's no hurry.
No better time
to spring clean,
throw open the windows and get
some fresh air into Glenbogle.
I thought father had left
all his clothes to Duncan.
Yes, he did.
He's taken what he wants,
the rest are going
to the charity shop.
It's about time your father did
something for the deserving poor.
Now that he's
not here to object.
Are you taking
all of it?
Every last jot
and tittle.
I'm glad Monty and Rommel
have taken it so well.
Poor little Useless.
They take me
for a walk every day.
Always the same...
the same route.
Old habits die hard.
( whimpering )
Am I intruding?
Of course not, and
dressed for action, I see.
Well, I'm not one
of those who thinks
that manual labor
is a Spanish butler.
Spam?
Hector took the nuclear
threat very seriously.
There's enough under the
bed to feed a small army.
Or small village perhaps.
What about Glenbogle?
Noblesse oblige.
A stack of these, too.
Ah, a full stomach
and a hearty chuckle.
Isn't that
just like Hector?
He wanted you
to have these.
You always admired them.
I shall wear them
with pride.
They fitted him like
the day they were made.
He kept his figure
to the end.
( exhales )
What a blessing
to be a small-boned man.
What's the book?
I've got an exam
this afternoon.
Head keeper business.
You'll be okay.
I'm not good
at exams.
I mean I liked-
I was good at history
but when it came
to the exam,
I didn't even remember how
long the 100 years war lasted.
Like cooking, it's all
in the preparation.
Give me the book.
And I've got to pick up
the new wolf from the station.
One thing at a time.
So, the ancient wolf's
natural prey?
Red deer, giant deer,
megalosaurus,
wild horse,
wild ox,
wild...
hare.
( bell jingles )
Well, that's
the hard part done.
Courage, mon brave.
If I had your courage,
Molly.
We must both be brave
and count on each other.
This lot'll
go down well.
It's rather heart-warming to
think that the poor of Africa
will enjoy the bracing
chafe of the tweed.
- It doesn't work like that.
- We sell them here.
- Oh.
- That'll be one of ours, I dare say.
My dear good woman,
all my attire comes
from Savile Row.
We have branches
everywhere.
Now you mustn't become
a stranger to Glenbogle.
Nor you
to Kilwillie castle.
As a matter of fact,
I've just added
a particularly delicious
vino to my cellar
which it would be
sacrilege to drink alone.
- Perhaps you'd join me?
- It's a little early, even for me.
- This evening?
- I've so much to do.
We could take a turn
in the launch.
Shall we say 6:30?
Good.
Ah, the hunter
home from the hill.
- Where are they?
- I'm afraid there were no rabbits to be had.
Golly,
the estate's overrun,
I mean they breed like-
like rabbits.
Nonetheless.
So, how's it all going?
- Wee problem. - Nimrod
has returned empty-handed.
Maybe the rabbits moved out
when the wolves moved in.
Golly, I know they have
sensitive noses but-
Archie, those wolves create
a terrible strong odor.
- I guess lunch is off then.
- We could have the competition at dinner.
Fine.
It's your turn
to decide the menu, Lex.
Oh, we are in
for a gastronomic treat.
Cullen skink!
Cullen skink?
Cullen-
excuse us.
Come here.
What?
Of all the things, you choose
some obscure highland fish stew.
She's probably
never heard of it.
- It just popped into my head.
- You really want to win, don't you?
I want to marry you and you'd
rather be my housekeeper.
You're gonna have to
make your mind up, Lex.
Golly?
Golly!
I'm just getting out of your
way now your zoo man's arrived.
- You still work here. - But if he asks me,
I'm gonna have to give him my opinion.
You don't want a conscientious
objector around on a day like this.
No, I want somebody
who understands animals.
All I know I've learnt from a book. He's
an expert, he'll see right through me.
- I'm sorry, son, but this was your decision,
not mine. - You're leaving me to it?
No, I'm going to do the
job that I was hired to do.
- By my father. - Oh- okay,
Archie, maybe you're right.
Let's just forget what's gone,
get rid of the baggage.
I mean, who cares?
That's not the way
I feel, Golly.
No.
I know you don't.
( clock chiming )
Don't you want to check
your answers, Mr. McKay?
I've got a train to meet.
I'm late already.
Duncan, slow down.
- is there a wolf chasing you?
- It's worse than that.
Is Arch giving you
a hard time, too?
No, I've got to go
pick up the new wolf
and Burns is here
for the inspection
and we can't open without him
and Archie's really worried
and... and... and he's depending on me.
On you?
Aye, great, isn't it?
Well, your man's scraped
through the written paper.
Well done, Duncan.
Skin of his teeth,
but he made it.
The important thing is that
he's good with the animals.
Oh, absolutely.
Here's Duncan now.
Burns: Oh, you're going ahead with it?
Aye. I'm not
scared of them.
You put a strange wolf
into the pack now,
they'll probably rip
her to pieces!
They...
they don't attack
their own.
Well, you can kiss
your certificate goodbye
until you can find someone
that has the slightest inkling
of what they're doing.
What's the problem?
Burns doesn't want me to put
the new wolf in with the others.
He has got a point, the
alpha female is pregnant.
You can't
sense it?
- Burns: who's he?
- That's our ghillie.
( latch clicks )
Golly:
Easy, easy.
Easy.
Easy, good girl.
Good girl.
That's it.
Go, go.
Easy, easy.
Good girl, that's it.
No one means you
the slightest harm.
You can still be
the boss of the pack.
- Easy, easy.
- ( wolf whining )
You show some respect
for your elders.
You might learn
something.
Here.
That's a girl.
That's a girl,
get the scent.
Good girl. see?
Nothing to worry about.
May come in handy
for the babysitting.
Good girl,
easy, easy.
Good girl.
Burns:
He's a natural.
Providing he takes the exam
you've got your head keeper
and your license.
Well?
Well, it is not what
I'm used to, Archie,
but if you ask me
to do the job,
I'll do it.
Thank you.
Sorry, son.
I handled it badly,
Golly.
That you did.
Not just you.
I really messed up
with Lex.
I don't know how I could
have been so thoughtless.
You had a lot
to deal with,
but now is the time
to mend some bridges.
What about Duncan?
Mightily
disappointed.
But he's young,
he can take the knocks.
The older you get,
the harder that becomes.
( laughing )
My granny taught me
how to cook.
She taught me
everything I know.
I used to dream
of living in a castle
and cooking for
a great family.
Is that still
what you want?
- What if it is? You're here.
- True.
It's a far cry
from the Grand Lothian.
I made a mistake. Is that
what you want to hear?
A mistake?
And you ended up here?
What did you do,
poison the president?
It wasn't a professional
mistake, and no,
I didn't poison
the president.
I won him over,
actually.
- Not the president.
- He was then.
Bill Clinton spent a night in
the hotel and I cooked for him.
So, you see, I was destined
to be in the kitchen.
Maybe I am too.
So, what did you
cook Mr. Clinton?
What I'm best
known for.
My signature dish
if you like.
Cullen skink.
That was so exhilarating.
The wind and the spray, oh,
you really must try it sometime.
"A.E.S. Kilwillie,
Eton, second 11." Oh...
well, I was quite an
all-rounder in those days.
- Delicious.
- You must have another one.
Or, perhaps
something to eat.
Nothing formal,
you understand,
just whatever
the kitchen can muster.
I really must get back.
Our new housekeeper is pitting
her skills against Lexie tonight.
There'll be tears before
bedtime. Another time perhaps.
Yes.
Another time.
Look, Lexie,
we don't have
to do this.
I was wrong,
I'm sorry.
Irene can work
at the wildlife center,
you can carry on here.
What do you say?
Let battle commence.
Thank you.
Well done, Irene.
A new take
on an old favorite.
Golly:
Yes, it's very nice.
Though haddock were just
a wee bit bigger in my day.
Never mind. You can
fill up on Lex's later.
- eh, Lex?
- One thing at a time, Duncan.
I'm sorry I'm late but
Kilwillie absolutely insisted
on dragging me out
on the loch.
And how is Kilwillie?
That was absolutely
delicious.
Thank you.
Don't worry, left plenty
of room for yours, Lex.
So you've
really done it.
You've made your choice?
Yeah.
No more doubts.
No more cooking?
Why would I want
to be in the kitchen
when I could be here
at my own table
with my own man?
Duncan: So that's a no
to the cullen skink then?
I still can't believe you
got engaged with a ring pull.
It's all we could
find at the time.
- The new wolf seems to have fitted in fine.
- Well enough.
I think it's great, this
wildlife center idea.
Makes life
more interesting.
Well, you're young.
You're not old, Golly.
You're- experienced.
Some women like that.
For example?
No one in particular.
You can put all such ideas
right out of your head, Duncan.
She's a looker,
and sophisticated.
I've no mind
to go courting Irene.
Aye, like you'd no
mind to be head keeper,
but here you are.
What do you think,
Lexie?
This yellow for the
golden sands of the Sahara
or the blue
of the African sky?
Yellow.
Yellow's more... cheerful.
Then yellow it is.
Um...
I've been thinking
about my room.
Redecorating?
Moving out... and moving
into Archie's room.
- May I ask- - if you
don't approve, it's fine.
May I ask what has
taken you so long, Lexie?
Love is precious, every single
moment of it. Don't waste it.
You're not young
forever,
even if you're
in love forever.
Are you?
In love forever?
Now, when Archie
drives you mad,
which he will from time
to time, you can move
into Hector's old room.
I'm going to decorate it next.
Something very warm
and very colorful,
don't you think?
What's this?
Archie MacDonald, will you
take this former brainless idiot
to be your lawful
wedded wife?
Yes.
But...
there is one condition.
Oh, yes?
Do you think that
we might improve
on a ring pull?
You stingy,
Scottish cheapskate.
That is nothing to what
my mother called me.
But that's Molly's.
She wanted you
to have it.
So, we do get
our fairy tale ending.
Good night, Mr. Laird.
Good night, Mrs. Laird.
( theme music playing )
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0