Hello.
Come here.
What's his name?
Useless.
Aw, who called him that?
What are you going to
tell your mother about me?
Nothing.
What about us?
What would Hector
have wanted?
My father is dead.
( Useless whining )
Useless!
( barking )
( theme music playing )
You can't just send
him away.
I just did.
- Archie: Morning all.
- All: Morning.
Tea? Coffee?
That is so kind.
Well, Lexie, last night was wonderful.
Everything
was perfect.
- Almost perfect.
- Golly: it was a triumph, lass.
Duncan: The whole day went
off pretty well, eh, Arch?
- Hmm?
- you know, Big Eric
being... exactly
where I said he'd be.
We're a good team.
I think I'll have a quiet day,
contemplating a life of leisure,
now that we have a new
and very capable
Lady of Glenbogle.
- I've got a lot to learn.
- So have I.
Still, I hope life will
still spring a few surprises.
Coffee, mother?
Thank you.
Do you know, I'd love
to travel again.
Why would you do that? Why
would anyone want to leave here?
Well, a man has to settle
sometime, somewhere.
It sounds suspiciously
like pipe and slippers to me.
You're much too young
for that.
Oh, look, there's Useless with
that young man from last night.
Lexie:
Oh, so it is.
Excuse me.
Would you like some
more coffee, Molly?
I couldn't shake him, he's
taken a real shine to me.
- What do you want from us?
- I came to return your dog.
A word of thanks
might be a start.
Thank you.
- Now please-
- what? Get off my land?
You have no right
to wreck my mother's life.
Oh, that's rich.
What about my mother?
Her life? who do you
think wrecked that?
Let's not start
a slagging match here.
I'm sorry, but that's in the past
and that's where it should stay.
It does affect all of
us, especially Molly.
- Somebody mention me?
- It's nothing, mother.
What affects
especially me?
Hector's son. But that
makes Molly his mom.
Molly is not Paul's mother, Duncan.
Hector MacDonald,
you dirty dog.
- Morning, Kilwillie.
- I'm looking for Archie.
Belated gift for the intended honeymoon.
- Rather generous. - Two
round-the-world air tickets, first class.
- That's slightly more than rather, old boy.
- Molly will be very impressed.
That never
crossed my mind!
( shudders )
You didn't know Hector
like I did.
Do you think he could have kept
this from me for what, 30 years?
Longer.
I was born in '66.
You and countless others.
You'll be blaming him
for all of them next.
I'm not blaming anyone.
Excuse me, I've got
a thousand things to do.
Paul-
- Molly, I think you'll be
pleased- - Not now, Kilwillie.
- Oh, I say, Archie-
- later, Kilwillie.
- Lexie?
- A wee bit busy, Kilwillie.
Is he telling the truth?
There's a letter from
the estate's solicitors.
I'm afraid there's
very little doubt.
These things happen.
Well, heaven knows,
Hector was no saint.
He made a mistake,
end of story.
- Is there anything I can do?
- No. thank you.
I told him what this
would do to her.
- Archie, don't-
- he had no right to come here.
Maybe you could try
showing a bit of leg.
I brought your mate.
Come on, at least
hear me out.
Right, you started this
so you're going to listen to
me whether you like it or not.
Paul: He asked me to leave.
How clear do you need it?
You have dropped a bit of
a bombshell around here.
The dust will settle and you can
all get back to what you're best at.
Which is?
Keeping your precious acres
free from the common herd.
Listen, pal, I'm just
as common as you are
so don't come
the underdog with me.
You married well.
I married the man
that I love,
and believe me,
he is worth the effort.
I hoped he and I could
get to know each other.
- It takes time.
- I haven't got time.
A couple of days at most.
I doubt the ice
will thaw that quickly.
It's worth a try.
A letter, your lordship,
a letter.
- Very far from unusual.
- This one is, sir,
for this one bears
the royal seal.
I've been out looking
high and low.
I guessed you'd gone courting
with Mrs. MacDonald again.
No, no, I was just
looking for Archie-
good lord!
Bad news,
your lordship?
Au contraire.
Kilwillie Spring Water
has been selected
for the royal table.
Is that all, sir?
Bested in courtship, second
in Molly's affections,
yet my foot is on the silken ladder
leading to the ultimate prize.
Kilwillie, by royal
appointment. hah!
( car doors slamming )
Does Archie know
about this?
No, not yet.
He's come a long way
to find us
- and doesn't have much time.
- I'm not going behind Archie's back.
You take care of Paul,
I'll talk to Archie.
See if I can
bring him round.
What about Molly? Is this not
rubbing her nose in it a wee bit?
No, it's helping her
face the truth, Golly.
You might come to regret
starting this, lass.
I didn't start anything.
Look, he's here, he's more
of a MacDonald than I am.
I know that.
So, do you not think he deserves
to know something about his roots?
Archie has to know, mind.
I mean, he doesn't take
a scrap of notice of me.
I may as well be
part of the furniture.
Archie has got a lot
on his mind, son.
He doesn't mean
to seem ungrateful.
I mean, like yesterday.
If it wasn't for me,
Big Eric would still be
staggering around out there.
I told you
you did a good job.
Yeah, I know, but a pat on the
back from Archie wouldn't go amiss.
It's my own fault,
of course.
Well, I don't push
myself forward.
I'm always in the background
being good old Dunc.
Well, do it,
assert yourself.
Why? no one would
take any notice.
Can you hear anything?
No.
No, neither can I.
- ( rock thuds )
- Dry as a bone.
The brochures came.
I know, everywhere we
talked about is so expensive.
We got married
economy class.
I want our honeymoon to be
something really special,
something to look back on
when the house is overrun
with little people.
Don't jump
the gun, you.
Anyway, all I need
is for you to be there.
That makes it special.
Well, that
and the hot sun
and the golden beaches.
How much do
you love me?
Oh, about that much.
A lot.
Good, because
you'll need to.
- Paul's back.
- You've seen him?
- No, I brought him.
- What?
He's Hector's son. You can't
pretend he doesn't exist.
- Where is he?
- Just hear me out.
- Paul is part of this family.
Okay? you can't
just send him away.
For Molly's sake,
as long as Paul's a stranger
to her then Hector will be too.
- She loved my father.
- And he betrayed her.
If he was alive today,
she would rant and rave
but eventually
she would forgive him.
- I doubt it.
- Paul is a living reminder of Hector,
- just like you are.
- You are wrong to interfere.
Archie, this gives me
the right to interfere.
I am part of this family.
Paul is too.
Where is he?
You tell me
where he is.
I'll take no time
to dig a trench.
Yeah, so long as he
comes up with the idea.
Duncan, Paul was
just reminding me,
there's the burn
not 50 yards away.
What do you think?
Have you any ideas?
It's a fair way
to move a house, Golly.
So, maybe we could...?
- Buy a bucket?
- Buy a bucket, or...?
Hey, we could
dig a trench.
- Great idea, mate.
- Excellent.
Badger!
- How are you feeling?
- Fine.
I wish you could talk
to me about this.
Why? it's the past.
Live for today, look
forward to tomorrow.
Yeah, but something
as big as this, Molly.
Hector had a fling, there
was a child, that's it.
If you want
to talk to him...
- To whom?
- Paul.
It's not too late.
Why on earth should
I want to do that?
Where is he? What are
you playing at, Golly?
I don't believe
he means any harm.
He's done enough. I don't want
him running into my mother again.
Look, I'm concerned
about Molly, too,
but the lad has
rights as well.
- Does he?
- Yes, he does, Archie, and so do I.
A lot of this is my fault. I
have some amends to make here.
Archie, that fellow
is attempting to steal
my commercial assets.
We were looking for a source
of water for the house.
- What's wrong with the well?
- It's dry.
- It was okay last year.
- Underground springs run to their own plans, not ours.
He can't live here
without water.
He'll have
to live without mine.
I don't know if you've noticed, but it
falls from the sky on a pretty regular basis.
Yes, and what falls
on my land is my own.
Archie.
I don't want to fall out with
you over this, but dash it all,
my water's about to
furnish the royal table.
I can't have it used by every Tom,
Dick and Golly for their ablutions.
That is both petty
and insulting.
Petty?
Archibald MacDonald,
consider our two great and
ancient houses in dispute.
Okay.
Oh.
Badger.
Do you see the trouble
he's caused?
You shouldn't have
got involved, Golly.
Don't take it out on him. It's
me you should be talking to.
I have nothing to say to you
that I haven't said already.
Lads, lads!
This is not
like you, Archie.
I want him
away from here.
No, son, this is my home,
he is my guest.
Right.
It's on your head.
What about Kilwillie?
He is the least of my problems
right now. You deal with it.
- ( knocking )
- Come in.
- Andrew: I hope this isn't a bad time.
- Not at all.
Do sit down.
You've no shortage
of bedtime reading.
Do you know how few
I've actually read?
They're just a silent
reminder of how little I know.
But we learn through living, don't we?
I admit, I've been a bit
overzealous in that regard.
Bet you wouldn't
change a day of it.
Maybe the odd day. But,
whether it's my age,
or maybe
it's this place,
but I'm ready
to change, Molly.
Don't change too much, you'll
completely lose your mystery.
I don't want to be a mystery
- I want to be a very good neighbor,
and a good friend.
Another Glenbogle
casualty.
People come here and lose
the will to leave.
Why leave-
when everything
you want is here?
You and your husband
were very lucky.
My husband.
Yes.
Actually...
there is something that you could
do for me, if you'd be so kind.
Kilwillie: Kilwillie Spring Water
will be the most sought-after,
the most exclusive,
the most hideously
expensive manifestation
of god's great bounty
that ever fell upon our heads.
Your mission is to guard
every drop and trickle
of this priceless
commodity.
Never in the history
of bottled water
has so much depended
on so few.
Carry on.
Seems Mrs. MacDonald
has finally
passed him over.
It still
looks good to me.
Disciplined drawing,
deft brushwork
and a pretty sound
composition.
But I completely failed to
capture the character within.
- Where's it go?
- This way.
- Mother?
- Keep going.
Can I have a word?
In here.
Golly needs your support.
Don't abandon him
because of me.
I can't keep you
out of Golly's house
- but I can, and I will, keep you out of mine.
- Why?
- Have you seen my mother?
- this isn't about your mother.
- Her feelings aren't important?
- of course they are.
She'll deal with this her
own way, like we have to do.
I don't want this any
more than you, Archie,
but we are brothers,
that is a reality.
- ( Archie sighs )
- Paul's right.
There is more to this
than just Molly's feelings.
First Golly, now you, why can't we
just focus on what's best for mother?
Why can't we just think about
what's best for all of us, Arch?
Well, we'd better start
by canceling the honeymoon.
What?
I can't leave here with him
around and my mother like that.
This place rules
our lives, doesn't it?
Glenbogle has
to come first.
We're just
caretakers, Lex.
We don't own it,
it owns us.
Badger,
some tins
from the pantry.
Oh, artichoke hearts,
gentlemen's relish
and shoe polish.
Thank you, your lordship.
Did you happen
to bring a tin opener?
I thought butlers
had those.
Oh, right enough,
your lordship.
I'll collect these tomorrow
morning when I bring the silver.
Very good,
your lordship.
Molly,
what have you
done with it?
Oh, that-
it's where it belongs.
And before you say anything,
the answer is definitely no.
- Really?
- nothing to do with Hector.
It was a poor painting and I've been
meaning to take it down for some time.
- I thought it was a good painting.
- No, it wasn't.
After all,
I should know,
I studied at the slade
before I came here.
You don't regret that,
though, do you?
Heavens no, being
the Lady of Glenbogle
in this beautiful,
isolated place
and all those wonderful
years with Hector,
of course I don't
regret it.
Whatever you
might think, son,
no man gives up
his own child
without a great deal
of pain.
Sounds like experience.
It's my daughter.
I've seen her since.
How did that feel?
Like looking
in a mirror.
She was
a stranger to me,
but I knew her
like my own hand.
Can't believe Hector
lost any sleep over me.
Oh, he did, he did.
Many a time there'd
be a knock on my door
in the middle of the
night, here he'd be,
bottle of malt
in his hand.
What did he talk about?
What it would be like if he
met you, what you looked like.
How you were getting on.
Caused me a few sleepless
nights, too, I can tell you.
Not to mention some
pretty ferocious hangovers.
- I've been thinking.
- And?
And I don't think we should
let Kilwillie call the shots.
I think we should
strike back tomorrow.
Lexie: I just can't get through to her.
- I've tried but-
- ( door opening )
- Morning, mother.
- Kedgeree for breakfast, Molly, your favorite.
No time, dear,
I must pack.
What do you mean,
pack?
I'm leaving.
- What, for a holiday?
- No, just leaving.
I'll go.
- Oh, give me a hand.
- You cannot just up and leave.
My mind is made up.
Don't try and stop me.
Let's talk about it.
I'll keep in touch, of course.
let you know where I am.
- I promise you, he won't come here again.
- Who won't?
- Paul, I'll get rid of him.
- Archie, please.
- Badger?
- Yes?
I claim this land
in the name of the Glenbogle estate.
I see.
Aye, right, well,
surrender now and
no one need get hurt.
Technically, it's not
mine to surrender.
Now, shall I pour
us some tea,
whilst you
think on that?
Aye, pour us some tea.
Good lord!
Tea with the enemy?
He's just following
my orders.
- You orders?
- Aye.
Maybe now you'll
listen to our demands.
I'll be negotiating with Archie.
I only talk to the organ-grinder.
Pompous ass.
He had the sheer affrontery
to call me pompous.
Good lord.
I take it he'll
be disciplined.
- It's out of my hands.
- he's in your employ.
- No.
- Then what is he doing here?
He's my father's son.
Well, then he ought
to know better. What?!
He's Hector's son, he turned
up a couple of days ago.
Good god.
So you can see how your waterworks aren't
exactly top of my agenda at the moment.
Hector?
Does Molly know?
- Mm-hmm.
- And?
She's leaving.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
We'd like to speak to
Sergeant Bowman, please.
Paul Bowman?
He's left this
as a contact address.
- Ah-ha.
- So, he's here?
Yes, yes he was.
He dropped in just to say
hello, but he's gone now.
Golly: Is there something
you're not telling us?
Technically, I should
be in barracks.
You mean
you're AWOL?
I had compassionate leave,
of course, when mom was ill.
And for the funeral.
So you haven't
been back since?
There was a posting
waiting for me in Cyprus.
But with mom gone and the
house and everything...
I've done a lot
of overseas tours,
but I've always had somewhere
to come back to. Somewhere I'm-
you know, home.
Is there something
we can do?
I've caused enough
trouble already.
Time I was on my way.
Is this a court-martial
job, son?
Yeah. but if I'd
found my father
it would have
been worth it.
What about going back,
facing the music?
- I can't, not yet.
- It doesn't seem right, though,
just leaving
with nothing.
I've seen the place.
You all.
It's better than nothing.
Golly:
Come on, son.
Come on, I'll give you
a lift to the station.
I've told Archie
and Lexie, of course.
But I wanted you to know
from me, not second-hand.
But where will you go?
How will you live?
There are one or two minor
details to hammer out.
I have friends and
contacts all over the world.
I could put you
in touch with them.
You'd be guaranteed
a warm welcome.
Thank you.
Or, I could come
with you.
As a friend,
nothing else.
I wouldn't dream
of dragging you away.
Your cottage,
you're so happy here.
Bricks and mortar,
Molly.
That's not where
the heart is.
I hope I haven't
offended you.
Not at all.
It's a very kind offer.
And I shall give it
some thought.
It's been a shock,
son, for Archie.
It'll take him a wee
while to get used to it.
It's been a shock
for me too.
But it's more
than that with him.
He looks at me and he sees
something he can't handle.
I don't know what it is.
Golly: They'll be watching the station.
I'll take you back,
wait until nightfall
and then you can get past them.
Golly, I've got you
in enough trouble as it is.
But Archie? Lexie?
Oh, they'll be fine.
Well, me then?
Your friendship means a
great deal to me, Kilwillie,
but the day
has come for me
to break the bonds
of Glenbogle.
Archie did tell me a bit
about the circumstances.
Hector?
It came as a bit
of a shock.
So Hector never
confided in you?
No, he didn't. Just
in Golly, apparently.
- Golly knew?
- According to Archie.
And he said nothing.
I beg you
to reconsider.
This is a time when you should
be among your friends, Molly,
- not all alone in the world.
- I won't be all alone.
Andrew's offered
to come with me.
He's on the run from the army,
he's put Kilwillie's back up,
he's turned Golly against me,
how can you defend him?
Because he's your own
flesh and blood, Archie.
- he's risked everything to come here.
- Yeah, to cause trouble.
To find out a little bit
about your father.
A few scraps,
other people's memories.
It means a lot, Arch,
believe me.
He'll be gone
by nightfall.
Go and see him, eh?
You knew and you
said nothing.
- I thought it was the right thing to do.
- For whom?
I've carried this for 30 years
and I would gladly carry it
for 30 more to protect
what I hold dear.
What?
Hector's reputation?
No, your family.
I'm leaving.
Are you? You did that once before.
How dare you?
You know nothing about
what happened that day.
Nothing at all,
or why I left.
- I was 19. I came back, didn't I?
- I know, by then
- Megan was already carrying Hector's child.
- And so was I.
- You can't blame me for that.
- I don't,
but I don't blame
Hector either.
Listen, Molly,
it is too late for him
to ask your forgiveness,
but it is not too late
for you to grant it.
You worked for
Archie long?
Born into it.
Part of the
furniture, eh?
Aye.
What is his problem?
It's not really
his fault.
He's got a lot to put up
with, being the laird and all.
It can't be easy,
doing that all on your own.
He lost a brother,
didn't he?
Jamie, aye, drowned trying
to save the family labrador.
Archie was there, mind,
but nothing he could do.
He loved this view.
He loved my mother.
He was an average
fisherman,
a rather poor golfer.
He loved his dogs,
the hills,
loved his malt,
especially that.
He fought in Korea,
he was stubborn,
sometimes stupid.
He often talked
too much,
sometimes not enough.
And we thought
the world of him.
Thank you, Archie.
Duncan told me
what happened to Jamie.
I'm really sorry
for you.
I want you to go now.
Andrew: Golly?
I was looking
for Kilwillie.
He said he was coming
up to see you.
Did he?
Something wrong?
You've not heard then, that
Molly's intent upon leaving?
Well, is that
a bad thing?
I'd like to know who's
been encouraging her.
- Well, perhaps she needs a break.
- No.
No, she needs to stay
and face things.
If she runs now, she'll
be running forever.
Maybe you're right.
I am right.
...tie it and secure it.
His lordship...
that man has taken
leave of his senses.
If we let him
finish it,
you can kiss goodbye
to your water.
It's okay,
we'll deal with it.
You don't have
to get involved.
Well...
since I'm here, it's the least I can do.
Yeah, and I have a plan.
Good, Duncan.
I'll create a diversion,
lead these three on a merry
dance through the woods,
and you two take
down the fence.
Will they not just
put it back up again?
Paul: Yes, but sometimes
you have to show the enemy
you can be as bloody-minded
as they are.
Drag them to
the negotiating table.
- right, Duncan?
- That was my thinking, exactly.
Okay, Duncan,
let's go with it.
All right, Duncan.
Come on, lads,
I haven't even
started yet.
Come on.
We've got
our diversion,
let's get on
with the job.
Badger?
What brings you here?
Just trying to walk off the
effects of Golly's cooking.
Good lunch, was it?
Venison, potatoes,
fresh vegetables.
What was that sauce,
Golly?
It was red wine,
mustard and wild thyme.
That must have
been grand.
It still is.
We couldn't finish it.
We were wondering maybe if
you could help us out there.
Well, what about
my duties?
There are times, Badger, when
duty betrays common sense,
and we foot soldiers,
as it were,
should unite to put
an end to this madness.
Aye, aye.
We're lions led
by donkeys right enough.
I'd be happy
to take lunch with you.
Excellent.
This way, Badger.
Look after
our guest, Golly.
My pleasure, Paul.
( humming )
I'm sorry, Badger,
I hope you don't mind,
but seeing as how
they've captured Duncan.
I'd rather be a prisoner of a gentleman
than a free man
in a world gone mad.
Lexie: This water business is a farce.
You've let it get
completely out of control.
Kilwillie's entitled
to protect what's his.
Anyway, he didn't
start it.
Paul did.
All his fault
as per usual.
Give him a break,
Arch.
He's upset everyone.
He's upset mother.
You can't blame him,
it's not his fault.
- Where are you going?
- There's something I have to do.
Send Duncan.
I can't.
I think he was finally beginning
to believe he could do it.
You know, be the laird.
Molly,
don't go, please.
- Kilwillie: Are we ready for the exchange of prisoners?
- That we are, your lordship.
Good.
Send Badger over.
Not on your life.
You give us Duncan first.
This is my land,
send over Badger.
I don't care. You give us
Duncan and we'll give you Badger.
- Badger!
- Duncan!
Lexie:
Right, now let me through.
Now, Lexie,
this is men's talk.
Out of your backsides,
as usual.
Now, do you expect Golly
to live without water?
Well, it's a precious
commercial asset.
And you really think
that Golly's needs
will make a scrap of
difference to your business?
This is a matter
of principle.
Principle?
Listen, there are people
hurting round here.
Archie and Paul
over there.
And what about Molly,
too, Kilwillie?
Don't forget about her.
And you are standing here bickering
over a matter of principle.
Over a small amount
of water.
Don't you know that there's
more to life than that?
Hear, hear.
I'm a reasonable
man, Lexie.
If you've got a suggestion,
I'll listen to it.
Thank you.
Now, we can start by
taking care of our friends.
I have a plan which
involves you all,
and which,
by the way, gentlemen,
is not optional.
Come on.
Well?
Well, the thing is,
Archie,
I've been a damned fool.
You were only trying
to protect your own.
If it's at the expense
of one's friendships
then it's a very
poor show.
Golly will have his water
at an annual peppercorn rent.
That's very generous
of you.
And didn't you have something
else in mind, Kilwillie,
as a sort
of goodwill gesture?
Oh, all right.
Golly can take advantage
of my offer much sooner
if he has some assistance
with the building work.
What did you have in mind?
I should like to place my estate
workers at his disposal today.
Many hands, as we know,
make light work.
- He'll be very grateful.
- We can help too, Arch.
No, no, I won't go to
Golly's house. You know why.
I know why
you should-
because he's your ghillie
and you're his boss.
Okay, so I'll go and
round up some helpers
but the laird should
be there, too.
As you said, Glenbogle
does come first.
- ( knocking )
- Come in.
Here you go.
Not too much,
is there?
You tell me,
Molly.
You've unfinished
business here,
and you know it.
- ( people talking )
- What's going on?
Quite a turnout.
It'll be a good time
to say goodbye at least.
No.
Pack a bag and slip out
the back door?
That may be my style, Molly,
it certainly isn't yours.
Put you backs
into it, lads.
Lord Kilwillie's
orders.
He'll be back at
headquarters, I suppose?
Messed up, didn't I?
Good old Dunc.
Can't even create
a diversion.
Duncan!
Aye, here
we go again.
Golly: Better see what the man wants.
Boss.
Hey, Big Eric.
We'll not see his like
round here for a while.
Nope. read it.
They're yours, Dunc,
you did a good job.
There's beer and food
for everyone here.
All right?
So, what can I do?
Paul: You can give me a
hand with this, I suppose.
- Where do you want it?
- Up there.
Ready when you are.
Goodbyes are hard.
Molly: That's Hector's
son down there with Archie.
His son, not mine.
Are you surprised
I want to leave?
No...
but I'll be surprised
if you do.
I don't think
you'll run away.
You're right.
Shall we join them?
I'll go
and unpack first.
( Useless barking )
It's fortunate
that neither of you
inherited your father's
D.I.Y. Skills.
- Useless?
- Golly: He'll be back.
Look, Golly, I'm sorry.
I had no right to talk
to you the way that I did.
This has been a lot
tougher for you
than most people imagine.
It was like
he'd come back.
But it wasn't him,
it could never be.
Archie, Archie,
you were a child then.
Stop blaming yourself.
Jamie would have
been a fine laird,
but he couldn't
have done more
or better than you.
Don't look back
anymore, son.
Perhaps I should
talk to Paul.
I can't tell you
how to feel but...
if I'd lost
a brother...
I'd be in no mind
to lose another.
( Useless whining )
Get away from
the edge, Paul, come on.
Useless is stuck,
poor lad.
He'll make his
own way back.
No, he won't.
Come on.
Here.
Come on, Useless.
- Got him?
- yep.
Here, give me your hand.
Come on.
Paul!
It's Archie.
Archie!
Where are they?
What's going on?
I can't see them.
( large gasping )
Archie!
- Have you got him, Golly?
- I've got him, I've got him.
- On your feet.
- I've got him.
- Go!
- Let's get him out.
- Come on!
Duncan:
Come on, lie him down!
Archie?
You okay?
Welcome back.
( whimpers )
You shouldn't be
drinking beer, young lady.
And why not?
Because you know
what it does to you.
You, Golly, know
far too much about me.
Listen, Molly,
I really am sorry
that I kept it
from you.
Mrs. MacDonald,
I wanted to apologize-
no, please,
there's really no need.
So, you'll be staying
for a while?
No, I'm going to go
back to my regiment.
Well then, you must
visit us whenever you can.
Your father loved this
place. His heart was here.
Thank you.
So, it looks like I'll have
you under my feet after all.
You know, Glenbogle wouldn't
be the same without you, mother.
And it wouldn't be the success
it is without you, Archie.
You've done it, you've
turned this place around.
With a little help.
Kilwillie:
So, you two,
is the honeymoon back
on the agenda?
No, I don't think
we can-
well, mother's not
going anywhere.
Golly and Duncan can
look after the place.
I'm sure you'll keep a neighborly
eye out. So, what's to stop us?
Oh, Kilwillie.
Oh, thank you, thank you,
thank you.
- ( footsteps approaching )
- Come on, come on,
don't keep the man
waiting.
Lexie: We're coming,
we're coming. sorry.
It took so long
- have you got the tickets?
Yes, they're here,
come on.
Molly:
Let me help you.
- Duncan: goodbye!
- Last one.
That's it.
Goodbye my darlings,
have a lovely time.
Duncan:
Take care.
See ya!
Bye.
- Bye!
( theme music playing )
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0