Norton commando.
Thought so.
Sorry to keep you waiting,
Archie. Take a seat.
- Coffee?
- No thanks.
Just tell me,
how bad is it?
Now, the deadline for
the death duties is up.
You've got
two days to pay
or you'll start to accrue a
significant amount of interest,
and that's on top
of the original sum.
I had a client in a similar
position not so long ago.
- And what happened?
- Bankrupt within a month.
Now, the bank have made
their position very clear.
They'll offer
no more help
until this debt
has been satisfied.
So your only chance is to
raise the money yourself.
I don't see how.
The wolf park is making a profit
but it's nowhere near what we need.
- There must be other ways.
- I've tried them all.
The ones I can
think of anyway.
- Surely there must be something you can do.
- Sorry, Archie,
I'm a solicitor,
not a miracle worker.
( theme music playing )
Thank you for coming,
Kilwillie.
Well, actually, I was
rather looking for an excuse.
You've never needed
one before.
I wasn't sure what sort of
reception I'd get from your mother.
Yes, after your declaration of devotion.
I did think I was about to enter
the celestial city at the time.
You were drugged,
she knows that.
- She didn't take me seriously?
- No, of course not.
Oh-
well, that's a relief.
So, what is it you
wanted to see me about?
If you needed to lay your
hands on a substantial sum
of money very, very quickly,
how would you go about it?
Well, strictly
entre nous,
Inverness to Heathrow,
Heathrow to Zurich,
taxi to the National
Bank of Switzerland,
back with my feet up at
Kilwillie Castle inside 16 hours.
And if that
wasn't an option?
- Stocks and bonds.
- Nor that?
Oh.
Well, I suppose,
at a pinch,
I could do without the
XJ6 or one of the Bentleys,
but it seems a pity
to split the collection.
You're not feeling the
fiscal squeeze, are you?
Yes.
The solution's
obvious, I'd say.
Not to me,
it isn't.
I'll always give you a
fair price for land, Archie,
- as long as it's the right piece.
- Absolutely not.
Oh well, it's up
to you, old boy.
Excuse me.
I think we need to
have some words, laddie.
It's a long time since
anyone called me that.
Yeah, it must be.
So I'd say you were old
enough to know better.
- Not with you.
- You nearly had me over in the village.
- I'm sorry.
- And now you're on a private estate.
- I had no idea.
- evidently.
Is there a telephone nearby?
She's just not turning over.
Down that way,
about 10 miles.
Nice bike, by the way.
- Kilwillie?
- Oh, Molly.
Matter of fact, I... I've been
meaning to come and see you.
- Really?
- Yes.
I want to clear up
any misunderstanding.
What misunderstanding
might that be?
Well, I-I said
a few things that-
- you didn't mean?
- No!
So you did mean them?
When a chap thinks
his number's up
he can become
rather emotional.
If that chap harbors
certain feelings,
well, he might
be inclined
to articulate them a bit
more than he would otherwise,
if circumstances
were different.
Oh, please say
you're not cross.
- You were Hector's best friend.
- And proud of it!
I thought you would have
more respect for his memory.
Oh, Molly, a moment's
indiscretion.
Can't we just put
it behind us?
Forgive and forget?
In time, probably,
but I can't pretend that
I'm not very disappointed.
( groans )
( sighs )
Archie: Nothing we could
sell would be worth anything.
We don't want to sell
the river or the loch
and obviously Ben Bogle
has to be protected.
This is the Grouse Moor, this
is where we stock the deer.
Exactly, so they're out.
Then I'd say
- then I'd say it has to be here.
That's Doon Brae,
no, we can't.
Whichever bit we let go, it's
not going to hurt any less.
We'd lose a huge stretch of water
and all access from the south.
It would make things
impossible.
It joins Kilwillie's land which
means he'll pay good money.
Archie, sometimes we have to cull
the herd to ensure its survival.
Maybe you're right.
It'll be a hell of a wrench
letting that go.
I think it's my favorite
spot on the whole estate,
ever since
I was a boy.
There's not a view
like it.
( washer spinning )
Duncan, what are
you doing?
Just thought I'd
finish this off for you.
You've done
that all right.
And how am I supposed
to use this?
- I was just trying to help.
- You're not.
And leaving a stone
in your shirt
wasn't the smartest thing
you could have done either.
You shouldn't be
keeping secrets from me.
I know what
the matter is.
- How?
- Archie told me.
Archie?
What did he say?
The estate's in trouble. That's why
you've been in a bad mood, isn't it?
- No.
- Well, you admit you are then.
Relationships are
all about communication.
We must listen
to each other very care-
- what did you say about a stone?
- In your washing.
You know what kind of damage
that could do to the machine?
- Where is it now?
- I threw it outside in the yard.
( gasps )
Oh, no.
Please, no.
It's for the driveway.
They've just delivered it.
- Splendid news.
- Archie: is it?
Absolutely. You want
to sell, I want to buy.
Do us both
a bit of good.
Hold on, there are
other interested parties.
You would put them before
your father's greatest chum?
I'm afraid all I care about
is getting the best price.
I see.
That isn't how Hector
would have managed things.
And I think that's a
valuable lesson to us all.
( knocking on door )
- Archie, have you got a minute?
- Not now, no.
It's important.
It had better be.
I'm sorry.
It's not a problem,
take as long as you like.
Do you think
he'll go for it?
Yeah, he's bound to, he
won't be able to resist.
Probably best
not to ask.
Oh, I think
the Kilwillie coffers
can run to a better
offer than those.
- Well?
- Nope.
Told you.
Oh!
I don't believe it.
- it's not.
- It is.
My lucky wish stone.
- I've had it since I was a boy.
- How does that work then?
Rub it over
your lottery tickets?
It was a christening present.
A friend of my granny's,
an old woman
with the power.
I tell it my wish
and then I turn round twice,
I throw the stone in the loch
and then that wish comes true.
- So why have you never done it?
- You only get one go.
But there must have
been things you've wanted.
So I'm saving
this beauty
for something
really special.
If only life
was that simple.
Well done, Archie.
I knew you'd see sense.
I'll get onto McGregor,
have him call in a surveyor,
- get the exact boundaries drawn up.
- While I arrange the readies.
Well, home for a
celebratory snifter, I think.
Actually, I think I might
hang on for a minute or two.
Looks as if we might
be due for a spot of rain.
What's on your mind?
It's Irene. I think she's going off me.
- What makes you say that?
- It's just she's-
acting weird.
Perhaps she thinks that you're
starting to take her for granted.
But I've not, though. I mean, just
last week I bought her chocolates,
- and not the ones on special offer.
- ( laughing )
And who said
romance was dead?
Where is she, anyway?
Away in a huff.
I don't suppose you could
have a wee talk with her?
Anything else?
Well, if there's any more tea
in the pot, that would be nice.
( knocking on door )
What are you doing
knocking at my door?
- Think I'd have knocked if I knew you were inside?
- Why did you?
I've been pushing this for
miles, first place I've seen,
there's a motorbike,
somebody might help-
- never mind.
- Wait a minute!
It won't hurt to have a look, I suppose.
Okay.
- Do you want to talk about it?
- What?
- Whatever it is that's on your mind.
- Not really.
Is it Duncan?
Partly.
If you don't want to go
out with him, just tell him.
He won't be happy,
but he will get over it.
That's just it, I'm
not sure what I want.
Then explain that to him.
He'll understand.
I doubt it.
I'm pregnant, Lexie.
- You're what?
- Expecting a baby.
Yeah, I know
what it means.
It's just a bit
of a shock, that's all.
You can say that again.
But Duncan'll
be pleased.
He won't,
believe me.
Most men say they don't
want kids, when it happens-
it's not his,
it can't be.
- Then whose?
- I was with someone before I came here.
I see.
Don't. Come here. Come here.
Please, don't say anything
to anyone, will you?
No, not if you
don't want me to.
But you have
to tell Duncan,
sooner rather
than later.
Do you know any rosses
living locally?
Not that I
can think of, why?
It's my mother's maiden name.
She came from this area.
That's why I'm up here. I'm trying to
track down some long-lost relatives.
You could try
the phone book.
I have, and the library
and the electoral roll.
And I've ridden through
every village on the map.
- No luck?
- No.
Okay.
Give it a whirl.
( engine starts )
Sweet as a nut.
You've done this before.
I've had plenty
of practice.
They say they can
be a bit temperamental.
Cup of tea?
Thanks.
Molly: Archie!
Archie, they're here.
He'd have understood.
No, I've let him down.
I've let you all down.
You had no choice.
Let's get this over with.
- Archie.
- You didn't waste much time, did you?
We can't afford to drag
our heels on this one.
This is the surveyor,
Greg MacDonald.
What's the matter, lad, would
you rather have had a Campbell?
No, I'm just surprised
we've never met before.
Ach, well, we live over
the other side of Inverness
and we keep ourselves
to ourselves,
- don't we, Morag?
- Aye.
- my wife.
- Hello.
I thought she ought
to be here,
- today of all days.
- Sorry?
Our first chance to see inside the
great ancestral home of the clan.
Tell me... is that not
William MacDonald,
the great duelist?
Um...
I think so.
Oh, definitely,
I'd say.
- We really ought to make a start.
- Yes, of course.
But I really think you ought to
hear what I have to say first.
Duncan.
- I know what you're gonna say.
- I doubt that.
You don't think
I'm serious about you.
Well, I've had an idea.
I'd like you
to meet my Auntie Liz.
- What?
- You'll really like her.
The thing is-
trying to catch
her at home.
She gets out
and about all over-
Monday night- bingo, every
second Tuesday- folk club,
Wednesdays-
self defense.
- Sounds like a busy lady.
- She is, but she can fit us in this evening.
How's that
for a stroke of luck?
I'm really not sure
I ought to come.
- Duncan-
- please.
It would mean
a lot to me.
- Okay.
- Great.
I'll give her a call...
before she puts her name
down for the dominoes.
Bear with me,
it's in here somewhere.
I'll just drop
that in the bin.
No, you will not!
I'd have nothing
for my supper.
Here it is.
- The 1715 Land Treaty.
- The what?
You've not heard of it?
It was drawn up amongst
the MacDonald chieftains
to ensure
all ancestral land
stayed within
our hands.
Sounds fascinating,
but this isn't really a good
moment for a history lesson.
I'm just coming
to the interesting part.
"If the laird ever has the need
to sell off acreage,
then any other MacDonald,"
such as myself,
"could invoke the right
to buy the entire estate. "
Which means what?
You have to sell us
Glenbogle.
( scoffing ) This is some
sort of a hoax, right?
I've researched
every last detail.
- Who'd take something like that seriously these days?
- I do.
Have you any idea what an
estate like this would cost?
I have a rather large
inheritance.
My family were very big
in offal products.
But we're talking
serious money.
Aye.
You're not
a surveyor then?
Oh, I still work.
Idle hands are
the devil's plaything.
And I daresay I'll find plenty to keep
us busy once we're settled in here.
Right, that's it, I've
heard enough. Go on, get out.
Well, if that's
what you want,
but you'll be seeing
us again soon enough.
I wouldn't
bet on it.
I'll show you out.
Your copy.
Come along, Morag.
Another?
Love to, but I'd
better order a taxi.
Taxi? more chance
of flying.
Listen, there's
a settee in there,
it's not much but
you're welcome to it.
- Sure?
- I wouldn't offer if I wasn't.
Well, beats sitting
in a room by yourself.
You know where the best
malt I ever tasted came from?
- The highlands, surely.
- No.
The Orkneys, Isla?
- Japan.
- Get away.
Mind you, I hadn't had
a drink in six months.
That would
account for it.
So, what line
are you in?
Anything and everything.
I've made and lost a great
deal of money in my time.
Managed to hold onto a
chuck this time round, though
and then hit the road.
What, you just hit
the road?
Yeah. I've been around,
seen a lot of places.
Funny thing is, I've
never been here before.
So, where do you
call home?
Right now, it's the back of the bike.
And when your
journey's over?
Wherever it takes me.
You have a visitor, my lord.
Probably not
a very welcome one.
I came to apologize for
what I said this morning.
It's already forgotten. Would
you like a glass of sherry?
Yes, thank you,
just a small one.
I didn't want us
to fall out,
not with everything else
that's happening.
About the estate, you mean?
Hasn't Archie told you?
We've struck a deal,
your worries are over.
No, Kilwillie, they might
have only just begun.
- Liz: it's lovely to meet you, Maureen.
- Irene.
Not often he brings
a lassie back for tea,
- is it, Duncan?
- No, auntie.
What was the name
of that last one?
Skinny wee thing,
covered in freckles.
- Jennifer Connor.
- Aye, that's it.
I'd high hopes
for the two of you.
She was six,
and I was seven.
So... should I be
looking for a new hat?
- Do you need one?
- Well, if there's an event in the offing.
Event?
One that involves bells.
What, me and Duncan?
You are round
for your tea.
This is the 21st century.
We're not about to trade
lifelong commitment
for a slice
of jam sponge.
Are we?
I just thought
it would be a good idea
if you two got to know
each other, that's all.
I see, and here's
me thinking
I might be hearing
the patter of tiny feet.
Why?
Are the mice back?
I can't buy it because
of a 300-year-old treaty?
That's preposterous.
We'll see. But I'm
afraid your rescue attempt
might have been
in vain.
Is there any other way
I can help?
I don't see how,
but all suggestions
are very welcome.
Then I'll put on
my thinking cap forthwith.
- Friends again?
- Oh, yes.
I'd better get back.
Nil desperandum.
I don't know where
these cobwebs come from.
More sherry,
Mrs. MacDonald?
No thank you, and I'll see myself out.
McGregor: These are the
estates covered by the treaty
and as you can see,
Glenbogle is indeed
one of them.
- Is it genuine then?
- Very much so.
When it was drawn up,
land was everything.
Lose the smallest piece
and it was a sign
of weakness and failure.
And so you'd also
lose face
in front of the other
great landowning families.
I can think
of worse things.
Yes, but more importantly,
it meant that the laird
who needed to make the sale
could no longer be trusted
with the rest
of what he owned.
Whatever
the circumstances?
They were very
unforgiving times.
Yes, but that was then and this
is now. It can't be valid today.
It's a precedent
that's never been tested.
There's a chance it could still be
considered legally binding by a court.
Even if we had no idea
that it existed?
Ignorance, I'm afraid,
is no excuse.
So, what do we do now?
Possession is 9/10ths
of the law-
so I'd advise selling to Lord
Kilwillie as speedily as possible.
Once that pocket of land is his
and you've paid the death duties,
there'll be very little
Greg can do.
Kilwillie? I presume
there's a reason
why you're looking
so pleased with yourself.
Come with me
and you'll find out.
Kilwillie,
what's happening?
All aboard
the skylark.
Oh, a picnic,
what a wonderful
surprise.
I thought you needed
cheering up.
Kilwillie, I've got
the contract for you.
- Not a good moment.
- All I need is a signature.
I make it a rule never
to commit on an empty stomach.
Especially not
this early
when who knows what
the day may bring.
- Archie!
- ( boat motor starts )
You'd better
come here.
Okay.
- Did he sign?
- Archie: Not yet.
Then it's too late.
Greg MacDonald's had an
emergency injunction granted.
As of 10 minutes ago, there's
a block on your land sale.
- So we can't sell to Kilwillie?
- Nor to anybody else.
- Then the death duties won't get paid.
- I need hardly remind you
that the consequences of that
are potentially disastrous.
- Where can I find him?
- Greg? Staying in the village
at the Glenbogle
Rose Guest House.
- Right.
- Lexie: Where are you going?
Where do you think?
Kilwillie: Do you want some more wine?
Molly: Just a little. Thank you.
Now, what's next,
I wonder?
Oh, I've had
enough, really.
This is the special
of the day.
Indulge me, Molly.
Kilwillie?
I'm not a chap who finds
this sort of thing easy,
but oh, Molly,
I'd like to marry you.
I really don't know
what to say.
Well, "yes" would
be rather nice.
I know your feelings
aren't the same as mine-
but over the years,
perhaps you might...
grow to love me.
A bit.
This really isn't
the right time.
Oh, but it is. Don't you see
it's exactly the right time?
It occurred to me
yesterday after you'd left,
if you marry me
I'd be family
and my money could help
you keep Glenbogle.
But I thought it was the
land that you were after.
I'd rather have you,
as my wife.
I really believe
you mean it.
I don't think for a minute
I'd ever replace Hector,
but we both know what
the estate meant to him.
And we can save it,
if you- if you
would just consider
taking me
as your husband.
I need some time
to think it over.
Expected to find us in
some fancy hotel, I suppose.
But a bed and hot food,
that's all we need.
Well then, why
do you want Glenbogle?
It deserves to be in the hands
of someone who respects tradition.
And you think
that I don't?
It's been my family's
home for generations.
But you're ready
to sell bits of it off.
- I have no choice.
- Don't give me that.
I've tried
every other option.
Like your new-fangled
wildlife park?
And the folk you let
up to visit it?
- if you mean our visitors, they're what keep us going.
- Not once I'm laird.
- You can't just shut the place to the public.
- why not?
I've no need
of their money.
But a lot of people
living round here do.
Their livelihoods
would be in your hands.
Being the laird,
it's not just a title,
but there are obligations
that go with it.
He has a fair point.
You've had your chance. I'll
run the place as I think fit.
- This injunction won't change anything.
- Brave words.
I think it will, once the interest
on those death duties starts accruing.
- Unless I pay them.
- Which we both know you can't.
And I'll make sure
that any court case
is as drawn out
as possible.
Ultimately, you could
be left with nothing.
That is unless you decide
to make it easy on yourself,
and I could buy it
from you now.
You still don't
get it, do you?
This isn't just about
me, I can't give in.
In that case,
may the better man win.
So, just when
we thought
things couldn't
get any worse...
that settles it
then.
That's marvelous.
Isn't it, Badger?
Yes, my lord.
Wonderful.
Champagne, I think.
The '73.
But I thought we were saving
that for a special occasion.
- Well, this is it!
- If you say so, my lord.
None for me,
thank you, Badger.
Surely a toast
to our future.
I must get back, tell
them all the good news.
You're right,
of course.
And after all,
we'll be popping
corks together
for many years
to come.
And if the worst does happen,
then you might have to find
- other jobs.
- What would I do?
It probably won't
come to that.
I just thought I ought
to tell you how we stand.
Thanks, it's appreciated.
Archie, I think your
problems might be over.
I'm going to marry
Kilwillie.
But you can't
really be serious.
It's the perfect
solution.
He's got lots of money.
Glenbogle will be rescued
and, well, being lady Kilwillie
can't be all that bad.
I wouldn't put my last pound on it.
Well, look, look how long
we've struggled.
This will secure
all our futures.
Yes, but at
what cost?
There isn't one.
Everybody gets what they want.
Except you. You'd be
sacrificing your happiness.
- Archie's right.
- I'm sorry, I don't agree.
I won't let
you do it.
My mind's made up.
You can't stop me now.
So, what do we do now?
I haven't got a clue.
I'll tell you one thing,
she's not gonna walk up the
aisle with Kilwillie to save us.
- I agree.
- I've got an idea.
Well now, Hector.
I think this could be the end
of Glenbogle as we know it.
Golly?
I thought it was you.
Aye, aye.
Morag.
- Hello?
- Can we talk?
Yes, but if you're
who I think you are,
I can't do
much to help.
But surely you can't agree
with what Greg's doing?
He's my husband.
I love him,
despite his faults.
- This is his dream.
- But is it what you want, though?
He thinks Glenbogle should be kept as
a monument to the glory of the clan.
When it's between them and
me, I'm used to coming second.
I suppose neither of us
could have known
what we were letting
ourselves in for.
- Marrying into this family.
- But I didn't.
- Eh?
- I'm the MacDonald.
When Greg married me,
he took my name.
Don't know why I didn't think
of looking in churchyards before.
Is that it?
Grandmother.
The last of the Rosses.
According to
the gravedigger there.
- I remember her now.
- Really?
She used to have
an apple tree in her garden.
When I was a wee boy
I used to just help myself,
until she gave me
a thick ear.
She never stood
for any nonsense, Mrs. Ross.
Apparently, she died
a very lonely old lady.
- I didn't know.
- He told me.
She worked on the Tavistock
Estate all her life.
Then, when they sold it,
the rest of her family and
her few friends moved away.
Well, they had to, there
was no other work round here.
- But not her though?
- No.
She reckoned she was
too old to up sticks.
So... that's it then,
you don't have any living
relatives in the area?
Nope, that's it.
The end of my search.
Time to be moving on.
Again.
Don't say anything. I
just want you to listen.
- But-
- please.
There's no easy way
to say this
and, for the time being, I
don't want it going any further.
What?
I'm pregnant.
I- I'm gonna
be a dad?
- No.
- But you just said-
it's not yours.
I don't understand.
It can't be.
We haven't been together
long enough.
So, you've been seeing
somebody else?
Before I came here.
Isn't there a tiny
chance it might be mine?
I'm sorry.
- What are we gonna do?
- I don't know.
I must be the world's
luckiest man,
hmm, Badger?
Mmm. Your crackers,
my lord.
Now, the honeymoon.
Caribbean or the Med?
It does rather depend
on the time of year,
but we shouldn't leave it
too long to tie the knot.
And on the day itself,
I felt if we could just keep it down to 300 guests
- each.
Much more than that, it
all gets a bit out of hand.
Whatever you think.
Wedding car?
The Bentley.
Or we could stretch
to a limousine.
I really don't mind.
No, that was a joke.
Stretch limousine.
Oh, yes, very amusing.
It makes us laugh,
eh, Badger?
On a regular basis,
your lordship.
You'll get to know my
sense of humor, my dear.
And all my little
ways and habits.
All right, Badger,
you can leave us.
Yes, your lordship.
Only I was wondering
if I should
- air a spare room?
- For what reason?
Some engaged couples
have a more
- modern outlook-
- right, point taken.
Actually, I'll be
going home...
tonight.
Oh, right.
Well, absolutely,
whatever you say.
( door closes )
- Mother?
- Archie, you're still up.
So, how was
your evening?
- Oh, fine.
- No, it wasn't.
I had a thoroughly
enjoyable evening.
So, why do you
look so down?
How do you think it makes
me feel seeing you like this?
- it'll get better.
- You don't know that.
It's me that's failed, why
should you have to suffer?
Oh, Archie,
you haven't failed.
As much as I loved
your father,
we both know that
this place was in
even more of a mess
before you came back.
And he loved you, too.
What do you think he'd make
of what you're doing now?
He'd understand.
No, he'd want you
to be happy,
but you won't be
if you do this
and neither
will Kilwillie.
It's not fair
on either of you.
Maybe-
maybe I'll speak
to him in the morning.
( clears throat )
Oh, Molly,
back so soon?
Come sit down.
Would you like
a cup of coffee?
- I can't stay.
- I'll be in the pantry
if you need me,
your lordship.
I was thinking of popping over to
see if you fancied a spot of luncheon.
- I'm not hungry.
- Much the same myself.
I could only manage
three rashers
and a half of round of
black pudding this morning.
It's the excitement,
that's what it'll be.
Kilwillie,
I'm sorry,
but I've changed my mind.
I can't marry you.
Well...
it's just a touch
of nerves, that's all.
No doubt I'll be getting
butterflies, too.
I'm afraid I mean it.
No, you don't.
You're a good man,
Kilwillie,
but if I were to become lady Kilwillie,
it would be
for your money,
and that's no basis
for a marriage.
Isn't it?
Well, not in my book.
I'm willing to risk it
if you are.
But I'm not.
I see.
Well, you can't blame
a chap for trying.
Oh, no.
No, no you keep it. It'll only
remind me of what might have been.
Please.
We can still stay
friends, can't we?
I was rather hoping
you'd say that.
Another cup, my lord?
No thank you, Badger.
You can take it away.
I know it must be small
consolation, my lord,
but you've always
got me.
And a truer servant
no man could wish for.
Maybe I should just be
content with my lot.
I can't imagine a woman being
more capable in the kitchen,
or neater with
a needle and thread.
I'm pretty nifty
with a duster, too.
Now, if you'll excuse me, my
lord, I have your bath to draw.
Ducks or battleships?
Why don't you chose?
Very good, my lord.
Here we go.
- You sure about this?
- Absolutely.
- Thank you.
You did
the right thing.
But we're still no nearer
getting the money.
Well, I did have
one idea.
I couldn't do it
without asking you first.
How's that?
Well done.
- That is terrific.
- Not bad.
Greg,
it's Archie MacDonald.
Why don't you come over?
I have a proposition for you.
I wish for Archie
to keep Glenbogle.
Greg: I hope this isn't
another wasted trip.
It's time we settled
this once and for all.
- I couldn't agree more.
- Good, then I challenge you to a duel.
- Sorry?
- My privilege as laird,
as laid down in
the amendments to the treaty.
But there are no amendments.
I was meticulous in my research.
So what's this?
Any territorial disputes
within the clan
can be settled
by pistol or sword.
So you win, Glenbogle's yours, I win,
and you never come back here again.
You're mad!
Like I said, he can talk the
talk but when it comes down to it
he just hasn't got what
it takes to be the laird.
What's that
supposed to mean?
It's not about how much you're
worth, it's about respect and honor.
And ultimately, it means
being prepared to die
to protect what's yours
and what you believe in.
And if you're not ready to do that, then
you're not worthy of taking my place.
But then I shouldn't be surprised
when you're not even a MacDonald.
- I'm every bit the man you are.
- Then prove it.
- Right, I will.
- You will not.
Do you think I'm going
to risk losing you
for the sake
of some stupid quest?
- You keep out of this, Morag.
- No! I've put up with enough. I'm not going to stand by
- and watch you get yourself killed.
- I'm not backing down.
Well,
in that case...
I'm the MacDonald.
So if there's going
to be a duel,
it'll be me fighting it.
- You can't.
- Yes, I can.
Taking on a woman,
it wouldn't be right.
Greg:
In that case,
I'll see you in court,
and you'll be made to give up
Glenbogle. Come away, Morag.
Archie!
We've got the money.
- How?
- Molly: Because of Golly and Lexie.
It looks like we won't be
going to court after all.
And you don't
have to fight.
Yes, he will.
You can't back down now.
- You just did.
- But I didn't make the challenge.
And I thought you
were prepared
to die for what you
believed in.
Pistols or swords?
Remember,
10 paces a man.
Greg, Duncan
will be your second.
You're not really gonna go
through with this, are you?
Archie: He needs to be taught a lesson.
It wasn't supposed
to come to this.
Just remember one thing,
I love you.
Are you both ready?
Aye.
As the challenge was made
by Archie MacDonald,
his opponent will
take the first shot.
In your own time.
( Greg gasps )
- ( Molly, Lexie cheering )
- Golly: It's not over yet!
Archie.
I don't have
to do this.
Last chance.
Okay, okay, you win.
- Duncan.
- What?
- You have to take his place.
- do I?
You're his second,
it's in the rules.
All right, fine.
For goodness sake, man,
it's over.
I was joking.
What's the matter with you?
It's over, Greg,
and I'm glad...
because it's you
I care about,
not living in some
stupid pile.
You're just saying that.
I don't deserve you.
I won't argue with that.
As we're not buying
the estate,
perhaps we could treat
ourselves to a taxi back.
Wouldn't
you rather walk?
- It's only eight miles.
- ( groans )
- Golly: Well done, Archie.
- You're the real hero.
I know how much
your home meant to you.
If you hadn't found
that document-
ah, yes, well I didn't.
It was all Lexie's work.
You didn't know that we had
a resident forger, did you?
- Molly: I don't believe it!
- Greg did though-
fortunately.
Doon Brae, it is
still your favorite
- part of the estate?
- It is, yes.
You know the old
ruined cottage up there?
It'll take a lot of work,
but it's yours if you want it.
Sounds good.
One question though,
what if he hadn't missed?
There was no
danger at all.
I sent Duncan
to get the pistols-
I told him to put the
powder in, not the bullets.
I knew you had
something up your sleeve.
I forgot.
What?
You're kidding?
You'd still
be safe enough.
These aren't accurate
at six feet
and you were at least
15 yards apart.
I'm gonna aim at that
dead branch there.
( gunshot )
Archie!
( theme music playing )
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0